Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 1-2:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Thanks to many others for one-off corrections!
Above: I replaced the honorific with something else because it seemed like you were trying to avoid them earlier. My suggestion would be to either have all honorifics or take them all out but it's up to you.
There will be a giveaway during this program!
TN: This giveaway has long expired. Please keep expections in check!
Don't miss it!
It has been 30 years since the loss of the Yo-kai Watch from Keita's era.
The arrival of the Demon King marked the end of peaceful, ordinary days
However, Natsume, who was chosen by the new Yo-kai Watch Elder,
the owner of the Ogre Watch, Touma,
and the practitioner of sorcery, Akinori,
along with the Yo-kai that defeated the Demon Lord,
brought back those peaceful days of ordinary life once again.
And after that, these children went on to
establish a Yo-kai detective agency.
in order to solve mysterious incidents caused by Yo-kai.
Now, the curtain rises on a new story.
Yo-kai Watch: Shadow Side:
The terrifying premiere!
A shocking one-hour special!
Punishment!
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
(Ghost Gang Leader)
The Boureibanchou is a frightening Yo-kai.
It's said that he appears before bullies
and leads those bullies to Hell.
And those who persist in their hatred of others...
might be mistaken for bullies and be lead to the same fate.
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou
My name is Keisuke Amano.
Things like ghost, UFOs and prophecies...
I don't believe in anything like that.
I thought that there's no way that any of that exists.
But as far as Natsume's secret is concerned...
There's definitely something fishy!
She's coming home late recently...
Don't tell me, she's gotten herself a boyfriend!?
Well, a boyfriend might not be so bad...
Maybe she's gotten into some strange cult...
and is being forced to pay them money.
Sorry for the wait, Akinori, Touma.
You're late, Natsume.
We also just got here as well, though.
What? I was late by three minutes.
Stop fooling around. Time is precious!
Akinori, you're playing make-believe running an agency, right?
P-playing make-believe!?
Our important activities influence the fate of the entire world!
You see, we are the Yo-kai Detective Agency.
There are many bizarre incidents in modern society that we solve.
We're here to take back the peace, to the relief of the hearts of the people!
Oh? So we are a collective agency?
We're not a collective agency! We're a detective agency!
Settle down.
Geez, Natsume! You're always saying it wrong!
-Which one is Natsume's boyfriend?
Is it the thin, handsome one?
Don't tell me, it can't be the fat one, right?
In fact, there's something I want to show you both.
It's this!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou?
There's a lot of posts about bizarre incidents lately.
It confronts people who've committed bullying, and punishes them
Punish?
Here's a posting from an eyewitness.
While I was returning home from cram school...
I heard a scream.
Wondering what it was,
I walked toward the scream.
And then I saw it there.
A big man in a school uniform was beating up some kid wearing a cap!
His size was beyond human.
And his face had a furious expression.
His eyes glowed bright red.
And then... He looked over his shoulder and came charging!
I was filled with terror and ran away as fast as I could.
Huh? Seems like an urban legend no matter how you cut it.
If the witness was about to be attacked,
does this mean he was a bully as well?
No.
Recently, people who aren't bullies were also attacked.
(Ghost Gang Leader)
So Boureibanchou, who punishes bullying...
is now beginning to bully the weak as well.
May I add something?
Whisper?
Yo-kai do not change their personality and disposition in this manner so easily.
Just like the fact that I would never stop my daily muscle training!
Listen, Micchi. If we need you, we'll call you.
Can you go somewhere else now?
Miss Natsume! It is the duty of a knight to protect a princess.
I will always be by your side! Muscle!
No thanks. You're annoying.
But that really is weird though.
As I have said before,
A Yo-kai's personality and pattern of behavior is never supposed to change.
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou should only punish bullies.
It should be impossible for him to be attacking innocents.
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou? Punishment?
What are they talking about?
Huh? Who's there!?
Uwaaa! Not good!
Ah! It's Keisuke!
Do you know him, Natsume?
Well... he's my younger brother.
Younger brother!?
W-W-W-Who are these guys!?
"Who are they?"
Keisuke, can you actually see Whisper and the others!?
For real?
That appears to be so.
W-Who the heck is this puffy guy!?
Puffy? How rude!
I'll have you know that I've been training my body recently, even my biceps!
What!? Are you trying to compete with my muscles?
Muscle!
W-What are you people!?
Is there something wrong with your eyes?
We are Yo-kai, no matter how you look at it.
Yo-kai?
I am Whisper.
(Slimamander)
And I am Mitsumatanozuchi. You can call me Micchi.
Hmmm... Come to think of it, you seem to resemble someone I know.
That aside, why is a normal person able to see Yo-kai?
Hey! That's my watch on your arm, isn't it!?
Why do you have it?
It's some kind of communication device, isn't it?
You were talking to it while there was no one around!
You saw that?
Then let me tell you... all about the splendor of that watch!
I see.
This device makes you see hallucinations!
And you're a cult organization that brainwashes people!
Hey...
And you've already been brainwashed by this cult!
Now you can't escape from the cult anymore!
Huh?
He possesses such a rich imagination.
Then what comes next is clear.
Would you like to join our Yo-kai Detective Agency right now?
They're trying to brainwash me!
There he goes.
But what happened just now?
Even with the watch, if you don't shine the light on Yo-kai, you shouldn't see them.
Seems like Natsume and Keisuke only need to wear the watch to see them.
(Ghost Gang Leader)
In any case, let's try to unravel the mystery of the Boureibanchou.
The time he's most commonly witnessed is during evening
Let's look for him then.
Nothing is showing up.
If you think about it, no one is being bullied either.
Certainly.
Of course!
Hey Touma, why don't you sit over here?
Huh?
And Akinori, beat Touma up with this stick.
B-Beat him up!?
It's just pretend.
Ah, I see. So I'm pretending to be a bully.
Is doing this really okay?
It's okay.
Alright, I'm getting into this!
Let's go.
Action!
P-Please stop it. I didn't do... anything.
Heh heh, I'm gonna bully you!
It's gonna be painful. It's gonna hurt.
Cut! Cut! Cut!
What kind of bully says "I'm gonna bully you"?
Do it more realistically.
Hey. Fat boy!
What are you doing to that kid!?
Um.. No.. This is...
Looks like you're a bully, aren't you?
You were about to hit him with that stick, right!?
I-I wasn't going to do that.
Bullies deserve the smelly onion!
Aaaaagh!
Don't tell me...
Hey! I'm not done talking to you yet!
It's there!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
That's the Boureibanchou.
He's attacking someone.
We need to stop him.
Yo-kai Watch... Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Yo.
Long time no see.
Ah!
He's here.
Whis!
Ha ha!
You're here too.
Huh? What? Wanna fight?
Ugh... Just by looks alone, I can tell we've already lost.
No need to worry.
Please insert the ark in the watch again and turn it the other way.
The other way?
And simply say, "Shadowside"!
Shadowside!
SHADOW!
Hiss!
Micchi, you're fighting too.
Roger that!
That's...
In Shadowside form, a Yo-kai can unleash its dark powers.
It's great for this situation!
(Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!)
Hyaku Neko Restsu Dan
Heh, you're pretty strong.
He ran away?
No. No matter how you saw it, he had the upper hand.
That's strange. Why did he flee?
Are you okay?
I am perfectly okay!
I didn't mean you!
Tsk! I don't get it.
Huh? Wait, why are you running?
I...
What did I just see?
Keisuke, you saw that too!?
Muscle!
-What is this?
What are these guys...?
It is as I've humbly described to you before...
We are Yo-kai.
Uwaagh!!!
It appears that he's fled again.
Was that a dream?
Wait... they could've all been wearing costumes.
Anyway, there is no way things like ghosts and Yo-kai can exist!
Huh? It's that guy from before...
So... have you guys brought your dues?
Yeah, Shiroda, sir.
Dues?
That's...!
I see what's going on!
I saw these guys on the news. They are a street gang!
They're organized criminals who gather money by shaking people down on the streets!
Huh?
Who in the world are you?
Looks like you've discovered our secret meeting.
That means...
We can't just let you go now, can we?
Maybe we should drown you in Tokyo Bay?
Wanna get off easy?
Then scream this as loud as you can
"I give up. I won't tell anyone about Shiroda. Please forgive me."
Okay?
Say it! You spineless weakling!
As if I would.
Huh?
I won't ever surrender to scoundrels like you!
What did you say?
I won't ever surrender!
I swore... I swore that to my friend!
That uniformed guy...
I see. It was you...!
This is bad!
Run away!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
...Boureibanchou?
Never give up, Kei.
I see...
I understand.
Even if these street gangs don't stand out like bullies,
...they're just as rotten as any bully!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou was hiding and waiting to punish these gang members!
Heh... Heh.... Hehhehhehheh.....
Don't tell me...that oversized Frankenstein monster is one of your buddies?
Whatever... I'll take all of you down!
Hehhehhehheh...
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou's fighting some kind of monster!
The malice within that person has taken him over!
(Wicked)
Looks like it's a Kaima, a special type of Yo-kai!
As if we needed more monsters!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Let's summon some help for Boureibanchou... huh?
The Yo-kai watch!
What's this?
The Yo-kai watch moved all by itself...!
Keisuke!
What is this!? What's going on?
Use that to summon good Yo-kai to help us out!
Why me!? Natsume, you do it!
When I tried using it, it came to you.
That means you're the one chosen to use it now!
Alright, I'll do it then.
So... What do I do?
Use this!
What's this? A key?
That's Komasan's ark.
Stick that into the watch and turn it!
Light!
It opened?
While holding the key, say this:
"Summoning! Come on out, my friend, Komasan!"
S-Summoning! Come on out my friend, Komasan!
What? It's just a regular dog that came out!
Now put the Ark in again, and turn it the other way!
SHADOW!
W-W-W-What is this!?
We did it!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou, I think I know who you are.
Huh?
I think I remember you from a long time ago.
That bracelet... You're Ken, aren't you?
You saved me a long time ago. You're Ken, right?
What was that? You're pretty weak.
Thank you for helping me!
Those guys are always picking on me...
Well... if they ever come back to bully you again,
I'll fight them off for you.
Really?
Sure.
But on one condition.
Condition?
Never say you're going to give up.
People can come in many sizes. They could be big like me, or small like you.
How strong or big you are is only a matter of how much you eat.
However, people who are truly strong are strong in here.
If you have faith in yourself, you'll remain standing 'til the very end.
If you are a truly strong person, then I will lend you my strength.
Understand? Men are courageous.
Mr. Kenji...
Just call me Kenji.
Okay! Men are couragous, right?
From that point on, we became closer.
And then we started calling each other Kei and Ken.
But, soon after that...
Ken got into an accident.
Keisuke...
It's because of Ken... that I... can stand up to bullies now.
Ken, you came back to fight them off for me.
Sure.
Seems like I've meddled a little too much though.
You're the one who seems a lot stronger though, Kei.
No way! Natsume and the gang just made some foul plays.
Who's making foul plays!?
Kei, you've also gotten stronger.
It's only strength that I've gotten from you, though.
It's all...It's all... thanks to you, Ken...
I've... I've...
Even ever since you've gone, I've never said I'm giving up, ever.
I see. That's good to hear.
I must leave soon.
Goodbye, Kei.
Men are couragous!
Goodbye, Ken.
Thank you for your courage.
What's this...?
When the the hearts of a Yo-kai and a human connect, an ark appears.
Keisuke, that ark is yours.
My... ark?
Hey, Keisuke.
Why won't you join our Detective Agency?
After much thought, I've come to the conclusion that this is just a dream.
No way anything like that can happen in reality.
Using a Yo-kai watch. Obtaining an ark. What about all that?
Well, residents of my dream world!
I'll be going home to wake up now.
Bye!
Hey! Wait up!
He's always been like that.
That stubbornness of not believing in ghosts or UFOs...
it all came from his fear due to being alone.
It's not like he doesn't believe in it.
He's just too afraid to acknowledge any of it.
In that case, shall we frighten him as best we can this time?
Oh, that'd be great!
Yo-kai, huh?
Ghosts, UFOs or prophecies.
I don't believe in that type of stuff.
But... Yo-kai exist. Yo-kai exist for sure.
After all, my best friend is a Yo-kai.
Umm. From now on, he'll be your new classmate.
This is Haruya Sakami.
Let's get along.
All you... humans...
Hello, viewers!
Had fun watching episode one?
This is a happy announcement!
Ha ha ha!
In celebration of this new chapter of Yo-kai Watch, we're having a special giveaway!
During the program, application instructions will be shown. Don't miss the ending!
There will be wonderful goods! Muscle!
W-What is it?
It's not you...
IT'S NOT YOU!
-H-Help me!
This time, there's a terrifying Yo-kai that crawls along the streets to ambush people from behind.
Look... It might even be creeping closer to you now... right behind you...
(The Bicycle Ridden by the Dead)
Shishanonorujitensha
Touma and Natsume are coming too, right?
I'm here!
Hey!
Greetings!
Looks like you two are finally working hard now!
Alright! As the Yo-kai Detective Agency, let’s do our part
to deal with these mysterious incidents lurking with society!
And the newest posting is... What!?
What are you looking at?
It's a shopping site.
This seems better.
Ooh! It's a new 8-speed model with a lightened frame...!
Wait! Hold it!
Geez! Instead of doing that, let's solve a case!
What? But it was my turn to use it...
Instead of looking at bikes on some shopping site, look here.
Huh?
I found an interesting post from before.
The bicycle ridden by the dead?
That's right.
Posts about it multiplied recently.
"While walking home from school,
the bicycle ridden by the dead approached from behind...
then it suddenly attacked me!"
Huh? What's with that?
It could be ghost related...
Or perhaps it might even involve Yo-kai.
Huh? So that's it!
Keisuke!
Well, in any case, it's either a lie or a complete misunderstanding.
Keisuke, interested too?
Huh?
Why not join our Yo-kai Detective Agency?
Huh? I only came to help my sister! That's all!
I'm here to bring her home before you cultists get her mixed up in something!
What?
I-I didn't even believe in supernatural phenomenon from the very start!
Well... What about that?
Pushing muscles!
Shoving muscles!
It's just a dream! Just a normal dream!
Well... they're certainly no different from demons...
Oh! Looks like we can contact this kid.
Let's interview them!
Muscle!
You must be Ryou, you posted about the bicycle ridden by the dead, right?
Uh-huh.
It's okay. It's just the bell of a tricycle.
I just got attacked, so I get scared when I hear the sound of bells...
That seems tough.
When were you attacked?
It was just a little while ago, and it seems like I'm being targeted.
While I was walking by myself, I felt a presence behind me.
Things like that kept continuing.
And then yesterday...
It suddenly appeared!
When I looked over my shoulder, it was there! The bicycle ridden by the dead!
And it was looking right at me!
It's not you...
It's not YOU!
Help me!
I felt a shock, as if something bit me on the head.
And after that, there was nothing...
So it said, "it's not you," right?
There's no question. This is the work of a Yo-kai.
But, what kind of Yo-kai is this?
Perhaps...
It might be a graveyard resurrection of someone with long, disheveled hair who rides a bicycle and attacks people.
Or maybe...
It's something that rides with the face of the dead.
That seems awfully frightening.
In any case, if there's a Yo-kai like that, we must do something about it.
♪There's no such thing as a Yo-kai...
it's all just a dream...♪
No way something's there...
Hahaha.... it's just my imagination.
It's not you!
Looks like there aren't any new posts.
Natsume...
Keisuke?
What happened?
I was attacked!
It said "It's not you"...
And my face...
Are you okay?
Was it the bicycle ridden by the dead?
Maybe...
Natsume, try shining the Yo-kai watch's light on his face.
Huh?
Hurry up and do it!
What is that?
The bicycle ridden by the dead did this!
It won't go away!
Does that mark have any connection with what it said?
Maybe it's on the other kid also?
The Youma radar's picking something up....
Ah... This is....
There's a strong reaction here.
Huh? No way, this is my school!
Are you okay?
This is it.
Ouch...
Ah! It's the same tiremarks that I have!
It doesn't seem to be around anymore.
It's showing up again!
It's on that kid.
It happened while he was going to cram school, right?
Why was he attacked?
And again?
I was attacked! I'm scared!
Hey, I was attacked too.
Looks like he was attacked by someone while I wasn't looking.
Whenever he hears a bike bell, he thinks it's that other kid coming.
But it turned out to be someone else, it seems.
Other kid?
Masaki is a kid who comes here often.
He is a 6th grader at Sakura Old Town Elementary School.
He often passes by here while coming back from Harukoi Seminars Cram School.
Sakura Old Town Elementary School and Harukoi Seminars?
We were just there!
Ma'am, do you know where this kid lives?
It's here!
The bicycle ridden by the dead turns up everywhere Masaki goes.
There has to be some kind of connection!
Maybe Masaki is the one summoning it.
No one's coming out.
Is no one home?
Hey, you kids, there's nobody home here.
Huh?
Um...
Does a kid named Masaki live here?
Ah...
I heard that he was involved in a traffic accident.
I heard he was taken to the hospital.
And right after that...
And then...?
I'm sorry...
Oh no...
Where is Masaki?
What is that?
Where is Masaki!?
This is bad! This is bad! This is bad!
That's the bicycle ridden by the dead?
Huh? No way!
Where is Masaki!?
I'll handle this!
Yo-kai Watch! Summoning!
SHADOW!
Come on out my friend! Jibanyan!
Hiss!
We did it!
Tch! I failed!
Jibanyan!
What's going on!? He already defeated the rider!
Don't tell me... the bicycle is the actual Yo-kai?
As if some wheeled jerk can beat me!
We did it!
Huh?
Wh...who the heck is this guy?
Seems like some serious things happened.
I've caused you trouble.
bike
Sorry-chari.
Bike
Chari...?
Anyway, what the heck was this for?
Ah, that's called an "X."
It's not coming off at all!
It was selfish of me to do that....
It should disappear in about a week.
In a week!?
Why would you do that?
Perhaps it has something to do with Masaki?
Yes...
Originally, I was Masaki's bicycle...
So, you're the type of Yo-kai that was originally an object.
Yes... my original form is gone.
I was looking for my master, Masaki.
But before I knew it, I couldn't remember Masaki's face anymore.
In the places Masaki often goes, I looked for kids wearing the same shoes he does.
Shoes?
The same shoes Keisuke is wearing?
Yeah. But while only thinking about meeting Masaki again,
I went on a rampage and started marking kids who weren't Masaki with an “X."
I couldn’t stand the thought of Masaki being dead...
Masaki sounds like a good master.
Yes. He was a wonderful master.
Wow!
I was given to Masaki as a birthday present.
Sweet! It's the Smart Cycle GX!
And from that day onwards...
Masaki truly cared for me.
He even gave me a name right after we met!
Bike
He named me "Chari"!
Chari...
He always calls me by that name.
Even when he showed me off to his friends...
Bike
Masaki would say, "This is my Chari!"
T-That's nice.
Bike
"Chari" isn't really a name though.
No, that's a great name, right, Chari?
Huh?
And afterwards?
Ever since the day we met, Masaki and I were always together.
We went to many different places.
We saw a lot of beautiful places together.
Anytime, anywhere, we were always together.
But then one day, suddenly...
Masaki was nowhere to be found.
I was left right there.
I was left outside for many days...
..waiting for Masaki the whole time.
Before I knew it, I became a Yo-kai.
And then I went around the places Masaki goes often.
Just to look for him.
And yet still...
Bike
Chari...
But...
But Masaki will continue to live on in my heart.
Because Masaki is my one and only...
...dear and precious master.
Here we are, Masaki.
It's been a while since we were home.
That's right.
It's been the longest for you, Masaki. Two weeks, was it?
I just heard Masaki!
Me too!
And me!
Who would have thought that we would go on a vacation to Hawaii right after going to the hospital?
And I only got just a sprain from hitting that car!
It got blown out of proportion!
We were worried about whether or not we could make it to Hawaii, though.
But it turns out we can just go to Hawaii anytime.
That's right.
Hawaii?
Sprain?
What about what that old lady said!?
Agh! Having allergies is really awful!
What!?
Allergies?
Masaki was at Hawaii the whole time!
What troublesome people! And what a troublesome bicycle!
Masaki... I'm so glad you're alright!
W-Well... it's great that your master is alright!
Hurry up and meet him!
Yes!
Masaki! Huh? Agh!
Hey, Masaki, Let's celebrate with this!
Ah! Oh yeah!
It's the Super Cycle 2000R! This is the one I've been wanting!
Don't leave this one behind like your other bike, okay?
Other bike? That's okay. I was getting bored of it, anyway.
Anyway, the newest model is the best!
How heartless!
What awful treatment!
What about this poor bicycle!?
Ho ho... That might the person we were looking for.
Wrong one, huh?
Bike!?
Chari!?
Natsume!
I-If that's how it is...
Let's go! Summoning!
SHADOW!
Come on out, my friend! Komasan!
Komasan! Subdue that Yo-kai!
Leave it to me!
I didn't call for you!
Even so, I'm volunteering! This is a volunteer's style!
Me too, just in case!
Wha? My burly muscles got X'ed!
What is with this awful graffiti!?
Falling Hound Rock!
Huh? What was I doing?
Seems like you've calmed down.
Are you alright?
Ah! I'm sorry!
It appears that I've caused even more trouble for you.
bikey
Sorry-chari.
Bike
Chari...
Don't worry about it!
If you ever fall into a rampage again,
You can count on the Yo-kai Detective Agency to bring you back!
Thank you very much!
He became an ark.
Bike
Chari...
Geez, you should join the Yo-kai Detective Agency already, Keisuke.
Nope! I don't even believe in that stuff!
Everything that happened today was just a dream!
There is no way any of this was real!
So how do you explain that X on your face?
T-This is just dry skin or acne or something...
Ah! That's right! I gotta do homework! See you back home!
He's really stubborn, isn't he?
It's too scary for him to accept, huh?
It's very much like him to say stuff like that...
See you then!
See you tomorrow.
Bye bye!
Why are you following me?
I have nowhere else to go.
If you can...
I already have a bicycle of my own.
Sorry.
If you follow me any further, I'll give you a weird nickname.
Bike
Instead of Chari... I'll... I'll call you Charlie!
Charlie!? Thank you very much, master!
Eh, never mind. Charlie won't do.
Bikeman
Ah. How about Chariotoko?
Please just call me Charlie.
Well? Did you find them?
(Arrow of Omen)
No. I fired the Kashi no Ya,
but it isn't the one we're searching for...
Is that so?
Then aim for other people.
As you wish.
Heh.
Thanks for waiting everyone! We'll be announcing some special presents!
TN: This giveaway has long expired. Please keep expections in check!
This time, we've prepared two types!
First, it's Touma's watch, Yo-kai Watch Ogre along with...
these other goods together as a set!
It's the Yo-kai Watch Ogre set!
And...
(Immovable Thunder)
In addition to that, the Deluxe Fudou Raimei Sword with...
these other goods! Together as the Fudou Raimei Sword Set!
By a random lottery, 15 winners will be selected!
For the Yo-kai Watch Ogre Set, call 0180-999-871
(Immovable Thunder)
For the Fudou Raimei Sword Set, call 0180-999-871 by telephone!
It's so hard to choose between the two!
I'll definitely win something!
And I'll get Natsume as a prize too!
Sure. Make sure you don't get that telephone number wrong!
We'll be waiting to receive your applications!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Hey guys, did you know about this?
There's a popular card game...
(Lighting Speed Era)
People who play Denkousekka Jidai are getting attacked, one after another!
Huh? I play that game too!
It's a boy in a red hat who snatches away your cards.
They say when he uses cards, unthinkable things will happen.
We should investigate this case!
Next time, on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
(Plundering Demon)
Ryakudatsuma Red Head