Thank you very much.
Whew!
That was a good meal.
You've got some food left over.
But I feel really full.
What a waste.
What's wrong?
What a waste...
Tonkotsu
Life
S-Some weird guy's here...
There's no one here.
Leave some for me!
Give me more and more!
Tonkotsu
Life
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
(What A Waste Man)
The tale this time of Mottainai Otoko is a frightening story.
He is rumored to appear in front of those who leave behind food.
"What a waste..." he whispers into their ears.
Perhaps he'll appear in front of you too?
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko
Oooh!
What do you think of this post?
Huh... Seems like a pretty interesting opinion.
Not bad! Not bad!
Looks like the two of you are finally starting to give your best for the agency!
So... What kind of case are you looking at?
What in the world is this?
It's a review site for a ramen restaurant.
Ooh, this seems pretty good....
I mean... if we're going to talk about food, then look at this!
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko?
That's right.
Posts about him have been multiplying recently.
What is he?
He appears before children who leave behind food,
and says, "What a waste" before possessing them.
Then, he takes away the child's appetite, leading to weakened bodies and weight loss, and they eventually die.
Weight loss, huh?
Ha ha ha!
Looks like you're getting worked up about nonsense again!
So you've come, Keisuke.
Looks like everyone in the agency is finally here!
No no no!
I don't remember joining!
-Alright, everyone!
(What A Waste Man)
Let's think about who Mottainai Otoko might be!
Huh?
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko, huh?
What could his goals possibly be..?
People who are possessed lose their appetite.
Does just looking at him cause you to lose your appetite?
How could that happen?
Maybe...
...He's a scarecrow monster who resurrects leftover veggies as zombies?
No way... There's no such thing as a vegetable zombie!
Really?
Then why was your voice trembling?
Another possibility might be...
Maybe he's a rogue mutant with the power to cover food with mold...
Mold!?
That'd spoil anyone's appetite.
Ha ha ha ha...
What are you guys saying?
There's no evidence of hauntings by these monsters and such. So I don't believe it!
In that case...
Let's show you the evidence then.
(What A Waste Man)
I'm most interested in Mottainai Otoko's motives.
He must have a grudge on people who waste food.
Natsume...
What's wrong?
I've noticed just now...
...That the victims have something in common.
Something in common?
According to posts on the Usuranura site,
At this ramen restaurant,
(What A Waste Man)
many people saw Mottainai Otoko.
Thanks for waiting.
This is your Super Mega Sized Ramen.
Here you go, too.
Woah...
Nobody can possibly eat this much.
Anyway, let's try eating it!
Now that was a meal!
That was surprisingly good!
I'm stuffed!
Ah.... Aaaaaah!!
(What A Waste Man)
We can't lure out Mottainai Otoko if we finish off everything!
I see... What about Touma?
Thanks for the meal.
What?
Wasn't that the normal size?
That's right.
There'll be nothing for us to investigate at this rate!
I didn't want to eat too much anyway.
How about Keisuke's ramen?
Ah!
That's right.
Take it easy and leave some behind.
I can take it...
(What A Waste Man)
If you don't eat it all, Mottainai Otoko will appear for sure, right?
Th... There's no such thing!
Then it's fine for you to leave some behind.
W... Well... Overeating is bad for you...
So let's stop for now...
What a waste...
Natsume...!
There's someone at that seat!
There's nobody there.
Wha... What was that...?
So I was just seeing things...
What a waste...
H... He... He was under the table!
Doesn't look like anything's there to me.
No no no no.... He was here!
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko was definitely here!
Touma! Akinori! Behind you!
I didn't see anything...
(What A Waste Man)
Keisuke, only you see Mottainai Otoko, right?
Yeah... Anyway...
Tonkotsu
Life
He was staring at me the whole time just now...
Why can't we see him, though...?
That's right!
I heard about this from Grandma!
There are Yo-kai with special energy resonance who can only be seen by those they possess!
Huh!?
What a waste...
If you're not eating it... Give it to me....
Leaving ramen behind is a waste...
It's a waste...
More...
Tonkotsu
Life
Give me more...!
Tonkotsu
Life
Thank you very much!
Are you sure you don't want us to come with you?
It's fine. He's with me.
If anything happens, be sure to call us.
Got it.
Is Keisuke going to be okay?
I'm kinda worried.
Today's gratin is delicious!
Isn't it?
I bought better macaroni this time.
Hmm?
What's wrong, Keisuke?
You haven't eaten at all...
No.... I'm not feeling that hungry.
Tonkotsu
Life
Are you alright, Keisuke?
Keisuke?
Why is he in my house?
He takes away the child's appetite, leading to weakened bodies and weight loss, and they eventually die.
Don't tell me... Am I going to die?
Are you.... leaving that behind?
What a waste...
Hey, Keisuke.
(What A Waste Man)
Is Mottainai Otoko here right now?
As if that's possible!
I mean, you haven't eaten dinner at all...
-I'm not feeling that hungry! That's all!
Wait, Keisuke!
So stubborn...
Keisuke, you haven't eaten at all.
I haven't felt hungry since last night.
Did you catch a cold?
Maybe you should visit the nurse?
Are you not eating that?
What a waste...
I can't take it anymore.
I know I'm starving, but I don't have an appetite.
But if I don't eat anything, I'll die...
How about ramen?
Alright...
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko doesn't exist... He doesn't exist...!
It's all a dream!
That's right...
(What A Waste Man)
There's no such thing as Mottainai Otoko...
I've lost my appetite, but I must eat.
Give it to me...
You're leaving it behind, aren't you?
Ramen...
If you're leaving it behind...
Give it to me...!
What a waste!
Give me more...!
I'm home.
Stay away!
Keisuke!
Keisuke! Are you okay?
Listen. Drop the act and answer me.
(What A Waste Man)
He's here, isn't he? Mottainai Otoko.
Yeah...
Natsume...
Save me...
How could this happen?
That seems pretty tough.
(What A Waste Man)
We need to drive away Mottainai Otoko as soon as possible.
Do you have any information about his true form?
According to what Keisuke said,
It came after him when he tried to eat some ramen.
The reports from the Usuramera site about ramen restaurants...
seem to be connected with this!
Yeah.
Was there anything distinctive about him, Keisuke?
Umm...
He seemed to be pretty muscular.
Did you mean like this?
Muscular!
Anything else?
We got ignored!
Shocking!
Ah, something was written on his t-shirt!
Tonkotsu
Life
(pork belly soup)
It said, "Tonkotsu Life"
Tonkotsu
Life
(pork belly soup)
Tonkotsu Life?
Wait...
There was a t-shirt like that...
Huh?
Right here!
See?
Tonkotsu
Life
Was it this t-shirt?
Yeah! It was this one!
(What A Waste Man)
So was this person Mottainai Otoko?
No. It's the same shirt, but he was a different person.
Huh?
Umattei
Closed
Isn't this store closed for business?
Seriously?
But they were quite good...
Anyway, let's check it out.
We might find some clues.
Umattei
We are closed
for business.
Thank you for your
long-standing
patronage
-Store owner
Of course it's closed.
Umattei
Just when I thought we had a promising lead...
We are closed
for business.
Thank you for your
long-standing
patronage
-Store owner
Huh?
The soup's boiling...
Welcome...
Please have a seat...
There... Please have a taste of our best ramen.
Huh?
Ra... Ramen!?
How did this get here...?
Wha... What do we do?
We've got no choice but to eat up...
It looks just like ordinary ramen...
Huh?
Will you not eat it?
What a waste...
What a waste!
Sniveling brats who leave behind ramen....
...And sneaky, nosy busybodies...
Useless....  They're all useless...!
(What A Waste Man)
Is this Mottainai Otoko!?
I had a bad feeling...
...so I think so!
Let's retreat for now!
Yeah!
No way!
It won't budge!
-Here, too!
You can't run!
It's useless!
Ramen is delicious, isn't it!?
Disgusting!
I'll handle this!
Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
Possession! Genma Benkei! Lend me your strength!
Nine o'clock. Benkei.
Benkei... has arrived!
(pork belly soup)
Tonkotsu...!
What a powerful charge...!
Seriously? Benkei is getting pushed back!
Ramen...!
That ramen...
I see...!
Touma! Summon Omatsu!
Possession! Genma Omatsu! Lend me your strength!
Three o'clock. Omatsu.
I am the healer of all living beings...
Omatsu. I am your opponent.
W-Wel... Welcome!
Please sit at the counter!
Will you still fight?
I give up...
That's incredible, Natusme!
How'd you know Omatsu would be effective?
(What A Waste Man)
I saw that Mottainai Otoko had a weakness for ladies.
(pork belly)
My ramen had much more charshuu in it.
Because...
Ladies who come to our restaurant should be treated preciously.
What?
Ha ha ha ha!
My name is...
(Round Pot)
Zundonmaru!
Zun! Don!
Who is this?
(What A Waste Man)
Looks like he's Mottainai Otoko's Lightside form?
Seriously? He seems even more terrible!
Stop harassment!
I won't allow such rude acts in front of Natsume!
Muscle!
What are they doing?
I have no idea.
Muscle!
They seem to be getting along...
Is it because they're both wierdos?
(Round Pot)
Hey, Zundonmaru...
(What A Waste Man)
Why did you become Mottainai Otoko and do all those things?
Well... about my true form...
I spent my life as a pot in this ramen restaurant.
Umattei
This restaurant was always loved by the locals.
The Large Perfect Volume Ramen, was the owner’s pride and joy.
It's a dish that always made customers smile.
But after a few decades...
The owner aged.
Even with shoulder and back pain...
He kept toiling every day to make ramen... But...
His body reached its limit.
And finally... The owner decided to close the store.
We are closed
for business.
Thank you for your
long-standing
patronage
-Store owner
And finally, in my heart...
I continued to feel the ache of being an empty pot.
And before I knew it, I became a Yo-kai.
Before long, I became jealous of those...
whose hearts and bellies were satisfied enough to leave food behind.
And from that vile thought,
(What A Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko was born.
Even though I'm a pot who'd be satisfied just by being filled with ramen.
That seems pretty sad...
But what can we do?
Can my skills live up to yours, dad?
I don't know that.
The world won't go easy on you.
Is that the owner?
Looks like his son is taking over.
All we do as restaurant owners...
...is pursue the flavors that satisfy the customer.
Running a restaurant also means facing the tough things that make you want to quit.
But you know...
When a customer lets you know how good the food is, your troubles go away.
I see...
If you choose to inherit the restaurant, I'll entrust this to you.
Dad, this is your...
I've had this ever since I started running this place.
Hey... treat my son well, like you did with me, will you?
Yeah! Leave it to me, partner!
Zundoumaru
Umattei
Grand
Re-
Opening
Yeah! The flavor is just like the old man's!
I didn't think I would ever taste this again!
This really brings me back...
Thanks for waiting!
I'll have a large ramen!
Right away!
Ah... We're out of hot water.
Ha ha ha ha!
Looks like it's my turn!
(Round Pot)
Zundonmaru!
Can I help you?
If you need hot water, then leave it to me!
There!
Don't tell me...
Stop it!!!
Saki, want to go home together?
Sure!
You know, I've found another cute shop!
Really? Where?
Excuse my lateness.
The staff meeting was extended.
Any new clues?
None right now.
Nevertheless... The moment we'll find it is approaching.
Our princess...
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Hey, have you heard?
School kids are reporting that they feel like they're being watched by someone!
Isn't that Keisuke's school?
Keisuke, let's investigate!
I've got nothing to do with it!
You do.
What!?
There are dangerous things happening at school one after another!
And there's a love story behind it too!
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
An Anatomical Model in Love