Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 23 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Hey! Where is this place?
Somebody!
Is anyone here?!
Hey!
What is this?
Why is this happening?
[laughter]
"Why is this happening," you ask?
The answer to that is...
...because you were born with that face!
Of course!
M-Monster!
M-Monster?!
[laughter]
That's right! So I am a monster!
I must conduct myself like a proper monster, then!
[shrieking and laughter]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
This story is about a frightening doctor with the face of a chameleon.
Just what kind of tragedy awaits those kidnapped by him?
That's something you'll have to see for yourself.
The Dark Clinical Records of Doctor C
Good morning!
Good morning, Natsume.
Huh? What's wrong?
Ken Sakiyama announced that he's going on hiatus on the news this morning.
And...
Ken Sakiyama?!
Was he an enka singer?
No. That's wrong!
Ken Sakiyama is the most popular and the most handsome actor nowadays!
All the movies and dramas he's in turn into huge hits!
Today's
Ken
Sakiyama
Exclusive
recent
unauthorized
sneak peeks at
filming
locations
and private
info!
FULL CANDID
SHOTS
HOTTIE
Uh-huh.
Handsome actors have been announcing that they're going on hiatus one after another recently.
We wondered if Ken Sakiyama would finally end up being one of them.
Huh? So this Ken Sakiyama is not the only one who's taking a break?
Geez, you haven't been reading the news at all!
Everyone's calling it "the mystery of the nonstop hiatus announcements!"
Mystery of the nonstop hiatus announcements?
Yeah.
That's been talked about a lot.
It's the hottest topic on Usuranura as well.
You mean that this case is Yo-kai related as well?
According to this post, there's a rumor that it's related to that serial disappearances case as well.
But wasn't that incident caused by Menkuiita going after handsome men?
(Man/Face Eater)
We've already solved that case.
So someone else must be involved this time, right?
Yeah. They might be the true culprit.
I see...
That's scary.
Have no fear, Ayame!
I, Akinori Arihoshi, will act as your bodyguard and protect you against any danger!
Thank you, Akinori!
Thank you, Akinori♪
I'll even jump into the fires of Hell to protect Ayame's smile.
And that's how roast pork is cooked.
HEY.
Every single actor on break went missing for several days.
Huh? What's that?
It's a post by someone in the industry.
[oink]
Maybe there's a reason why they went unaccounted for over that period.
News! Big news!
What is it, Keisuke?
Ken Sakiyama is at a park nearby!
Wha?!
Over here!
Where?
There! The bench below the tree!
Huh? That person?
Huh? But he looks just like a normal guy!
He doesn't have the aura of a celebrity at all.
I'm sure there's no mistake here!
Then why don't we go ask him?
Huh? What?
Um... May I have a moment?
Would you happen to be Ken Sakiyama?
Ah. You must know me well.
(Masked Bicycle Rider)
You're Kamen Charidaa after all!
Kamen Charidaa?
Ah, I know about that!
It's one of those tokusatsu shows you loved a long time ago, right?
Uh-huh!
Transform!
(Masked Bicycle Rider)
Kamen Charidaa!
2 HOURS NO CHARGE
EVERY 12 HOURS
YEN
Higashitachi Group Coin-op Parking Lot
Dedicated to Traffic Laws! Kamen Charidaa!
I remember now! You were in that show!
Thank you.
That was a pretty old show.
I'm happy that you remembered me.
Kamen Charidaa was the first role I ever acted in. It means a lot to me.
But...
After the incident happened...
...you were the only people who recognized me.
What happened?
Did something happen during the days you went missing, perhaps?
We're investigating the reason for the continuous hiatus announcements.
On behalf of you and the other actors,
and for the fans, too. We want to help solve this.
I understand.
But I don't know if I can explain it properly.
I was going home from work that day.
Then someone attacked me.
The next thing I remember was being tied up in a decrepit hospital.
Why is this happening?
[laughter]
"Why is this happening," you ask?
The answer to that is...
...because you were born with that face!
Of course!
A chameleon monster?
Not only that...
...it was wearing a medical uniform.
Medical unform?
And it said this after removing its mask:
I am Doctor Chameleon.
Doctor Chamelon?
I don't have a formal medical license, though.
[Laughter]
What are you doing?
"W-What are you doing?"
[Laughter]
I'm starting the medical procedure to remove your aura of handsomeness.
That's good. Very.
Very!
I'll erase the handsomeness from everyone in the world just like this.
[Laughter]
-I passed out after that.
When I woke up, I found myself laying where I was attacked.
What do you think?
Doctor Chameleon...
Without a doubt, it's a Yo-kai.
F-For real?
Mr. Sakiyama, do you know where that hospital is?
Do you really believe me?
Yes!
I believe you.
Me too.
Alright, I get it! I believe it, too!
Thank you.
In any case, do you have any clues or info for us to follow up on?
That's right...
My smartphone should've tracked my location.
But who knows what other dangers lurk in that hospital.
Hospital
Please, just don't go there by yourselves.
Sakiyama warned us about coming here ourselves!
He just warned us!
So why did we come anyway?!
Who else can handle these Yo-kai cases?
You've got the Yo-kai Watch this time. So don't be such a scaredy-cat.
B-b-but...
Ah, that's right, Natsume...
Can you lend me some of your ar...
-Whis!
Here's some arks.
[Keisuke shrieks in fear]
Geez. Don't just pop in like that, Whisper!
Ah. I had no intention of perturbing you.
Whis?
Come on out, my friend!Jibanyan!
[Jibanyan hissing]
Umm... What?
Jibanyan! Attack that white blobby thing!
Keisuke, no!
I don't know what's going on.
But there's a job you've summoned me to do.
[Whisper squeals in fear]
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
[Whisper moaning]
-Ha! Doing that felt kind of nostalgic.
My body remembers this feeling, too...
I-Is Whisper going to be alright?
He'll live.
In Progress
Operation
You brats... For what reason have you come?
I have no quarrel with you.
Operation
In Progress
If you don't want to die, then leave.
Operation
In Progress
You're Doctor Chameleon, right?
Operation
In Progress
Show yourself!
Operation
In Progress
I don't know who you are.
But if you attempt to interfere with my goals,
nobody will go home alive.
I'll dissect you all without anesthetics!
[laughter]
SHADOWSIDE
Now, who shall I disect first?!
So this is Doctor Chameleon.
Jibanyan, please!
Yeah. I'll handle it!
[laughter]
"Yeah. I'll handle it!"
What about it, punk?
[laughter]
[gasps]
W-What's this?
[hiss]
No way!
It transformed into Jibanyan?!
Tch!
How dare you mock me!
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
Ora ora ora ora ora!
[laughter]
Damn it!
What an annoying prick!
Jibanyan!
He can even mimic abilities because he's a chameleon?
He's a real dangerous one.
You all seem to be in some trouble!
Huh?
Ha!
Huh? Tch!
Materialization!
Hyper Micchi!
Landing!
Allow me to explain:
Hyper Micchi can Hyper Materialize the Hyper Micchi Cloak, Hyper Micchi Suit, Hyper Micchi Belt, Hyper Micchi Gloves, Hyper Micchi Boots and Hyper Micchi Pants in only 0.2 seconds!
A wordy explanation, as usual.
And it's even more needlessly detailed than last time.
[laughter]
Huh?
Now he's Hyper Micchi too?!
And because the Hyper Micchi Suit is hyper stuffy and hyper hot,
The amount of time I can remain as Hyper Micchi is hyper limited!
And he's finishing his lines, too.
It's double the sweatiness and dorkiness.
Hey, you!
It appears that you, my opponent, has about the same burliness as I do!
It appears that you've got muscles as splendid and undistorted as mine!
They're buttering each other up.
Now it's four times the dorkiness.
We love muscle!
Oh, no! Time's up!
[laughter]
Spinning and spinning! Oh dear!
I knew this would happen.
He's never going to give up, is he?
What's wrong? Is that all you've got?
It's my turn!
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
[chanting]
Yoshitsune has arrived.
Huh? You... You're a handsome one, aren't you?
I'll erase handsomeness from everyone in the world!
Now he's copied Yoshitsune?
He can even transform into a Genma?
[yelling]
No matter how strong his opponent is, he'll mimic them into a stalemate!
What do we do?
That's right!
Whisper! Give me the arks!
Sure-whis!
If only we could use that Yo-kai.
Right on! Keisuke!
Huh?
Summon that Yo-kai!
Huh? Uh-huh.
Touma! It's time to tag out!
Understood.
Now, Keisuke!
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out, my friend! Junior!
It's me, Jii!
Hey, Doctor Chameleon!
Let's see if you can shapeshift better than Junior!
Uh-huh.
Let's have a contest to see who can shapeshift the best!
Da ze!
And the subject you'll be copying is...Whisper!
Huh?!
Whis?!
Oh-ho!
You think you can steal the look of the Yo-kai World's dandiest Yo-kai?
Jii hates it, but he'll be Whisper.
-Excuse me? What did you say just now?
I'm reluctant to mimic such an ugly form, but...
Hey! I can hear you!
Now! Jibanyan! Get him!
[hiss]
Whissu?!
Drop dead!
Huh?
Alright!
Da ze?!
What in the world?!
Dr. Chameleon doesn't mimic just looks.
He replicates everything else, too.
In other words, when he copied Whisper,
he faithfully copied Whisper's uselessness and powerlessness!
Of course!
Whis!
Huh?
Ugh...
Hey! Doctor Chameleon!
My lightside is called Leon.
I see.
So, Leon, why did you steal handsomeness auras?
It's because I hate those jerks you call handsome actors.
Do you have a grudge against them?
Yeah.
What happened?
[sigh]
Before I became a Yo-kai,
I used to be an actor when I was a human.
Really?
I was so admired, they called me the chameleon actor.
Chameleon actor?
Just like a chameleon, I could blend into any scene.
I was an actor who could act any role.
Ah, you must be...
The late actor Kenzou Takita?
Thanks to my well-respected acting ability, many jobs came my way.
I wound up costarring with many handsome actors.
You've got a problem with how I do things, huh?
Huh?
C'mon c'mon, whatcha gonna do?
When I off you, I'll end the kid right after, too!
[laughter]
My roles always wound up being the antagonist to the good-looking main characters.
I got more and more villainous roles.
Out of curiosity, one day, I read up on what people thought of me on the Internet.
But I could only find words of hatred for me from fans of the handsome actors.
(Anonymous)
Takita is srsly the WORST
takita go KYS
just looking at him pisses me off
quit messing with sakiyama
He's def not putting up an act right? lol He h8s him 4 real lol
takita be power tripping nuff said lol
lolololololololololololololol
Before long, it started spreading outside posts on the Internet.
Wasn't that Kenzou Takita just now?
Seriously? Isn't he the guy who bullies Ken Sakiyama?
He's the worst!
Even in my everyday life, hatred showed up everywhere.
Before long, my own hatred for handsome actors grew worse.
Professor. It's over for you now.
Damn it!
If only...! If only you weren't here!
Isn't Takita yelling a bit too loud?
[gasping]
Takita!
Right up until my own death, I was consumed by my hatred of handsome actors.
Before I knew it, this is the form I changed into.
So that was the reason you stole the handsomeness auras.
Handsome actors have it good, don't they.
They've got fans bawling just by going on hiatus.
But not a single person cried for me when I died.
You're wrong!
Hm?
A-Ayame?
I learned that you died when I saw the news.
But right afterwards, this video was uploaded. Didn't you know?
Video? "Thank you, Mr. Takita?"
Thank You
Mr.Takita
Takita, you were always there for me when I had trouble performing.
If it weren't for you, Takita, I wouldn't have been an actor.
Thank you so much, Takita.
We acted together on dramas, plays and movies...
Takita...I'm...
Takita.
Because of your encouragement, I was able to do my best acting.
To Charidaa, you were his greatest rival.
But to me, you were an inspirational hero.
I'll never forget you.
Truly...
Thank you very much!
What is this?
Is this how those guys remember me?
Those actors didn't do anything wrong.
Why don't you turn them back to normal?
Hah!
Even the most terrible actor can express such superficial lines.
That's not true!
They all really cared about you, Takita!
But still...
There's no need for me to hold on to this.
Huh? That's...
Are those the handsomeness auras you stole?
They're flying back to the other actors.
See ya later.
Umm...!
Thank you very much!
No. Thank you.
Thanks a lot, little girl!
Farewell!
Sakiyama's coming back!
Good thing!
Isn't it?
It's not just Sakiyama, but all the other actors are coming back too.
I guess it's case closed.
(Man/Face Eater)
But between this case and Menkuiitaa,
handsome people sure get attacked by Yo-kai a lot.
I wouldn't expect any more Yo-kai incidents involving handsome people.
I know right?
Well, it's just like what I've said long ago.
What happens twice shall happen thrice.
Huh?
Ayame, did you say something?
Huh? What did I say?
Something about twice or thrice?
Something about lunch?
[gasping]
Stay away! What do you want with me?!
The princess requires beautiful men as nourishment.
You've interfered without permission.
Such sin is unforgivable.
You'll serve as an example for the other Yo-kai.
You will be dealt with now.
Damn it!
[yelling]
What is this power?! It's so strong, I can't copy it!
Idiot.
Don't compare me to weakling freaks like yourself.
Help... Me...
No.
[splatter]
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is the Detective Agency Office!
Detective
Agency Offices
It's our base for day-to-day activites.
Actually, it's just my room!
What? You knew just by looking?
Equipped with air conditioning!
Furnished with a refrigerator!
And set up with Internet access!
Isn't it perfect?!
But there's just one bad thing...
The bathroom's in the main house! It sucks to have to go when it rains!
Detective
Agency Offices
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
Terrible things are happening in the Hana Hana Family Land amusement park!
Eep!
Children who play with this costumed character revert to a baby-like state!
Its name is Hana Poncho!
It's a mascot character that should have disappeared long ago!
So why is it doing that to the kids?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Dreaming Hana Poncho
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs