Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 11 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
I am a cat Yo-kai.
My name is Jibanyan.
I have no memory of my past.
There are a lot of things I don't know about myself.
Yeah. For example...
Why is there a notch on my ear?
Did somone else leave that notch?
And there are other things I don't know.
It's been beloved for over 30 years, and now it's even more delicious!
Why? Why do I have this craving for chocolate?
And why two tons of it?
Why?
Why is it that when I see these four-wheeled things, I'm filled with rage?
And what I know least of all...
Why can't I help but let my feelings soften up whenever I see them?
Yes. By that I mean...
...schoolgirls.
When I see girls of that age, these tender feelings begin welling up.
Why do I feel this way when I see schoolgirls?
If I look into it, I might be able to get back these lost memories.
No... I'll get them back for sure.
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
I am a Cat Yo-kai
That day, I was lying in wait for those detestable trucks as always.
Ahh, damn. There aren't any cars big enough.
I can't get any satisfaction sending some small fry flying.
A schoolgirl, huh?
What's this?
When I laid eyes on that schoolgirl, these feelings welled up within my chest.
It was a feeling that was somehow different from when I looked at any other girl.
It's the first time I've felt this.
Why can't I take my eyes away from her?
Is it because her skirt is 15 centimeters above her knees?
Is it because of the slight scent of Champagne Rose shampoo wafting toward me?
I could feel that this schoolgirl was someone special for some reason.
(Reapers)
Shinigami?
That must mean that schoolgirl is...
...destined to lose her life today?
(Reapers)
It's pitiful that someone that young is about to be taken by Shinigami.
But the fate decided by the Shinigami is absolute.
Anyone who defies such a fate will not be forgiven.
Anyone... Anyone...
Tsk! I went and did it.
But why?
(Reapers)
Interfering with the Shinigami is foolishness!
Even if my mind knew that, my body moved on its own to save this girl...
But why?
What's happening... to me?
Wait!
What?
U-Um... Thank you very much! For saving me.
If you weren't here to save me, I would have...
Hey, you. You can see me?
Ah... yeah.
Why is that? I am a Yo-kai. Normal humans shouldn't even be able to see me.
Ah. It might be something I've inherited.
My mom also see things sometimes.
Inheritance, huh?
Children take after their parents, for better or worse.
Aaah, geez!
This is going to be quite problematic.
We were on a strict schedule.
Schedule?
Yes. We are supposed to reap your soul.
What?!
You. Cat Yo-kai!
Please don't interfere with our work this time.
As a fellow Yo-kai,
(reapers)
you ought to know that interfering with shinigami is illegal.
Sure.
(reapers)
One must not hinder shinigami from reaping souls, no matter who the human is.
Exactly.
We'll be willing to overlook your interference just now.
Please don't interfere with our work this time.
Alright...
Do it.
No!
Bastard!
Again?!
Hey! After them!
I don't know... why am I even doing this?
We lost sight of them.
Yes?
What is your status?
We've encountered unexpected interference.
Interference?
Yes.
The human we were scheduled to reap was abducted by a Yo-kai, who then fled.
Why would a Yo-kai do something like this?
Anyway,
as you already know, once someone has been registered to the list...
...we must take their souls without fail.
(reapers)
That is our utmost duty as shinigami.
I understand.
I will be expecting better news.
Tch!
Easier said than done!
Hide here for now.
Where is this?
This is my one and only hideout.
Nyan Reno?
Who is this?
An actor that I've been interested in recently.
Hey... why were they targeting me?
I'm just an ordinary schoolgirl!
I haven't done anything bad.
And I haven't even witnessed any crimes, either!
So why?!
(reaper's)
Your name wound up on the shinigami's list.
(reaper)
Shinigami?
Yeah.
Once you're on that list, they'll do anything take your soul.
(reaper's)
That's the shinigami's mission.
If they take my soul, will I die?
Yeah.
Why me? I'm still just a high school student!
There are still things I want to do!
I've got dreams for the future...
Dreams?
I want to be a designer, just like my mom.
Designer?
What was that...? Was that one of my memories just now?
Mom...
Huh?
Don't just stand there. Sit.
Thank you.
What is your mother like?
Huh?
Your mom, I meant.
My mom fulfilled her childhood dreams and became a designer.
She's made a lot of wonderful clothes.
I've always wanted to be just like my mom.
I guess that's not happening...
Charge!
Stay here and don't move.
Tch!
(reapers)
Picking a fight with the shinigami...
...what a stupid thing for me to do!
I... I'm getting the feeling that I know you...
What?
What was that memory?
Do I also know this schoolgirl?
I feel like I know her from long ago.
Damn!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
That thieving little cat Yo-kai!
Absolutely unforgivable!
I will tear his soul into pieces!
They'll find this place too.
Let's rest before we move on.
I don't even know your name yet.
My name is Miho.
I'm...
I just realized something.
Come!
I'll lure them away. Escape when you get the chance.
But what about you, old guy?
I'll handle myself somehow.
Wait!
You've been quite the troublemaker, haven't you?
If you'd like, then help yourself to some more!
Give us the girl.
Just leave and never come back.
Finish him.
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
How uncouth.
Why are you going so far just to protect a little girl?
Heh. That's what I'd like to know too.
Hmph. Very well.
Let's take care of this before we have to work overtime.
No! No! Let go of me!
Miho!
Old guy...
Damn...
Just stay still and look.
You'll get your payback for messing with us.
However... The girl gets it first.
May you live as long as possible in your next life.
Old guy!
Miho. Run and save yourself!
Never! I didn't even get your name!
My name is...
...Jibanyan...
Jibanyan?!
Jibanyan! Jibanyan! Jibanyan!
Jibanyan...
Good riddance. He's finally dropped dead.
Alright.
Let's grab the girl's...
Hmm?
Hello?
What is the situation?
We had some trouble, more or less.
But we're about to extract the soul from our target.
Actually, there's been a bit of a clerical error.
What?
That girl you're after...
...she lives at Sakuramoto-machi 3-3-3 and her name is Miho. Am I correct?
That's the info you gave us in the documents, boss.
That may be so, but...
The soul we were supposed to take today...
...lives in Sakuramoto-machi 3-33-3...
...and she's actually old lady Mizuho, age 133.
Someone must have accidentally removed a few threes.
And the names "Miho" and "Mizuho" are very similar.
By the way, about old lady Mizuho...
She was visited by family this morning, and was found to have passed away.
She seems to already be in a standby queue headed to Heaven.
And that is why I'd like you to offer Miss Miho our sincerest apology on our behalf.
Thanks.
Argh! Quit messing with me!
Umm... May I have a word with you?
This is extremely difficult to admit, but...
It appears that we have made a bit of a mistake.
Let us meet again some other day, when you get the chance to discuss the matter more thoroughly.
We truly are very sorry.
Farewell...
That's all we have to say for now.
Hey.
Hold it.
You guys just opened up this huge hole in my gut...
...and you think you're gonna walk away just like that? Huh?
S-So you were alright!
Jibanyan!
Does this look "alright" to you?
You owe me some compensation!
Compensation?!
Gimme 2 tons of chocobars. Right now!
S-Such short notice!
Besides, we must consult our lawyers...
Is that so? Well then...
I guess we have a failure to negotiate!
I should really quit this job!
It's okay.
Let my mom treat those wounds for you.
We're getting close to home. Keep going!
Miho?
Mom!
Umm... you see...
You... can see me?
I can see you.
(Rudy)
You're Akamaru, right?
What?
(Rudy)
Akamaru...
Akamaru!
(Rudy)
We meet again, right? Akamaru!
I...I'm...
That's right...
I...
I remember!
That's right!
(Amy)
(Rudy)
That's right! I used to be Emi's cat, Akamaru!
That's right!
I died that day and became a Yo-kai.
I remember now!
I remember how I became a Yo-kai! I remember it all now!
Ah! Your stomach is healed!
Remembering everything must have completed me somehow.
(Rudy)
Akamaru.
I wanted to see you.
Me too!
I see...
I felt like I knew Jibanyan was because he was Akamaru all along.
And I must have been interested in you...
...because I sensed that you were Emi's daughter all along!
Hey, Akamaru.
What is it, Emi?
Since you're here, I want to do something with you that I've always wanted.
Is that alright?
Of course! Anything you want!
Yay!
Isn't this fun? Akamaru?
Thanks for saving my daughter.
Thanks a lot, Jibanyan!
Yeah... See you later.
Let's meet again, Akamaru!
I am a cat Yo-kai.
I've finally gotten back these precious memories.
Never again... will I forget.
And that's how Jii was born!
Ho ho~. So that's what happened.
A lot of things happened since I've become a Yo-kai too.
By the way, I was crushed to death by a komainu statue.
And that's how I wound up like this.
Komasan, that's sad.
Well, same story here.
Such is life.
Along with the Ashira Gouenmaru sword that you have,
(Yo-kai holy swords)
once we have the five youseiken,
we'll be able to awaken the princess's power.
Yes.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
But, if we are to take the Fudou Raimei Sword from Touma Tsukinami...
(Acala)
...then we'll be forced to fight Fudou Myouou.
It won't be easy to do.
It wouldn't be any fun to just take it by force anyway.
And this one?
I'll leave the particulars to you.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Go ahead and take the Fudou Raimei Sword for us.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Trivia
Akinori's
SHADOWSIDE
Today, let's talk about Usuranura!
Various reports of Yo-kai related incidents are posted on this site!
Incidents of scientifically unprovable acts of Yo-kai are endless!
As the Yo-kai Detective Agency, we check Usuranura every day...
...and we act to help the victims who post there
By the way, what in the world does "Usuranura" even mean?
Hmm... That's another mystery for us to solve!
Hey, have you all heard?
About the perfect fortune teller, Sendo Rei?
She can predict anything perfectly!
What?
We went to visit Sendo Rei, the fortuneteller!
And Touma had his fortune told!
Huh? I can see a majin behind me...
(spirit)
What?
(Acala)
Is that about Fudou Myouou?
How does she know?
This person's dangerous!
She's definitely a super perfect sexy dangerous fortuneteller!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
Touma's Imprisonment