The Movie
Shadowside:
Revival of the Oni King
Yo-kai Watch the Movie Shadowside: Revival of...
MICCHI
MCiCHI
MIIICHI
MICCHI
Yo-kai Micchi the Movie Shadowside: Revival of the Oni King
Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 25 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Bweh-heh-heh-heh-heh!
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
I am the Oni King, Rasen!
I shall destroy this world by my own hands!
Kyaa! Help me!
Tch! Us small fries are too weak to be a match for him!
If he were here... If only he were here...
Bweh-heh-heh-heh-heh-heh-heh!
Stop right there, Oni King Rasen!
Who are you?
I am the muscle of justice who smashes the wicked! A super macho hero!
Micchi has arrived!
Aaah! My beloved Micchi!
Take this! Micchi Beam!
Guah! I'm beaten!
In the face of an attack by the cool, strong, and macho Micchi,
I, Rasen shall die immediately!
And that's exactly what happened!
The End
I defeated Oni King Rasen, who threatened the world with destruction.
And I also splendidly saved my beloved Natsume!
Nah. That's a lie.
Yes! A complete fib!
Whoa! Since when were you here?
Just who the heck were you calling a "small fry?"
Shall I tell him what really happened?
Alright.
We transformed into our shadow sides and challenged Rasen.
But our enemy was formidable.
None of our soultimate attacks could connect at all.
Whoa, Komasan is great at drawing!
What an unexpected talent!
Da ze!
Micchi, as Mitsumatanodzuchi, was quite easily defeated before he could land a single hit.
No!
That's not how I remember it at all!
You really are useless.
Muscles is weak.
He was defeated in just five seconds.
Muscles is inept.
So who really beat Rasen in the end?
It was Touma, right?
-Whis!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
He used the Fudou Raimei Ken and sliced him!
It was so cool!
Jii wanted to see it too!
I didn't do it alone.
It was also thanks to Natsume, Akinori, and the rest of the Yo-kai.
So Micchi wasn't really that important after all.
He made no difference at all
[sigh]
And I spent all night drawing those pictures!
But now I finally get why Natsume always thinks you're useless.
Ouch.
Useless
Even though you act like her "knight," you're annoying and creepy looking.
Ouch. Ouch!
Annoying
Creepy
Muscles is stinky!
Useless
Annoying
OUCH!
Creepy
Stinky
By the way, where's Natsume?
She's not here.
Ah, she's with her friend toda -
-Oh, no!
Right after coming home from club activities today,
she's supposed to go shopping with her best friend, Saki!
Natsume's
Schedule
Why do you know that?
Muscles is such a stalker.
I shouldn't be here!
As Natsume's knight, I must march out!
I'm coming, Natsume! Natsume! Natsume!
There he goes.
I hope he doesn't do anything unnecessary.
Yeah.
Jii's worried about Natsume.
Should we go after him?
What do you think, Jibanyan?
What a pain. Just let him be.
Oh, my beloved Natsume!
Micchi
She must be shivering in fear without me!
By these muscles I so pride myself on, I'll have you in my arms before long!
Please wait for me!
[Laughter]
I've finally found you. I will never forgive you!
Mitsumatanodzuchi.
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
The story this time is about Mitsumatanodzuchi, also known as Micchi.
This Yo-kai has a hidden past.
But is it filled with nice and beautiful memories?
No. It seems that there is a Yo-kai who is holding onto intense hatred.
And when they attack Micchi, will it end tragically for him?
Farewell, Micchi
Natsume, did you find something you like?
Yeah. I'll go try these real quick.
[Humming]
Your knight, Micchi, has arrived!
Natsume...
You're just tired.
Micchi has -
Micchi has arrived!
[Natsume screaming]
Huh? What's wrong, Natsume?
Nothing! Everything is alright!
What are you doing here, Micchi?
I am your knight.
I shall watch over you as your bodyguard!
What? C'mon, gimme a break.
Oh, dear. He is annoying her as usual.
Muscles is annoying and ugly.
By the way, what about Komasan?
Pee.
Hey, are you marking your territory again?
That was pretty cute!
Yeah.
♪And I~♪
Oh my. Where is he going?
What's this?! A shameless pick-up artist?
Punishment!
Are you okay?
I, Micchi have exterminated that loathsome insect for you, Natsume!
Listen, Micchi. That person was only asking for directions.
Micchi!
Micchi. Micchi. Micchi. Micchi.
Thank you for waiting!
Natsume, you ordered a huge one!
No, no, no, no! I never ordered this!
Don't tell me...
It's Micchi's special deluxe mega-sized burger!
It contains 5x the meat and 10x the love and smiles!
Please eat up! Hahahahaha!
Ah! That's so cute!
Go ahead.
Thank you!
Special technique: Micchi Bartering!
I'd like this, please!
Huh?
[Scream]
Here you go, Natsume. You wanted this one, right?
You idiot!
What?
[Crying]
-Sorry about that!
I don't understand. Why is Natsume angry with me?
Muscles is stupid.
Oh, dear. Whis.
Just cut it out!
Everything you did was uncalled for!
Why would you make that little girl cry? You're the worst!
As your knight, I was only trying to support you from behind the scenes.
I already told you that I don't need it!
If you follow me any longer, I'll report you for being a stalker!
S-Stalker?!
Muscles turned white!
Looks like he's been burnt to white ash.
A knight and a stalker are as different as Heaven and Earth, isn't it?
Looks like he'll need some time to recover from this one.
See you again.
Yeah. Bye-bye.
Geez. What does he mean by "knight" anyway?
I didn't even ask for anyone to protect me.
[Snickering]
M-Mitsumatanodzuchi?
Are you Micchi?
[Laughing]
You're not him!
You've got Mitsumatanodzuchi enthralled with you, haven't you?
Who are you?
If you want to know, then ask him!
[Scream]
That's Natsume's scream!
Natsume!
That stalker sure came to faster than expected.
What's this?
"Mitsumatanodzuchi, I have your woman."
"If you want her back, then come to the abandoned factory on the outskirts of town."
What's wrong, Micchi?
Natsume's been abducted.
It was all my fault.
Despite being her knight, I let down my guard over her for only a moment!
I must save her immediately!
No way! Muscles is weak! And smelly! You'll lose!
We need to think of a plan!
[War cry]
He couldn't even wait before going.
Wait for me, Natsume.
Your knight Micchi will save you, even if it costs me my life!
Natsume!
SHADOWSIDE
[Slithering]
What?
Agh! Stop!
Natsume!
Micchi!
You came for me!
Ha!
Heaven calls! Earth calls! Natsume calls!
And I call myself the rescuing knight!
Super macho hero!
Micchi has arrived!
Too long!
I'm happy you're here, though.
[Rattling]
You haven't changed at all!
Ah! That voice!
I'm happy to see you again, Mitsumatanodzuchi!
Oh! Don't tell me, you're...!
[Cackling]
Mitsumatamidzuchi!
It's been much too long!
How about you show me your Mitsumata form, Mitsumatanodzuchi?
I am no longer Mitsumatanodzuchi!
I'm Micchi now, Mitsumatamidzuchi!
Ha! You've lost all pride as a Mitsumata, have you? Mitsumatanodzuchi!
And you're infatuated with being a Mitsumata as usual, Mitsumatamidzuchi!
Do you know each other?
Your names are so similar. It's confusing.
Long ago, we were a fearsome duo in the Yo-kai World. We were the Mitsumata Brothers.
Huh? Is that true?
Back then, we used to do all kinds of wicked things.
[Imitation motorcycle vocalization]
Sometimes, we would play doorbell pranks.
Let's
get along
Sometimes, we would spray graffiti on houses.
Let's
get along
The Mitsumata Brothers
were here!
We did all sorts of evil things that I'm disgusted just thinking about.
T-That's certainly evil.
And dumb.
We were bound by a steadfast friendship.
Hey Mitsumatamidzuchi. Good thing we were born as Mitsumata. This is the best!
That's right! Mitsumatanodzuchi!
But then, our friendship was suddenly destroyed!
Micchi has arrived!
Mitsumatanodzuchi! What is with that form?!
Didn't you hear? Hero Yo-kai are in fashion in the Yo-kai World! Zyuwa!
Hey! Where did your pride as a Mitsumata go?
Mitsumata? Nah. It looks too villainous and unpopular.
You ought to try this athletic humanoid look, too!
What?
It was then that I swore revenge against you for your betrayal.
I understand your feelings.
But you've made two mistakes.
Number one is getting my beloved Natsume involved!
The other one is...
Just when you looked kinda cool. Of course you'd go down in one shot.
Seems like you haven't been slacking, Mitsumatamidzuchi.
Nah, It seems like only you've gotten a lot weaker.
Then let me show you my new powers!
Materialization!
Hyper Micchi!
Allow me to explain:
Hyper Micchi can Hyper Materialize the Hyper Micchi Cloak, Hyper Micchi Suit...
Nobody needs an explanation!
Did you say "Hyper?!"
Let's go!
This power!
How's that? This is my true pow...
Huh?
Oh, no!
My grudge is no laughing matter!
Micchi!
[Laughing]
After I tear you in three, I'll turn you back into a Mitsumata!
[Screaming]
Micchi! Forget about me! Just run away!
I am Natsume's knight.
I will protect Natsume with my life!
-Shut up!
Why?
You're just Micchi!
You're just Micchi! Stop trying to show off!
What a bother! I'll burn you dead this instant!
Farewell, Mitsumatanodzuchi!
Micchi!
[Hissing]
What?
Geez. You're a weakling. Stop trying to act cool.
Jibanyan!
Oh dear, didn't you say before that going after Micchi was too much trouble?
Quiet, you.
You all...
Alright. Let's beat up this guy and go home already.
[Roaring]
Tch! Now I've got to use my trump card!
[Natsume screaming]
-Whis!
Natsume!
How do we fight an opponent like this?
Mitsumatamidzuchi's weakness is the middle head's eye!
Alright!
[Roaring]
How annoying!
Whis!
[Roaring]
It's... It's... It's no use!
That good-for-nothing!
[Roaring]
In this case...
Junior!
Jii?
Transform into this!
What's that?
It's a seesaw for throwing stones like a catapult.
Sounds fun! Jii will become a seesaw! Da ze!
Good. And now...
Ah! There it is!
Micchi Beam!
Micchi!
Whis!
Hey! What are you doing?
Soon, I'll completely turn into stone.
When I've turned to stone, catapult me into his eye!
What a perilous gamble!
Heh. I've changed my mind about you a little.
Standby OK! I leave it to you, Komasan!
Falling Hound Rock!
Take this! Micchi Missile!
[Roaring]
Natsume!
Micchi!
[Roaring]
[Natsume screaming]
Thank goodness. Natsume.
I've lost, Mitsumatanodzuchi.
No... Micchi!
I couldn't win by my power alone.
I won because of Natsume's love, and the power of my comrades.
Comrades, huh?
So you're not coming back to the Yo-kai World with me?
That's right. I will become a hero in this world.
Mitsumatamidzuchi, be the Mitsumata Hero in the Yo-kai World for me!
Yes. I swear on my pride as a Mitsumata.
And I on my pride as a Mitsumata.
Micchi!
Micchi! Get a hold of yourself!
Natsume.
Even in death I, Micchi...
...will be your knight forever.
Micchi! Don't die! You're my knight, aren't you?
C'mon. Answer back.
Micchi.
Micchi!
[Laughter]
Huh?
Natsume!
You've finally acknowledged me as your knight, right?
Huh?
Don't tell me.
OFFICIAL
Natsume's official knight!
Micchi has revived!
Micchi has revived! Micchi has revived!
Natsume! Micchi has revived!
What is this?
Well, that's one of his powers.
He can turn into stone and break into pieces and still come back.
That's right!
Of course. Now that I think about it, Yo-kai can't ever die, right?
As you said earlier, Natsume,
from now on, I will be your knight forever!
Ah-ha! I'm your knight! I'm Natsume's knight! A knight! A knight!
-Um... can I... take that back?
[Micchi gasping]
[Micchi yelling]
[Himeno giggling]
His face isn't my type at all.
But having a devoted gentleman doesn't sound so bad.
What are you doing?
I will always be at the princess's side doing wonderful knightly poses.
From now on and always, I will be the princess's knight!
Go away. Immediately.
Yes!
That's not what a knight is.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Jibanyan!
Jibanyan is a cat Yo-kai whose spirit is bound to a specific location.
Jibanyan
He loves chocolate so much, that when anything happens, he'll demand two tons of it immediately!
There's no way anyone has that many!
Jibanyan
His face is very frightening, but he's a reliable Yo-kai.
He really hates water, though. Whenever he's summoned next to water, he just goes home.
You're too temperamental, Jibanyan!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
Terrible things are happening around toilets lately!
Toilets?
Incredibly pained voices come out of them.
When people come to investigate and open the stall door...
BAM!
Aaaah!
A monster comes out and drags them into the toilet!
Yuck! That's terrible!
What kind of Yo-kai lurks in toilets?
I can't even imagine it.
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Demonic Man-Eating Toilet