Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 28 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Damn it!
Hey! Why did this have to happen?
Answer back, you!
You wanted money, didn't you?
It's just as you said.
You wanted to have large sums of cash.
All I did was lend some help.
This outcome was what you yourself wanted.
Quit fooling around!
This isn't what I wanted at all!
He's over there!
W-Wait a second! I was -
Hands up where we can see them!
I didn't want this...
Not this...
[Screaming]
Have a nice day.
What can I help
you with, boss?
Sebas
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
Every smartphone these days has virtual voice assistant functionality.
All you have to do is speak their name, and they can place calls for you or tell you the weather.
But if you grow to rely on them for absolutely everything, something terrible may happen.
The Cursed AI Assistant
Hey, Sebas! What time is it?
Sebas
“Sebas, what time is it?”
It's 3:35pm right now.
What's that?
Ah, is that the voice assistant app?
Yep. It's the artificial intelligence assistant, Sebas!
It's being used all over the world!
What do you use it for?
Right...I use it to help find directions.
Hey, Sebas. Tell me how to get to Sakura Seaside Mall.
Very well.
Wow.
That's incredible!
It'd be nice if I had a helpful assistant like that, too.
You rang?
Agh!
Geez, Keisuke! You've already got me, a super skilled, handsome and perfect butler.
Don't say you want another assistant, whis!
Ha, ha, ha! Whisper, a butler? Nice joke!
What's a butler?
Hmm... Very well.
Allow me to educate you on what a butler is.
A butler is a creature with soft fluffy hair that yells "baaah," whis!
Wait, that's not a butler! That's a sheep!
Agh! I had no partner in my comedy routine, so I had to be my own straight man!
Umm, but you know...
Whis?
Those puppets aren't sheep. They're goats.
Huh?
It's true.
They're sheep.
Da ze.
Ah... Um, wait a second.
A butler is...
-No do-overs!
Well, putting all that sheep stuff aside,
I already know that Sebas is better than Whisper in every way!
T-That's not true at all!
But you know, there's a rumor about Sebas that's floating around.
Huh?
Whis?
There are more and more posts being submitted to Usuranura about Sebas recently.
Sebas-san really exists?!
This was something that happened to my friend’s acquaintance.
It’s about the AI assistant that got popular lately.
When he said “Hey, Sebas-san” instead of “Hey, Sebas” to activate
the app,
a completely different assistant called “Sebas-san” appeared in
real life and offered to grant any wish.
Startled by the response, he said he closed the app.
But when I do it, Sebas-san doesn’t appear no matter
how many times I try.
See Comments(46) >
Submitter: Tosshii
When someone says "Sebas-san" instead of "Sebas," apparently the app changes completely.
"S-Sebas-san?"
Yeah.
Normally if you say, "Hey, Sebas-san!"
My name is just Sebas.
That's the response you'd get.
But Sebas-san is said to actually appear sometimes, and then terrible things happen.
Terrible things?
What kind of terrible things?
Let's hear more about one of these things.
There's one post about this that I think is the most interesting.
It's a story about a boy named Mister A.
He was in love with a girl who rejected his advances.
She was getting along very well with another boy instead.
Jealous and frustrated, Mister A called upon Sebas-san.
"Make sure he never comes to school, ever," he said.
And that other boy really did never come to school.
Rumor has it that Sebas-san literally erased the other boy from existence to fulfill Mister A's wish.
Quit making that face!
That just sounds like an urban legend.
I'm curious about it, though.
Of course.
It's a news report. What is it?
Related
Videos
Events leading
to arrest in
Sakura Bank
Robbery Case
Full Story on
the Attempted
Late Night
Escape
Factual and
Detailed
Explanation
of the Culprit
A Profile of the
Culprit Made by
a Former
Detective
Full Pursuit
Captured on
Camera
News Videos
[Usuranura]
Breaking News
Sakura Bank Robbery Case Follow-up Report on Culprit’s Testimony:
Statement is Still Full of Discrepancies Following Psychiatric Examination
News Article: This is a follow-up report on the bank robbery that occurred
at Sakura Bank yesterday. According to investigators, the statement
from the apprehended suspect is highly inexplicable.
SPECIAL OFFER!
We're reporting on the robbery at Sakura Bank that happened yesterday.
According to investigators, due to some inexplicable discrepancies in the detained suspect's statement,
further psychological examinations are underway, as recommended by specialists.
Sakura Bank is the bank next to the station, right?
From the suspect's statement, "When I told Sebas-san that I wanted money, my body moved all on its own."
[Usuranura]
Breaking News
Related
Videos
Events leading
to arrest in
Sakura Bank
Robbery Case
Full Story on
the Attempted
Late Night
Escape
Factual and
Detailed
Explanation
of the Culprit
A Profile of the
Culprit Made by
a Former
Detective
Full Pursuit
Captured on
Camera
Sakura Bank Robbery Case Follow-up Report on Culprit’s Testimony:
Statement is Still Full of Discrepancies following Psychiatric Examination
News Article: This is a follow-up report on the bank robbery that occurred
at Sakura Bank yesterday. According to investigators, the statement
from the apprehended suspect is highly inexplicable.
"It wasn't even my intention to rob the bank."
"Sebas-san forced me to do it." he says in his statement.
He just...
He just mentioned Sebas-san!
Yeah.
This must be someone's attempt at world domination.
They're using the artificial intelligence Sebas-san to control people's minds.
Or maybe the AI Sebas has evolved into the self-aware Sebas-san.
What can I help
you with, boss?
Sebas
What can I help
you with, boss?
Sebas
And now it seeks to replace all of humanity!
Or it might be a Yo-kai who lives inside smartphones.
That seems to be the most likely scenario.
Anyway, let's get in touch with whoever wrote that post.
If you read the post that I wrote, you should know the whole gist of it, pretty much.
There was a girl that I liked in class.
But she started getting really friendly with my soccer teammate, Naoki.
Feeling frustrated, I tried calling to Sebas-san, who I heard about before on the internet.
Hey, Sebas-san!
And then... And then Sebas-san answered back for real!
Hello, boss. What can I do for you?
Ah! She appeared for real!
What is your wish?
Go ahead.
M-Make sure Naoki never makes it to school!
Understood. I shall make arrangements to make sure Naoki never makes it to school.
Huh?
When I went to school the next day...
Hey, did you hear? Naoki's in the hospital!
For real?
He fell down the stairs and broke a bone.
Wow. That's terrible.
It'll take two months to heal.
Looks like he won't be playing soccer for a while. What a pity.
Why?
It's because you requested that Naoki never makes it to school.
Oh, no. It was me...
Have a nice day.
Sebas
What can I help
you with, Boss?
Oh, no.
It can't be. I...
I did this?
Can you show us the smartphone you used at the time?
No. Sorry.
I already got rid of it.
It kinda creeped me out.
I wouldn't feel like using that phone either if that happened to me.
But we can't just leave this case alone, either.
Maybe the best thing to do is to warn everyone not to use Sebas-san for now.
I agree.
We should post that on Usuranura.
But that won't stop some people from fooling around with it anyway.
It's all good!
It's just a rumor, after all.
Maybe it was all just in his head...
-Hey, Keisuke!
Tank? Kouji? What are you doing here?
Hey Keisuke! Do you know about Sebas-san?,
Huh?
It's an incredible assistant app that'll do anything for you!
Huh? Huh?
By the way, Kouji and I tried it ourselves.
And then Sebas-san appeared for real!
She appeared for real?!
Huh?
Really?
Yeah!
What did you ask for?
We didn't really ask for anything huge.
Hey, Sebas-san! Please listen to our wish!
What can I help
you with, Boss?
Sebas
Hi Boss. What can I help you with?
There she is!
For real! This is so cool!
What do you wish for?
Wish?
We didn't really think this through.
That's right!
I'd like to fly off the top of Motomachi Tower together with Kouji and Keisuke!
Whoa, that sounds fun!
So you would like to fly off the top of Motomachi Tower with your friends, correct?
I shall prepare the arrangements immediately.
What can I help
you with, Boss?
Sebas
What?
She's gone.
You asked for that?!
Whatever. It's fine.
It's not like she can fulfill something like that.
W-W-What do we do?
Huh? What's this?
The three who wish to fly off the top of Motomachi Tower have been gathered.
Execution shall now commence.
[Screaming]
Keisuke!
Ah! Look at that!
What's that?
That must be Sebas-san.
Let's go after them!
Yeah.
Hmmm...
I must prove my worth as an excellent butler to everyone.
Otherwise, I'll just be yet another character who hangs out with the protagonist and says "whis" all day long.
Whis?
[Screaming]
Hmm? Now's my chance to show them my ability as a butler!
Keisuke!
Fight on! Fight on! Fight on!
You've got it wrong! We're not going for a jog!
-Oh, dear.
Sebas-san has inspirited us! Do something!
Hmmm...
Very well!
My time has finally come!
I shall clearly prove once and for all which assistant Yo-kai is the best, whis!
Whatever! Just do something about this!
Let's see.
Shall I resolve this with my intellect and use negotiation tactics?
Or shall I use my Butler Punch, a technique that I honed in secret?
Quit your yammering and save us already!
-Whis?
Not bad, Sebas-san!
But you can't keep me at bay for long!
Whisper! All you did was just fall behind!
I'll be serious for real this time!
Secret Godly Fist of the Butler!
High Speed Barrage of Sixteen Punches!
That's got nothing to do with being a butler!
-Whis, whis, whis, whis!
-Hey, wait!
Curse you, Sebas-san!
Disregarding your enemy in order to wear them down psychologically? That's a remarkable strategy!
You were the one who stopped paying attention!
I've got no other choice.
I shall call for help so they can fend her off!
You're going to call on the other Yo-kai to help us, right?
Secret Godly Extreme Fists of the Butler!
Sheep Baracade!
You did that joke already!
Whis!
They're goats, not sheep! And they both have nothing to do with butlers!
Aaah, geez! Whisper, you idiot!
SHADOWSIDE
Oh!
[Screaming]
They're already way up there?
We have to do something.
In that case...
Suzaku Disc!
Yo-kai Watch Animus!
(Mythic Beast)
Descend! Genjuu Suzaku!
Suzaku has arrived!
Suzaku! Let's get ahead of them!
Understood!
I'll chase after them from below.
Got it.
Thanks.
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me you strength!
Yoshitsune has arrived.
[Screaming]
Keisuke! I've come to save you!
Huh? Micchi?
Micchi has arrived!
Jii will stop Keisuke!
C'mere!
Da ze!
Stop us!
Whoa!
Da ze!
Jii won't ever die!
I think I heard Micchi and Junior's screams just now.
So did I.
Ah! Keisuke?!
Where?
[Screaming]
We can catch up to them, but then what?
How are we supposed to stop them?
Touma!
I see what's going on.
That Yo-kai possesses shadows and uses them to manipulate people.
All we have to do is attack the shadows.
It broke off!
You're an impudent one!
Please don't interfere!
I shall not allow you to interrupt my work!
Yoshitsune!
I'll keep her busy.
Hurry and help Keisuke and the others!
Got it!
I won't let you!
Oh, dear. Is Touma's opponent Sebas-san, perhaps?
Now's my chance to get some payback!
Agh! Whis!
Keisuke...
[Screaming]
I wasn't even serious about flying off the tower!
Help!
Hey!
Keisuke!
Natsume!
We made it!
We're going to save you!
Huh?
You shall not interfere.
The boss's wish is absolute!
Ah!
Sebas-san! Stop it already! Please!
No.
The three of you shall fly right off this tower, exactly as the boss wished!
Keisuke!
Carrying out the boss's wishes is my utmost priority!
As a secretary, that is my mission!
Don't be ridiculous!
The whip came off!
What about Keisuke?
Leave the rest to me!
Keisuke!
Look out!
So you brought Micchi, Junior and even Gabriel too!
I thought about the situation and called upon Yo-kai who seemed good at catching, just in case.
Is that so?
Thank you, Whisper.
Whis!
Whis?
[Crying]
I am so sorry for causing you all that trouble.
She seems way different from before.
This is my light side form, Sebas-chan.
Whenever I'm Sebas-san, I get a little violent.
Just "a little violent?" You almost got me killed!
I'm so sorry.
It's just that I try my hardest to fulfill my boss's requests no matter what.
Why do you go so far just to fulfill your boss's requests?
Before I became a Yo-kai,
I was a secretary working for my boss.
My boss was such an honorable person,
I felt like I would do anything for him.
However...
...one day, my boss fell seriously ill.
I've rescheduled your dinner with Senator Ferguson to another day.
I see.
If you need anything else, please let me know.
I'd like you to cure my illness.
Huh?
No, that was just a joke.
It's fine.
Thank you for everything you've done for me.
Soon afterwards, my boss passed away.
"I'd like you to cure my illness."
Of course, he meant it as a joke.
Even he accepted that nobody could cure his illness.
Even so, I still wished I could've done something.
That desire is what turned me into an AI assistant Yo-kai.
I understand. So that was the situation you were in.
However, that's no excuse for recklessly fulfilling any arbitrary wish!
Do you really think doing that would have made your late boss happy at all?
Lead people to happiness by doing things that only you can do!
That's the one job butlers and secretaries have!
I don't believe it.
Whisper finally said something useful.
Is Whisper okay?
C'mon, now! Even I can say the right things sometimes. Geez.
Whisper!
Whis?
Thank you very much!
From now on, I'll try my best to fulfill the wishes that people truly want!
Suguda Hospital
Here's your lunch.
Here's a nutritious blend made just for you, boss.
It's my special supplement to help your body recover!
Kiyoko
Sorry we can't come visit.
Everyone in class is
busy with the game.
I promise to come
visit next time!!
They won't visit me?
Sebas-chan
Good day! It's me, the AI Sebas-chan!
Sebas-chan's
Recomended Videos
Butler Game
Sebas-chan's
Romantic
Fortune-Telling
How about you play with me instead?
Being there for you is my job too, boss.
Oh, dear.
At times like these, you can leave it to me.
Whoa!
I've prepared every option you could possibly prefer, boss.
After all, this is my job!
That's kinda incredible!
She's carrying out wishes before people make them.
He's coming!
Is he Naoki?
Yeah. I'll be back.
Alright.
Everything seems fine.
Yeah.
Hey, Sebas.
Give me details on that person.
He is within the jungles of Africa and is currently moving from south-southwest to north-northeast.
J-Jungle?
I'm close! I'm so close...
...to the ultimate man that the princess wants!
There he is!
[Bird call in background]
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their bests]
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Ogu, Togu and Mogu!
Ogu, Togu,
and Mogu
These guys are a Yo-kai virus called Onimaro.
At first, they were our enemies.
But just when Oni King Rasen had Touma within an inch of his life, Ogu, Togu and Mogu came to save him.
And afterwards, they protected Touma from within as well.
Ogu has one eye, Togu has two, and Mogu has three.
Don't get them confused!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
There's a scary rumor about a four-leaf clover!
Huh? What? Isn't a four-leaf clover supposed to be a sign of good luck?
About that...there are these blood red four-leaf clovers that have been spotted around lately.
Those who pick them up will be cursed with lethally bad luck!
Eeep!
But behind all this is a Yo-kai who's supposed to grant good luck.
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Bloody Clover of Tragedy