Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 8 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Merry Shopping
Oops! We've accidentally spilled some juice!
Do you find it troublesome to deal with waste paper and bulky cardboard?
In times like these, just call for it!
Almighty!
That's right! It's Almighty's turn to help!
It'll even take care of huge spills.
As you can see, it can take care of large pieces of trash.
And then vacuum up even the smallest pieces!
And it can even use its suction to filter out the air!
Thanks a lot, Almighty!
Thanks to internet connectivity, Almighty's cleaning AI is always improving!
Incredible!
Good job.
It's the best companion for making your house a comfortable place to be.
It's Almighty! The all-purpose cleaning machine!
It's being sold for 29,800 yen, tax included!
Have a merry day!
It's hot.
Hee hee hee hee hee hee hee hee hee hee...
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Strange happenings aren't always the work of Yo-kai alone.
Consider the electrical appliances that enable your modern lifestyle.
What frightening things will happen when these familiar machines suddenly bare their fangs at you?
Almighty's Uprising
Misaki! Want to go play today?
Sorry, Manami. Al's waiting for me at home.
Al?
That's right. Al is short for Almighty.
Misaki, did you buy an Almighty too?
Isn't that product hard to find because it's so popular?
You're lucky to find it.
My dad bought it in a web auction.
And he got it for only 3,000 yen!
3,000 yen?
That's too cheap.
You sure it's not broken?
Not at all! It's a little dirty, but it runs just fine.
I'm home!
Welcome home, Misaki. Cleaning is now complete.
Good job!
There you go! Al is all clean too!
Clean. Clean.
But there's nothing I can do about this burnt spot. What happened here?
I got it! Just wait here.
It's gotta be around here somewhere.
It...It's hot.
Al, I've got something for you. Here!
Ah! It's so cute!
It's perfect for you, Almighty!
Thank you, Misaki. Thank you.
There's someone in my class that bought an Almighty.
It'd be nice if we had one at the agency too.
What? We have one already?
Yeah, my grandma bought this for me.
She said it's because I never clean my room.
That's not something to be proud of, though.
Wow! It can even clean in those places?
Natsume!
I won't lose to it at cleaning!
Please take a look!
Heave ho!
Unsightly, Muscles.
Let's get serious then!
Almighty! Let's have a window cleaning match!
Understood.
Ready? Go!
Micchi wiper!
I'd like one in my house, too!
Yeah!
Wait a sec.
There's a post about Almighty on Usuramera.
W-Why's it on that weird site?
What does it say?
"If you consider its features and abilities, it should really be sold for 100,000 yen", they say.
"This is no ordinary appliance. It seems to use a design that resembles inexplicable ancient technology," it says.
Ancient technology?
What is that? Seems kind of dumb.
O-Of course...! Ha ha ha...
No... This isn't an improbable story.
What?
Almighty became popular because it's both cheap and high quality. But I don't think that's all.
There's definitely a ulterior motive!
U-Ulterior motive?
For example, it could be a monitoring device made by the government to spy on citizens.
Or maybe there's a special unit that's used to eliminate spies living among the people!
Something like that.
G-Getting taken out like that is super scary!
Complete.
Muscles lost!
Hey, Almighty. Tomorrow is Saturday.
We're having a field trip then. So you'll be housesitting.
Where is this field trip?
It's a place called The Next Generation Energy Research Institute.
Energy...
Next Generation Energy Research Institute.
10:00 AM
Here we are researching completely new, environmentally friendly forms of energy.
The technology used to make the well-known Almighty was also created here.
This is the Next Generation Energy Research Institute's main plant.
So cool!
This is super awesome!
Let's take a picture!
It's incredible that robots did it all!
It really is!
Let's head to the next point of interest.
This is the same energy as Almighty's.
If only Almighty was here to see this too.
Ah...
What...?
Where is everyone?
My phone isn't connecting at all.
I wonder where everyone went.
Seems like the advertising is going well.
Yes. Today the local elementary school students are here for a field trip.
Even so...
...we're not only showing how safe it is by having the children over for a field trip...
...but we're letting them advertise for us by letting them take photos and video.
This research requires a lot of money.
In reality, the safeness of this energy isn't confirmed yet.
But we won't be able to get funding for research if that gets out.
Let's use the the publicity the children are generating for us as best as we can.
Just like we did with Almighty.
Energy!
Huh?
A-Almighties?
Wasn't there a shortage of those?
A-Almighty?
Natsume!
Akinori? Touma?
What's going on?
It looks like the Almighties are going on a rampage!
Why are there so many?!
At this rate, there could be an accident.
Micchi has arrived!
Who asked for you to come!?
Leave this to me!
Micchi Magnum Strong Kick!
Ouch!
Oh no! Don't touch me there!
Geez. What are you even doing?
There's no other way.
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Jibanyan! Do something about these Almighties!
Ora ora ora ora!
Good!
Do your best!
B-But with these numbers...we'll be...
You're all junk!
Damn... There's no end to them.
Jibanyan!
That's not good!
Energy...
Huh?
Energy?
They all left...
Where are they headed?
Don't tell me...
The Next Generation Energy Research Institute is in that direction.
They're after that energy?
What?! But Keisuke is supposed to be there today!
What did you say?
Misaki, where did you go?
So that's the Energy Research Institute over there?
The Almighties...
Don't tell me they're in there!
Huh?
Just what in the world?
Hey, doesn't the color of that smoke seem dangerous?!
Keisuke...!
Misaki... Energy...
They've come out!
What is this?
There are still students here!
Get the kids as far away from the plant as possible!
Don't tell me Keisuke is...
Alright, I'm going to do something!
Possession! Genma Benkei! Lend me your strength!
Benkei has arrived!
Alright!
Go while you can!
I'll take it from here!
Thank you!
You're welcome!
No one asked you!
Alright, you Almighties. Bring it on anytime now!
Ack!
Whis!
Da ze!
We were unable to find Keisuke among the evacuees.
Keisuke...
The ceiling!
This way's blocked too!
What do we do? We haven't even found Misaki yet!
Chief! The gas has ignited!
Agh. We have no choice. Evacuate!
And gather the research materials!
Whis! The fire has gotten quite bad!
What do we do?
We fight our way through!
Summoning!
Shadow!
(Azure Dragon)
Come on out my friend, Seiryuu!
Thank you, Seiryuu.
Call on me again anytime.
It's here! Hurry!
Excuse me, but do you work for this institute?
Y-Yes.
Um... my younger brother...
Where are the other field trip students?
They must be along the field trip course, obviously.
Can you tell us where that is?
Hell if we know! Go check the information boards around here!
Excuse me, but would you kindly answer our question?
Wh-Wh-Who the hell are you?
Hey.
Huh?
Answer... the question.
The field trip course is that way!
I see. Thank you for your cooperation.
Da ze!
Okay, let's hurry!
Alright!
It's no good. It won't connect!
What's going to happen to us?
Keisuke!
N-Natsume?!
Keisuke, are you okay?!
We're fine, but we're trapped by rubble.
Hey, Akinori... Keisuke says that he's blocked in by rubble.
Huh? Cool!
Hey! Now's not the time for jokes!
Keisuke!
Aren't Dogman's jabs the best?
Natsume! Akinori!
Is nobody hurt?
Yeah!
Let's get to safety!
Hurry and run!
Wait! What about Misaki?
That's right!
A girl in our class got separated from us.
We need to go find her!
I get it. Then leave the search to us.
Lead everyone else to safety.
But...!
Take care.
You're a member of the Yo-kai Detective Agency now.
Uh-huh.
Ah. There she is. That must be Misaki.
Let Natsume know right away!
Roger that!
Don't be scared.
Okay...
What is it?
W-What is that?
It's poison gas!
Help me!
Ahh! Almighty!
You came for me!
Energy... hot... This area... is dangerous...
Huh? I see.
Almighty... You realize it as well!
What do you mean?
About the energy that's being researched here...
The attack has stopped?
What in the world?
Touma!
Natsume, did you call for me?
I didn't ask for you!
But... whatever.
It's fine! The Almighties aren't the bad guys.
Well, that's good!
Anyway, it's over.
Alright. Let's go home then.
Yep!
What's that?
Almighty!
Misaki!
No!
Must save... Misaki...
Must save...
Must save Misaki... Must save Misaki...
-Almighty...
Almight!
Please stop!
At this rate...
Mi...sa...ki...
...must save...
...That is our... mission...
Almighty...
Watch out!
Misaki!
What's this...?
I must save everyone.
That is... my mission...
Was that... Almighty's memories?
Misaki...?!
Wh-Who is this guy?
I am your 24-hour complete support for anything from lifesaving to plumbing problems.
I am here to keep your world safe!
Robonyan... Double Oh!
Well... I understand the "Robo" part.
(cat-like)
But there's nothing "nyan" about him...
That's right! Show us anything that's befitting of a cat!
Jii wants to see too!
I'm interested, too.
I know, right, Natsume?
I will protect Misaki!
I'll be back!
He ran away...
That was a Yo-kai, right?
That seems to be true.
Due to a certain situation, the Next Generation Energy Research Institute has been closed, and Chief Hikidashi has been arrested.
The institute was found responsible for the Almighties' rampage.
The manufacturer has issued a recall for all units.
What's a recall?
It means the maker is going to fix the flaws in the things they sold.
A recall for everything?
In other words...
Total Recall!
What was so funny about that?
Beats me.
It's the head splitting movie!
It's head splitting! Head split!
The Princess... Where is she?
What kind of person is the Princess?
The Princess exists to control demons.
She has the power to take over Youmakai.
(The Yo-kai World)
Oh dear...
The Princess lives among human society.
And she lives as normal human right now.
But... we will definitely find her.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Akinori's
Yo-kai Watch Shadowside
Trivia
Today, we're talking about Touma's Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
Touma uses the Yo-kai Watch Ogre. These are the high rank Yo-kai called the Genma:
Goemon, Omatsu, Yoshitsune, and Benkei. They can all be called upon to possess him.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
And when he uses the Fudou Raimei Sword...
(Sword Warrior Demon, Acala)
...he can also call upon Kenbumashin Fudou Myouou for possession.
It's super strong!
Geez! I'm just so jealous!
Hey, have you all heard?
About the sushi restaurant Maguro Zanmai and their medium and high grade tunas?
Sounds delicious!
I know, right?
Ah, what I meant to say was...
There's a flying, man-eating tuna that suddenly appears from the sky...
...right in front of people walking down the street!
What? I definitely don't want to get eaten by a tuna!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
It Is Called a Man-Eating Tuna