Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 22 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
What should I do?
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Ah! It's beautiful!
Thank you!
H-Hey! Are you alright?!
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Touma and the Oni King's Fragment
Touma is in trouble!
Hurry up, fatty!
W-Wait! Whoa!
Hey! Stop blocking me!
Suguda
Hospital
Touma...
I wonder what happened.
What happened?
They say he collapsed on the street suddenly.
They still don't know the cause.
I need to...
...go back...
Touma!
Do you want to go home?
Touma.
We have to let him rest.
What is this?
What is it, Touma?
Where does it hurt?
Touma...Touma...!
His parents can't see it?
This is no ordinary sickness.
That unusual Yo-kai energy...
This is definitely the work of a Yo-kai.
S-Seriously?
So this must also mean that ordinary doctors can't heal him, right?
Sorry, Natsume.
I have work to attend to at the laboratory.
I'll bring you a change of clothes for Touma.
Don't worry about it.
We'll be here to watch over him.
Thank you.
We won't be away for long.
Okay.
Let's have a look at the Youma Radar.
Did you figure something out?
Ah ha! Nothing at all!
That's no good!
But there's one thing I'm sure of.
This isn't a typical case of being inspirited by a Yo-kai.
For sure.
We can't even see the Yo-kai.
So in other words...
There might be something terrible happening within Touma's body!
Something terrible?
Perhaps a bug Yo-kai made a hidden nest within his body.
And it is just waiting to mature and then burst out right out...
B-B-B-Bug?!
-Augh! Or maybe...
It's a cluster of man-eating Yo-kai that's draining the aura from Touma's body...
N-N-No way! That's super impossible!
Hey! Our friend is sick right now. This is no time to be joking around.
Sorry. I did it by force of habit.
What was that?
Don't tell me a Yo-kai appeared for real!
Where is Touma Tsukinami right now?
Grandma?
Akinori's grandma?
Tell me this instant!
You can't cure him without me!
Please! You're causing a disturbance!
Hello, madam! Allow me to help you!
So you've finally come.
Hurry and take me to his room!
Sure! Of course!
But madam, you aren't a doctor, you know.
Sure, I'm not a doctor, but you can't cure him without me!
Oh, wow! That's incredible.
Yes. It is incredible.
By the way, madam, did you come by yourself?
They just left.
Your grandma really does know how to cure Touma, right?
That's right. I should go find her.
Akinori's grandma?!
Why through the window? Wait, what floor is this?!
Don't worry about it!
I knew it. Something really bad is happening.
This is a really bad one, right?
Yes. This is an especially bad one.
Is that true?
I was able to sense the Yo-kai energy all the way from my house.
But we can't tell what's wrong with just the Youma Radar.
That's right.
As great as the things I make are...
...you can't use that to search inside bodies.
So today, I've brought over a brand new invention.
I call it the Youma X-ray.
Youma X-ray?
I will write the results of the Youma X-ray in his Youma medical charts with a Youma pen.
Alright.
Does she just like saying "Youma" all the time?
Now, let us begin.
T-This is...
What is that?
Something is residing within his body!
Akinori!
We must expel it immediately!
Alright!
It looks alright.
Bring me the purification seals.
Okay.
[chanting]
Oh spirits of disease residing within Touma Tsukinami...
I force you out into this world!
Did it go well?
I don't know of what evil will come forth.
Do be careful of what comes next.
Right!
Now then.
[chanting]
What's that?
Akinori!
Coochie coochie coo...
It was all just for that?!
Begone, evil Yo-kai!
This body belongs to Touma Tsukinami!
-Just looking at it makes my nose itch!
Haa... Haa... choo!
So it's finally shown itself!
Now... show us your true form!
Whoa!
Call us, and we shall appear! Tah-dah! YAY!
What?
You're...
So he was being inspirited by Onimaro?
Ah... hold on. They're not bad guys.
What?
We met when we were fighting Rasen.
They saved Touma's life.
Right?
We saved him.
YAY!
Ah... so that was you.
I heard all about you from everyone.
I'm grateful that you saved Touma.
Granny! YAY!
Gratitude! Yay!
Looks like they're getting along.
Mogu... you were inside Touma, right?
I was together with Ogu and Togu.
But something bad showed up inside Touma all of a sudden.
Then I got separated from Ogu and Togu.
Yay.
If we defeat this bad thing, will it cure Touma?
That's right! Yay!
YAY.
The only way to cure Touma is to enter his body and defeat the bad thing.
Yay.
I kinda have a really bad feeling about this.
Grandma, I'm going in.
Be careful in there.
If you let your guard down, there's no telling what will happen.
Keisuke. If you're scared, you can stay behind.
I-I'm going too!
No. Let's have Keisuke stay behind and assist me.
Huh?
We have no idea what's going on inside.
We'll stay here and support the others.
We'll leave it to you, Keisuke.
Got it. You careful in there, too.
You can count on us!
Now then...
Are you ready?
Yeah.
If you touch that swirl, you'll be able to enter. Yay.
What is this?
Yay.
T-They disappeared?!
Akinori... Natsume...
Take care of Touma.
SHADOWSIDE
YAY.
Is this the inside of Touma's body?
That's right! Yay!
Huh?
It's soft.
B-But...we don't have any landmarks. How do we know where to go?
Oh, it's Ogu and Togu's scent!
Huh?
Over here! Yay!
Huh...? Wait!
This is...
It's the same evil spirit that came out of Touma!
Ogu and Togu are upstream from here. Yay!
Alright. Now's the time.
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Magurodon!
W-What did you want from him?
Isn't it obvious? We're riding upstream.
Whaaat?!
-Thanks a lot!
Hey, hey, hey! Is this safe?!
Madam, what is this?
Ah, perhaps this is the root of the cause.
Akinori... Natsume...
Please hurry!
Where are we going?
Ogu! Togu!
Ah!
Mogu!
Were you two pushing it back? Yay.
Yeah, but...
We're at our limits...
Do your best! Hold on...
Yay!
Ogu! Togu!
Something is coming.
What is that?
His name is Kabila. Yay.
Kabila?
He is a Yo-kai who was formed from the fragments of our former boss, Oni King Rasen.
A fragment of Rasen still remained inside Touma.
So he was causing Touma to get sick!
Get out.
I shall begin creating a new world.
You shall not interfere!
Let's do this!
Eat this!
Alright!
This time... I'm using this one!
(Kyryn)
Kirin!
Let's go!
(Mythical Beast Kyryn)
Descend! Genjuu Kirin!
Kirin has arrived!
Alright! Go get 'em, Kirin!
Who's he?
Ah! He transformed!
Yay!
Take this!
Right on, Kirin!
Ah! Oh, no! Ugh!
Kirin!
Damn it.
It's my turn!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
Tch! What a disgusting lowlife. Well, whatever.
Let's go!
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
Ora ora ora ora!
You're no big deal for a big guy.
Go ahead and try messing with me if you dare!
Hey! What kind of sign language is that?!
Jibanyan!
I-It seems way bigger than it was before!
I'm going to assist them!
Haiyah!
Umm... Is everything alright?
I'm hearing some strange voices in there.
Oh, no!
S-Sorry about that! That was actually my voice just now!
[gibberish noises]
What do we do, Natsume?
For now, we should...
...run away!
What is this wind?!
Achoo!
What was that just now?
The evil thing inside Touma is finally out!
Where's this?
Ah? We're outside!
Yay.
Kabila...
It followed us out!
Yay.
I shall create a new world. You shall not interfere!
This is bad.
Get lost!
Jibanyan!
Kirin!
That was a useless struggle. But this is the end.
Die!
Wait!
Leave my friends alone!
Touma! Keisuke!
Touma Tsukinami!
Possession!
Kenbumajin Suzaku!
Suzaku!
Lend me your strength!
Hyakkaryouran Suzaku Soutenzan!
(Blooming Flowers, Suzaku Azure Heavenly Slayer)
Suzaku has arrived!
I see! When we got Kabila out, Touma was able to wake back up!
He sliced them with his sword!
Incredible!
You impudent fake...
This time, it's my turn to strike!
What's he trying to do?
No way!
Heavenly Cross Attack!
We've won!
Touma!
You look better now!
Thanks, everyone.
Hey, Touma.
Let's be together from now on.
That's right! Together.
YAY!
Thank you... Ogu... Togu... Mogu...
So you can leave the hospital tomorrow, Touma?
Yeah. There's nothing wrong with my body anymore.
They're just going to do some checkups.
I see!
YAY!
Jii's super incredible!
Oh, by the way, Touma, when you collapsed...
...you kept mumbling about needing to get back.
I said something like that?
Was there a TV show you couldn't miss?
Nah. It's nothing like that.
Quit talking, fatty!
That's right!
Shut up!
YAY!
Quit interrupting.
Grrr...
Actually, today is my mom's birthday.
To celebrate, I wanted to give her flowers.
But I couldn't get her anything at all.
That's nonsense.
Mom?
Seeing you healthy is the best present of all.
Jii's got an idea!
YAY!
Natsume, you really saved us!
Umm, Mom?
Hmm?
Happy Birthday.
Ah! They look beautiful!
Thank you, Touma.
Just how long is Junior going to be a bouquet of flowers?
At least he's trying his best for today.
Himeno...
...I mean...
The legendary man who the princess desires.
Are you really going to look for him?
Of course.
That's what the princess wants, after all.
Hurry it up.
If you dare dilly-dally...
...Then maybe I'll have you eaten.
What?!
I'm just joking. It's a joke.
I've said it before.
What I want is the legendary...
Why are you stripping?
So that it's easier for you to eat me, princess.
I must... keep it together...
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
(Swordsmen Spirit)
Today's topic is Kenbumajin Suzaku!
Kenbumajin
Suzaku
Touma can summon Kenbumajin Suzaku to possess him,
(Acala)
just like how he can summon Fudou Myouou.
Suzaku's just as fast in the dual sword-welding Kenbumajin form
(Mythical Beast form)
as in Genjuu form. If you blink during a battle, you'll miss it.
Geez!
Suzaku's cool in his Kenbumajin form, too!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
About beautiful actors all taking time off?
What's that?
Cool handsome actors are all taking time off one after another!
Why is that?
We should get in touch with the actors who went on break.
Huh? Don't these handsome actors look kinda average now?
Something happened to them in a hospital deep in the mountains!
Eeep!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Dark Clinical Records of Doctor C
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs