Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 30 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
What?! What's going on?
Looks like a pretty delicious man.
Wait! Please! I'll do anything!
Just relax, beautiful man.
Feed me that delicious soul.
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
This story is about Ayame Himeno, a beautiful but mysterious woman.
She shows a pure and innocent side to Natsume and friends...
...And she shows a dark and mysterious side to Haruya and his followers.
Which of these personas is the real Ayame?
Will tragedy strike for Ayame before this mystery is solved?
Ayame's Fall
The legendary man that the princess seeks is here.
Well, this is what hundreds of years will do to someone.
But we can reawaken the princess's powers using this.
Is that really true?
Hmm?
The purpose of gathering the Youseiken was never to reawaken her powers,
but to gather the strength needed to attack more human men.
Therefore, if she really does need those dead remains...
Then Ayame Himeno must actually be...
Douketsu.
Hmm?
I'm certainly not unaware of your concerns.
However, we must have faith in the princess.
I shall finally meet that person.
I've been waiting for this legendary man for hundreds of years.
I can't wait to meet him!
Huh?
Ah, a message?
It's from Akinori.
Akinori
I'm so excited about
tomorrow, I can't
sleep
♪
I'm so excited about tomorrow, I can't sleep!
It can't be!
I can't believe I finally go out with Ayame today!
Akinori!
Whoa!
A-Ayame!
Ayame...
You're an angel who has swooped down from the heavens.
No, a goddess.
Sorry for making you wait.
Um...no worries! I actually only got here just now.
That's a lie. He's been here since morning.
Junior! Shhh!
This is a first date, after all.
He's doing the shtick where the guy arrives too early because he's nervous.
Let's follow them, shall we?
Stop!
We finally got the two of them together.
Let's watch over them without interfering.
What?
What do you mean?
They invited us to come along, but I turned them down.
I thought I should let those two be alone together.
Of course. We already know that Akinori likes Ayame, right?
I get it now. So that's what it was.
Huh? Touma...
You never realized it?
Sakura Motomachi
Photography
Contest
Meeting Hall
is this way
Sakura Motomachi
Photography
Contest
Meeting Hall
is this way
That's incredible, Akinori!
You won first place in photography contest!
Well, it's not that big of a deal.
So, are you not gonna tell me what picture you took?
Hmm...
It might surprise you a bit.
First Place
Akinori Arihoshi
This is the picture that you took?
First Place
Akinori Arihoshi
Sakura Motomachi
Photography Contest
Meeting Hall
W-What do you think?
I took it while we were coming back from solving a case,
So cute!
Ha, ha! That tickles!
I kinda thought you looked really nice.
I took a picture without thinking.
Ahh! Are you mad that I photographed you without permission?
Well, I never realized you took my picture in the first place.
But you took a really lovely picture of me.
Thank you, Akinori.
Thank you, Akinori. Thank you, Akinori. Thank you, Akinori.
-Ahhh. I can die happy now.
Hmmm. This looks just delightful.
Natsume is happy. Why?
Natsume is mature enough to be interested in romance now.
What is it, Touma?
Nothing. It's just my imagination.
Now they're looking through the telescopes.
Ah. I can't resist looking in those all the time!
Ah!
I can see my house from here!
For real?
Why don't you look, Akinori?
Don't mind if I do.
There, see?
Y-Yeah!
Aaah!
I'm with Ayame!
I'm with Himeaya!
Ayame Himeno and Akinori Arihoshi are side-by-side!
Side-by-side!
NIce! Nice!
They even look like a real couple!
Hey, fatty! It's shrink or swim!
Junior, you said that wrong.
Motomachi Tower
Ah, sorry. I gotta go to the toilet.
Sure.
Princess.
Ayame,
I love you.
Please be my girlfriend!
Alright. This is it.
Go, Akinori!
Be brave and confess your love!
Huh? Where is Ayame going?
Should we follow her?
Hmmm...
But if Akinori doesn't come back...
Ah, there he is!
Ayame,
I love you!
Please be my girlfriend!
Oh, dear!
Huh?
I'm so sorry.
But I'm already married!
Who's she?
We've been waiting for you, princess.
What about him?
Yes. Here he is.
Finally.
I've finally met you!
Now, let us become one.
What's happening?
P-Princess?
Ahh. Delicious.
How repulsive.
She's nothing but a man-eating crone!
You hag! You're not the princess!
Douketsu, are you still on about that?
But...
It's just as you've said, Douketsu.
Princess?
[Laughter]
Are you still calling me your princess?
You're a terrible judge of character, boy.
Haruya Sakami, you've served me very well.
But you've outlived your usefulness.
O-Oh, no.
[Laughter]
Ah.
I am now one with my beloved's soul.
Where did Ayame go?
What's this?
A very strong Yo-kai is nearby.
I can't allow Ayame to be in danger!
Did something happen?
Let's go.
A-Ayame?
[Screaming]
A-Ayame!
Akinori!
What is that?
[Laughter]
I've finally regained my true powers.
SHADOWSIDE
[Laughter]
I'm overflowing with power!
There's no mistaking it. This is proof that I've reunited with him!
Ayame.
What is that? A spider Yo-kai?
We must save Ayame!
Stand back!
I shall handle this Yo-kai.
Mr. Shimanouchi?
Huh?
Don't tell me, Mr. Shimanouchi is Douketsu?
How dare you ridicule my master!
Huh? Is that Sakami over there there?
Do you know him, too?
Nah, he's just a classmate.
Why are those two here?
Fatty! Ayame's in danger!
Ayame!
Akinori, stay back.
Run away.
Ayame!
Come on, Ayame!
Oh, no.
Douketsu, what is the meaning of this?
What are you and Sakami doing here?
[Laughter]
Don't judge them too harshly.
That puppy's been playing fetch with me, Jorougumo, the whole time.
Shut up.
I will never forgive you for this.
Is that really Sakami?
How dare you deceive me.
For this crime, you deserve death!
I've got you now.
What's this?
Damn it!
[Laughter]
And now you can't even do a thing!
Do you think these feeble strings can stop me?!
I'll take your powers as well.
What?
You two are just so useful to me, aren't you?
[Screaming]
She's draining away their Yo-kai energies!
Farewell, Haruya Sakami.
You were a good lackey until the very end.
Now, then. I guess I'll take your souls next.
Eeep! She's coming!
Now, then...
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
[Hiss]
Jibanyan, fight that Yo-kai!
Natsume!
I am your knight!
Micchi!
Whatever, Micchi!
Jibanyan, please.
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
As if a cat can harm me!
Jibanyan!
Looks like it's my turn!
Special Technique, Micchi Beam!
Hmm? Did you do something?
Allow me to explain.
Against higher ranked opponents, the Micchi Beam has no effect.
I stand no hope of winning against boss class enemies.
Cheers!
-Why did you even bother?!
Alright, it's my turn.
Possession!
(Acala)
Kenbumajin, Fudou Myouou!
Fudou!
Lend me your strength!
Lightning! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Sword!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Fudou Myouou has arrived.
Oh, dear.
What a fine, mature gentleman!
Hmmm?
[Laughter]
What do you think? Tough, aren't I?
You won't escape me!
Huh?
Ugh!
Touma!
Ugh.
Hey, are you okay?
Y-Yeah.
Fudou Myouou just lost.
[Laughter]
[Screaming]
Tch!
We're gonna lose at this rate.
C'mere!
[Screaming]
We're leaving!
Ayame and Akinori are still in there!
Do not fear!
Huh?
Micchi Jump!
Micchi!
Great landing!
You can do it if you try, Muscles!
How rare for him to actually be useful, whis.
Oh, c'mon!
There's no point in loitering. Let's go!
Uh-huh.
Why?
How could this happen?
[Laughter]
Huh? What is this?
This looks kinda bad.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Huh?
Hey!
[Gasp]
[Laughter]
Ordinary humans won't sate my appetite.
Huh?
Motomachi Tower is...
Granny, are you here?
Oh, Natsume.
Hmm? Is that girl...
[Sigh]
So that's what happened.
Jorougumo might have bitten her soul when she separated from her body.
Oh, no. Does this mean that Ayame's...
Huh?
What's this?
There's a spider web-shaped bruise on her neck.
That is Jorougumo's curse.
Curse?
If we leave her like this, it'll spread to her whole body.
When it does, Jorougumo will have eaten her entire soul. And she'll lose her life.
Damn it.
If only I didn't leave her side.
This isn't your fault, Akinori.
That's right.
Just who is Jorougumo?
Jorougumo is a brutal man-eating Yo-kai who committed atrocities in this area about 500 years ago.
Jorougumo loves young beautiful men more than anything else.
She consumes not just their flesh and blood, but their souls as well.
But then one day,
Jorougumo found a completely perfect and beautiful man.
I want you!
Give all of yourself to me!
But he was also a legendary mystic who was just as powerful as her.
[Screaming]
The handsome mystic defeated her and sealed her away in these lands.
But why did she inspirit Ayame?
That mystic's last name was also Himeno.
What?
So that means that Ayame is...
Without a doubt, she is that mystic's descendant.
As time passed, Jorougumo gradually broke the seal.
Because Ayame is related to the legendary mystic,
Jorougumo resonated with Ayame's latent powers, which she used to resurrect herself.
Grandma, can you tell us how we can save Ayame?
You must defeat Jorougumo and bring back Ayame's soul.
So that's how.
Alright! Let's work together to bring down Jorougumo!
But even Fudou Myouou's blade can't cut through her webs.
Oh, dear. Even Fudou Myouou's powers are no match.
Do we stand no chance of winning?
Hey. Can you hear me?
Huh?
Who are you?
This voice...
Are you Douketsu?
I can't speak for long.
Retrieve the Genbu Houtenfu.
(Axe of Law)
Huh? But why?
There is only one Youseiken that can cut Jorougumo's webs.
You must find the Genbu Houtenfu.
Heed my words.
(Treasure Sword Palace)
The Genbu Houtenfu is in the Yo-kai World's Houkenden.
Obtain it at all costs.
Why are you telling us this?
Aren't you trying to get the Youseiken for yourselves, too?
I only wish to protect my master.
You know what to do.
(Treasure Sword Palace)
Let's go to Houkenden.
Uh-huh.
Ayame.
We'll save you, no matter what.
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their best
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Boureibanchou.
Boureibanchou
Boureibanchou is the first Yo-kai that Keisuke befriended.
He protects the weak and punishes bullies.
He is a manly Yo-kai whose fighting power is on par with Jibanyan's.
His signature phrase is "Men are courageous!"
Geez!
I want to say a cool catchphrase like that too!
Boureibanchou
Next Episode
Preview
Ayame is inspirited by the man-eating Yo-kai Jorougumo.
To save her life, we must fight Jorougumo!
In order to obtain Genbu Houtenfu, an axe that's said to even split oceans,
we must head to Houkenden.
The journey will be filled with countless terrifying traps.
What?
Will we be able to form a contract with Kenbumajin Genbu?
I'll go!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
A Fierce Duel! Suzaku vs. Genbu