Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 27 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
[Moaning]
W-What is that?
[Screaming]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
Humans have a history, and so do the Yo-kai.
Komasan actually had a younger brother long ago.
Can their bond bring the two of them together once more?
And whatever happened to the younger brother?
The Wandering Komajiro
Huh?
An album?
Akinori
starts
training
He looks happy
getting his
first backpack
Rolling over
for the
first time
Getting
better
at walking
Showing
interest in a
Kabuto helmet
Looking up
various
things
Huh? Grandma took all these photos?
Oops.
Whoa!
W-Who's this crazy cute girl?
So cute!
I've never seen this cute shrine maiden before!
But why would grandma have this picture?
Maybe she wants to marry me!
Akinori.
Let's get along!
It can happen!
I want it to happen! I'll make it happen!
If it ever happens...
[Laughter]
Wait up, you!
You can't catch me!
Whoa!
Oh, you! I won't lose!
Oh. Sorry. Are you okay?
I'm not fine at all!
Akinori, I've stolen your heart!
Ah, hah, hah, hah! What a rosy life! Hah, hah, hah, hah!
Is it raining?
Ah! It's a rainbow!
Ah! How auspicious!
[Screaming]
Ah, geez!
Can you not pee there?
Sorry about that.
Lucky for you. At least it wasn’t poop.
That wasn’t lucky for me at all!
Good thing it wasn’t poop, though.
It's no good at all!
Ah.
It's Akinori.
[Akinori giggling]
Thanks for having us over!
Oh, umm, everyone's here!
Hey, Komasan peed on me just now!
That's just how it is. This has always been Komasan's turf since long ago.
How long ago?
Ever since before I became a Yo-kai.
Komasan used to be a dog raised by this shrine.
I see.
A Komainu statue fell on him, crushing him to death, and then he became a Yo-kai.
Uh-huh.
It was... really heavy.
Really... heavy?
That's quite a nostalgic story you're telling.
Granny?
Thanks for having us!
When Komasan was a dog, we used to call him Nobushige.
He was loved by everyone in the neighborhood.
Hmm. Speaking of which, you were fairly popular yourself when you were younger, Mitsue.
Mitsue?
That's my real name.
Hmmm? A young Granny?
No one called me "Granny" when I was young, you know!
Well. Who cares about that now?
What do you mean, "who cares?"
Take a look at this!
Huh?
Who's this girl?
Oooh!
That's me.
Huh?
That's me when I was younger.
WHAT?!
No way.
He thinned out even without summoning Suzaku!
What... What did I imagine?
Wait for me!
Akinori, I've stolen your heart!
[Gagging]
What's this?
Wow! She's cute!
Huh?
Heh. Is that so?
I can't believe it.
Even her bones sagged.
What did you just say?
Nothing at all.
Why did that cute girl turn into this beast of a crone?
It's called getting older!
I've trained as a shrine maiden for as long as I can remember.
Adults all around me were charmed by my valiant and diligent personality.
She just praised herself!
Before long, I grew into a beautiful young woman overflowing with youth and energy.
She praised herself!
But even though I was popular for being beautiful,
I loved tinkering with machines from time to time.
It was my hobby's contrast with my beauty that added to my appeal.
This solidified my popularity.
Back then, we were always together.
Isn't that right, Komasan?
Uh-huh.
And the little one was always with you too.
Little one?
How nostalgic.
Is this a grave?
The big one is Komasan's.
It's Nobushige's grave.
I became a Yo-kai then.
By the way,
the detective agency is pretty close to this forest, isn't it?
It sure is.
What about the smaller grave next to it?
It's the little one's grave.
Yes. It's Komajiro's grave.
Komajiro?
He's my younger brother.
Komasan, you have a younger brother?
Uh-huh.
Here's a story from long ago.
Komajiro would always frolic around the area.
He was an energetic little one.
But when I was crushed underneath the Komainu statue,
Komajiro was unceremoniously killed as well.
When I became a Yo-kai, I came back here.
But Komajiro wasn't there with me.
I thought that he just didn't become a Yo-kai.
After I turned into a Yo-kai, I became known as Komasan.
Since I'm Komasan, maybe my younger brother should be Komajiro.
And that was the name I gave my younger brother.
Komajiro's sense of justice was strong.
We would patrol the area together every day.
But now, it's just me.
One other thing we did was...
Peeing to mark your territory?
Komajiro, Everyone's here to visit you.
Oh!
Huh?
What happened here?
Why is there a hole here?
Whoa.
It's true!
Oh, dear.
Does this mean that Komajiro emerged from his grave, perhaps?
Huh?
Why is that?
It's possible that Komajiro became a Yo-kai recently.
Leave it to me.
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
Yoshitsune has arrived.
How do we find him?
I can follow the traces that Yo-kai leave behind.
Huh?
Is this where Komajiro went?
The traces stop here.
But he should be near.
Thank you.
Another pond?
He's always been near water, it seems.
Perhaps,
Having just become a Yo-kai, he's been feeling thirsty.
But no matter how much he drinks, the thirst couldn't be sated.
Meaning that he's transformed into a monster who lusts after human blood!
[Roaring]
[Whimpering]
And we've been lead to this pond just to become his first victims!
Are you here, Komajiro? Come on out!
Stay away!
Is he not here?
[Gasping]
What is that?
Something's coming!
Komajiro?
No! It's too small for a dog!
It's something else!
It's coming closer!
Mo-mo-mo-mo-mo
Mongee-ribbit!
A-A frog?
What? He's so cute!
Komajiro!
Komasan!
Huh?
K-Komajiro is...a frog?!
Mongee-ribbit?
SHADOWSIDE
Look, is this really Komajiro?
Mongee-ribbit?
He's not a dog?
I never said that he was a dog.
Komajiro would always frolic around the area.
He was an energetic little one.
Of course!
Looks like we completely misunderstood.
Yeah.
But why did you become a Yo-kai now?
You were buried in your grave, right?
After I became a Yo-kai, I hibernated-ribbit!
You hibernated after dying?
I'm a frog, after all-ribbit!
That's the reason?
I see. So you were just sleeping in.
You're okay with that answer?
You slept for a really long time, though.
Ribbit.
I'm a frog, after all-ribbit!
So cute!
So being a frog is your excuse for everything?
I'm a frog, after all-ribbit!
There it is again!
Can I ask a question?
How can a dog and a frog be brothers?
That's right.
That question, huh?
We were always together.
Even though I was a dog and he was a frog.
We weren't even able to speak to each other.
But even so, I thought of the two us as brothers.
Komasan! I thought of you as my big brother, too-ribbit!
And I was so happy when you gave me my name-ribbit!
Ribbit.
Mongee-ribbit!
I love being on top you your head, Komasan-ribbit!
It's been a while since the last time you sat on my head.
I understand.
Huh?
Even though they couldn't talk to each other, both of them thought of each other as brothers.
Both of them died at the same time.
When they reunited as Yo-kai, they become brothers for real.
I see.
Isn't that nice.
Yeah-ribbit!
Yeah-ribbit...
That Komainu statue is loose. it falls from the pedestal quite often.
Is that so?
Decades ago, that Komainu statue fell on us during a blizzard.
Ribbit.
Uh, during a blizzard decades ago, you say?
Yeah.
We were returning after the end of our usual patrol,
There was a huge noise all of a sudden.
And then, the statue fell.
That's when both of us got squished flat like pancakes!
Uhh...
It was.... really heavy. Ribbit.
-It was.... really heavy.
It can't be...
What's wrong, Granny?
Nevertheless, the way it fell was incredible.
It made a huge noise when it landed, too! Ribbit.
Yeah. I wonder what made it fall.
That statue didn't fall by itself! Ribbit.
Somebody must have pushed it! Ribbit.
Komasan! Let's find the culprit! Ribbit.
Whoa. Is the Komajiro Detective Agency forming?
Your sense of justice has always been strong.
Let's find the culprit and beat 'em up!
Alright, Touma. Let's try that again.
Uh-huh.
Yoshitsune has arrived again.
Ribbit! You're helping us, ribbit?
Yeah.
Huh? Granny?
Gulp!
Where are you going?
I was just heading inside. That's all!
Don't get too worked up finding the culprit.
That's right! We want to find the culprit!
Trying to find the culprit, huh?
That won't be necessary.
Why is that?
The reason is...
Gulp!
The culprit is already here!
What?
Granny?
For real?
My eyes do not deceive me.
Mitsue Arihoshi. Also known as Granny.
You are the culprit!
No way!
Don't tell me it's Granny.
Indeed.
It's as he said. I am the culprit.
How could she?
M-M-M-M-M-Mongee-ribbit!
I'll attack the wicked, ribbit!
Is he changing into his shadow side?
Eep!
Mongee-ribbit!
Whoa.
He seems really...
Spindly.
Don't call me spindly, ribbit!
He's serious.
Look at the aura coming out of Granny!
It's another Granny!
What kind of a plan is that?!
G-G-G-Granny!
Granny looks like the final boss in a video game.
Komasan! Help me out, ribbit!
I can't ignore my brother's request.
[Growl]
Falling Hound Rock!
[Groaning]
Let's go, ribbit!
Falling Frog Rock!
Ribbit!
Ribbit! Ribbit! Ribbit!
This ends now, ribbit!
If that's what you're doing...
I'm so sorry!
Huh?
Ribbit.
You could've just apologized from the beginning!
But they came at me with such fearsomeness!
So, Granny, how are you the culprit?
When I was younger, I didn't want to yield to the snowstorm while training that day.
Ha!
Haa!
Huh?
[Thud]
Oopsie.
[Sneeze]
Let's fix that tomorrow.
Geez, it's cold!
I wouldn't have imagined that the statue I knocked over that time was the same one that crushed you two.
The next day, the Komainu statue was back where it was.
The adults told me that Nobushige and the frog died from the cold weather.
They didn't want to hurt the feelings of a beautiful shrine maiden by telling the truth.
So they decided to keep it a secret.
Yes. In other words,
it's a tragedy that was caused by my own beauty.
Is that really remorse or just a humblebrag?
Komasan, Komajiro.
I am really sorry!
Hmm. I don't really understand what happened. But that sounds normal.
Yo-kai can be selfish sometimes as well.
We forgive you, ribbit!
It's an Ark!
Looks like it's case closed. Right, Natsume?
Uhh, yeah.
Why did you only appear this late?
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Is this our new comrade?
I am Mitsumatanodzuchi!
But you can call me Micchi!
Mongee-ribbit! It's a snake, ribbit!
My eye!
How rude! Why did you...
Why? Stop that!
-Oh, yeah. Frogs and snakes are natual enemies.
I'm hit! I'm hit! I'm hit!
-Ah. So that's why?
Curse you! Why must you hit me in the eye like that?
Oof.
Justice always wins, ribbit!
Komasan! Let's go on patrol, ribbit!
It's been too long since we were together like this.
Away we go, ribbit!
Aah.
It's just like the way they used to be.
Mongee-ribbit!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their bests]
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Komasan.
Long ago, he was a dog named Nobushige owned by the Arihoshi clan.
Komasan
But he died when Granny knocked over a statue by accident.
As a Yo-kai, he's called Komasan.
Even as a Yo-kai, he's been protecting the Arihoshi clan.
But even so, how'd that cute girl turned into Grandma?
Argh! It's so complicated!
Komasan
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
There's a rumor about the AI assistant on smartphones.
You mean the voice on the phone that answers back when you ask what the weather is tomorrow?
That's right! It's an assistant called Sebas.
But sometimes a really creepy assistant comes out instead, they say!
[Keisuke whimpering]
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
The Cursed AI Assistant
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs