Previously on on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside.
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
(Yo-kai Holy Swords)
Once we obtain the five Youseiken,
we'll be able to awaken the princess's power.
Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 14 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Your Fudou Raimei Ken was stolen.
Shutendouji is an Oni Tribe Yo-kai, boasting the highest class of power even within the Yo-kai World.
He seems to be disguising his presence.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
The Fudou Raimei Ken is a legendary Youseiken.
The only thing that can oppose a Youseiken is another Youseiken.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
You must obtain a new Youseiken.
(Animasu Tenjou Kyou)
Animus Tenjou Mirror!
Going with the naming pattern we've used up 'til now, let's call you Yo-kai Watch Animus!
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
The Animus isn't used with the Youseiken.
(Mythical Beast)
It's used with these Genjuu discs.
Let us take it back together.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
The stolen Fudou Raimei Ken!
What is it?
It seems they've obtained it.
They've obtained it?
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
Certainly not a new Youseiken, right...?
No, it's not a Youseiken.
It's a power I've never felt before.
We mustn't let our guard down.
I can find out more about its true form.
Please leave this to me.
What? You're not someone I can rely on.
You couldn't find the princess.
You couldn't dispose of Touma and his Ogre.
Did you want to embarrass yourself further?
You're just incompetent.
Don't get in our way. Just guard the house.
But I can...
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou, Wicked and Heavenly
(Mountain of Prayers)
Huh? We were just at Inoriyama, though.
It appears that Suzaku has warping abilities.
A shopping mall?
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Is the Fudou Raimei Ken here?
Without doubt.
That I know.
(Swordsman Spirit)
After all, I was a Kenbumajin just like him.
(Mythical Beast)
By the way, why did you become a Genjuu?
That's enough about me.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
There. Now we must go find the Fudou Raimei Ken.
Alright, let's go.
I don't really see anything out of the ordinary here.
For sure.
Natsume, I've got to go to the bathroom.
Uh-huh.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
But if the Fudou Raimei Ken is here...
Shutendouji must be hiding here as well.
(Colossal Inferno)
Ashura Gouenmaru's wielder must be as well.
We can't let our guard down.
Huh?
W-What was that just now?
What's wrong, big guy?
Uh... Nothing at all!
W-What's happening?!
Natsume! Natsume! Natsume!
Attention, a lost child has been reported.
Keisuke Amano, from Sakura-motomachi.
Keisuke Amano, your older sister, Natsume, is waiting for you at the information counter.
Natsume! Natsume!
This place is dangerous! Natsume!
Wait... what?
What's going on?
-Natsume!
Keisuke!
Thank goodness!
W-Who are you?!
Touma Tsukinami...
If only you had obediently sunken into the ocean, this wouldn't have happened!
Today, I'll show Shutendouji my true powers!
Huh?
You're Shutendouji's ally?
That's right! My name is Fukurou!
What?
I can also use these blow-darts like this!
I am not incompetent!
Run away!
What is that?
It's a roast chicken zombie!
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry! Won't eat roast chicken ever again!
What are these guys?
I won't eat fish again, either!
It's no good!
In that case...
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Huh?
This sure is a nasty place.
Come on out my friend, Komasan!
Pee. ♪
Why is he peeing?
You summoned me just when I was about to pee. Geez.
And why'd you summon their Lightsides?
Ah, I wasn't thinking.
You got a problem with Lightside? Don't belittle us!
Jibanyan!
That hurt! You little...
Alright!
Awesome!
Are you not gonna summon Micchi?
Micchi?
Ah. I forgot all about him.
If he heard that, he'd be crying by now.
Well... Let's try calling him then.
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend, Micchi!!
Ah! I can't summon him!
Ah, come to think of it...
He got knocked out while fighting Suzaku!
Ah! That's right, I remember now.
Now he'd be crying at that, too.
But we're okay without Micchi anyway.
Heh. Serves you right.
Heh. It's not over yet.
After all, I still have this!
Ah!
That's...
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Fudou Raimei Ken!
Why do you have it?
That idiot Fukurou is disobeying orders.
You realize what will happen next, right?
Well now. Let's see.
Hey! Give that back!
(Acala)
With this, Fudou Myouou's power is mine!
No!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
To use the Fudou Raimei Ken in the Human World,
you need the Yo-kai Watch Ogre to adjust its energy wavelength!
You can't use it!
Even I can perform energy adjustment myself!
And this is how I'm doing it.
(Acala)
I'll summon Fudou Myouou with my own blood.
Stop it! You're bleeding!
(Swordsman Spirit Acala)
Possession! Kenbumajin Fudou Myouou!
Lend me your strength!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Lightning! Thunder! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Ken!
(Wicked Acala)
Fudou Myouou Ja has arrived!
Oh no. He performed the possession!
(Wicked Acala)
Fudou Myouou Ja?
Just what is that?!
Jibanyan! Komasan!
Oh! It's no good!
Alright, now!
Suzaku Disc!
Disc?
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
It appears they've obtained it in lieu of a Youseiken.
Yo-kai Watch Animasu!
(Mythical Beast)
Descend! Genjuu Suzaku!
Suzaku has arrived!
Alright! Let's go, Suzaku!
Akinori!
What is with that look?
What?
"What?" nothing!
You've gotten thinner, Akinori!
W-What? How?!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Would you kindly return the Fudou Raimei Ken?
SHADOWSIDE
Suzaku...
Let's go!
What?
Suzaku!
It's harder for Suzaku to fight indoors!
In that case...!
Let's head down.
Yes.
He busted through the roof!
Oh, we did it!
What's that?
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou has refused to accept Fukurou.
Forcing a possession like that will result in a rejection reaction.
I've got it now!
We did it!
Good work!
I must return. For your health's sake, that is.
You've lost even more weight!
(Mythical Beasts)
Summoning Genjuu burns up calories?!
He turned back a little.
You were useless 'til the very end.
He's...
I just...
...wanted to be of use to Shutendouji...
Do you use that mask to avert your eyes from reality?
Shutendouji has told me that he expected nothing from you.
You are just worthless trash.
How do you even dare to stand next to him?
But he did tell me something quite unexpected.
That you're a fool who will surely bring yourself to ruin through reckless rampage.
I-I must...
I must... find her...
I must find the princess by my own hands.
I will find her...
Then stand up.
Stand up.
Even if you must use the last of your strength.
Let yourself be consumed by the inferno.
And as you die, a dark malice shall be resurrected.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
The Fudou Raimei Ken!
That's...
What is that?
Fukurou, damn you!
T-This power...!
This is bad!
We must stop it!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
I need to find the Fudou Raimei Ken!
Touma!
At this rate, the building is going to collapse!
What's happening?
Micchi's ark...
What? He's not dead yet?
If he heard that, he'd be in tears.
Natsume, try summoning him!
Uh-huh.
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend, Micchi!!
"Come on out, Micchi!" And at those words, I've come from far away.
To tell you the truth, I am no longer Micchi!
During my fight with Suzaku, I narrowly avoided death!
My body has gained even more power after returning from the ICU!
Your Micchi! Everyone's Micchi! Micchi, Micchi, Aaah, Micchi!
Hurry up and come out!
Roger that!
Materialization!
Hyper Micchi!
Wait. Allow me to explain.
Hyper Micchi can materialize the Hyper Cloak and Hyper Suit in only 0.2 seconds!
Hey, what's this countdown for?
A good question. Hyper Micchi's form is on a time limit.
This time limit is decreasing as we speak.
Whatever! Just stop that thing!
Leave it to me!
Ah, only 10 seconds left.
Five! Four! Three! Two! One! Zero!
Agh! Oh no!
Oh, dear.
He spent too much time talking.
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou! Please lend me your strength once more!
(Heaven Acala)
Fudou Myouou Ten has arrived!
Touma!
Awesome!
He's gotten stronger!
Lightning Thunder Electric Attack!
Lightning
Thunder
Electric
Attack
Iron Hammer Thunder Slash!
It all returned to normal.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Good grief. So they've taken back the Fudou Raimei Ken just like that.
I'll let them hold onto it for now.
Besides that, what was it that Fukurou transformed into just now?
Who knows?
What are you doing, Akinori?
Don't you remember what Suzaku said before?
(Mythical Beast)
Akinori. Always be sure to take best care of the Genjuu Disc.
As Suzaku says!
Take beast care... of the beast disc?
What's so funny about that?
Oh, by the way, Touma.
Please take this.
What is that?
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
It's for storing your Youseiken. It's the Youseiken Holder.
Do I stick it in like this?
Yes.
And here, Natsume.
What's this?
It's the Ark Holder, for holding your arks.
Huh!
What about me?
But you've already got it.
Your Beast Care Beast Disc Handkerchief.
What?!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Yo-kai Watch Movie News!
The fifth Yo-kai Watch Movie is set to be released!
It's called...
Yo-kai Watch the Movie: Forever Friends!
Nyaa! That must mean "Let's be friends forever," right?
Huh? "Who are you," you ask?
I'm Nekomata, and I'll be taking on an important role in the movie!
Please look forward to it!
Preorders for the movie tickets begin July 14th!
And my super rare Yo-kai ark is included, too.
Hey, have you all heard?
There's a super cute girl who transferred into my school!
Her name is Ayame Himeno. Everyone calls her Himeaya.
She became the most popular girl at school instantly!
There's no way a cute girl that cute exists...
She exists!
Oh no! A cute girl that cute is gonna turn into a target of the cute girl serial kidnapping case!
You said "cute girl" too many times!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
One Hundred Thousand Years a Single Cute Girl
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs