Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 7 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Anime-Land, Adachi TV(TVA)
Hey...
Huh?
W-What?
Do you think I'm... pretty...?
What?
Do you think I'm...
P-p-p-p-p-p...... pretty?
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
This time is a story about a scary woman wearing a long coat.
"Am I pretty?" she says, as she lifts her hair.
What fate will you meet, when you see her face, I wonder?
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna
It hasn't been raining much so you must be thirsty.
I had the buy these. They're so cute.
Plants are so soothing.
Hey!
There's troub-
Sorry Akinori!
Beckoning
Happiness
Rejoice, my people!
I've obtained information on a new case!
What kind of incident is it this time?
Just wait a second...
Found it! It's here.
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna?
Uh-huh. There's even eyewitness accounts!
Taking the usual way home from work one night...
A lady in a long coat called out to me.
Then she said...
"Am I pretty?"
As she said that, she lifted her hair. And then somehow...
And then her face split right in half vertically!
You scared me!
Don't pop out like that! You're scaring people!
But someone's face splitting in half is so frightening!
Even so, this post seems really interesting!
It's most likely a Yo-kai, but it could be a ghost as well.
Maybe it's an alien lifeform?
I don't think it's any of that.
Why?
Well... Faces splitting in half seem common in made-up stories.
What's a splitting face?
Hey there, Junior.
A splitting face... probably looks something like this...
Mongee!
It's stretching! It's stretching! So fun!
Jii wants pull too!
H-H-Hold it!
Hmm.... So if you don't say she's pretty after she asks you, "Am I pretty?" you'll get eatten?
Ha ha ha! Who could possibly ignore my beautiful body?
Don't you think so too, Natsume?
(Splitting Face Woman)
And it also says that since Kaosake Onna is weak against pomade,
...if you say "pomade" three times, she'll run away.
That's wierd.
Pomade! What's Pomade!? Is it tasty?
Umm... No I wouldn't say that it's tasty...
Well, pomade is...
Whis?
It's something that you use with your hair.
Geez! Please don't do unnecessary things to my swirl!
Sniff sniff... Whisper stinks! Smells like old man!
Whis?
It also says that if you give her hard candies, it'll give you a chance to run away.
What's hard candy?
Well... hard candy is...
Whew...
Don't give me that "whew".
Why were you facing backwards?
Umm.... It's just.... huh...?
What are you holding?
Umm... this?
It's just hard candy.
Just in time for Jii...
That's hard candy!
What?
Sweet!
What have you done!?
(Splitting Face Woman)
I got this candy just in case Kaosake Onna came after me!
Keisuke, did you know about Kaosake Onna?
Don't you always deny things and say, "There's no such thing as monsters!"?
Ah... Well...
(Splitting Face Woman)
Perhaps you were fearful of meeting Kaosake Onna on your way here, as revealed by the timid posture in which you've come?
Ah. So that was why.
He looked really spooked, didn't he?
What a splendidly defensive posture!
Keisuke's spooked!
Well... I can't really help it!
(Splitting Face Woman)
There's people I know who say they've seen Kaosake Onna before!
For real?
(Splitting Face Woman)
So... Who was it that saw Kaosake Onna?
You know the flower shop that mom often goes to?
It's Azusa, the person who works there.
Ah, it's her!
It seems like someone's been playing a cruel prank on her and mom.
As member of the Yo-kai Detective Agency, you knew it might be a Yo-kai related case, right?
No. Well, I was just saying that if we didn't get to the bottom of these pranks, people will be worried...
Fine...
Over there?
Is that Azusa over there?
Yep
Alright, let's interview with her right away!
Excuse me!
I'm so sorry! Are you okay?
I really am so sorry!
It's fine! I'm alright.
Huh? Aren't you two the Amano siblings?
I'm Keisuke.
I'm his older sister, Natsume.
Ah! That brooch...
We've got a matching pair
Is that so.
What do you want? It doesn't look like you've come to buy flowers.
(Splitting Face Woman)
We'd like to hear about your encounter with Kaosake Onna.
I'm working right now.
It won't take long. We'd like to hear more.
Please.
What a bother...
Please go home when we're done, okay?
Alright.
I was taking my usual route to work...
It was right in front of that old building.
Hey...
What?
Wh... What...?
Am I... pretty...?
Pomade! Pomade! Pomade! Pomade! Pomade!
You scaredy cat...
So what happened afterwards?
Who knows?
She didn't chase after me as I ran away.
What did her face look like?
What it looked like?
It seemed kinda red...
Red?
And she was like, "Gwaah!"
So she was like, "Gwaah"?
Just like that.
So she's red and kinda "Gwaah"?
Uh-huh. I see.
Those were some helpful clues!
I don't understand it at all though...
Uh-huh.
But I feel like she reminded me of something...
What is it?
I don't know.
Well. It seems like it was some sort of bad prank anyway.
This conversation is finished.
If you're not buying anything, then go home.
I'm in a good mood only because the flowers have bloomed well.
If I'm not careful, I'll lose sales.
Geez. These carnivorous plants are so creepy. There's no way they'll sell.
I should put them in the corner instead and feed them some minnows.
Let's go back.
That's right. Let's not disturb her work.
That's right.
There's no mistaking it.
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna's true form is that of a Yo-kai.
Now is the time for the Yo-kai Detective Team to act.
Azusa didn't seem too afraid of her it looks like.
No no! It'd be scary for other people!
We should do something about it!
"Other people"? Aren't you the one who's scared?
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna...
I wonder what kind of Yo-kai she is.
When she splits her face, maybe another one appear?
Maybe she rips apart her other body parts to reveal more claws?
And if you're bitten, you might turn into the same kind of monster.
That's certainly quite scary.
The Youma radar's going off.
This place!
Let's go.
Azusa!
Did you need something else?
(Splitting Face Woman)
This is the place where Kaosake Onna appeared, right?
Huh? That's right.
She's going to appear here again! Please get away!
How would you know something like that?
She's here!
A long coat and long hair...
She's finally appeared.
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna!
Come.
Yes.
What is going on with this sakura bloom...?
The princess will come shortly.
Ms. Azusa, please run to safety.
No way I'm leaving kids here to fend for themselves!
We're fine. Please leave this to us!
How could you be fine at a time like this?
Wait for me, okay?
Am I... pretty?
Eeep!
What's that?
She's...
She's a plant Yo-kai!
I'll do it!
Let's go!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend! Jibanyan!
I'm counting on you, Jibanyan!
Go for it!
While you were preoccupied...
We're joining the fight too!
Nobody asked you guys to come!
Natsume!
I feel terrible just having you stand there!
What's with this punk?
Whatcha trying to do?
Huh!?
You're no ordinary foxtail, are you?
We should do something!
Special Move! Michi and Whisper's twin double kick!
They got eaten!
Wait, doesn't the "twin double" part sound kind of off?
You're fighting me next!
You're pretty spry for a weed!
It's fast!
Jibanyan!
Hey! Seriously!?
No way...
Even Jibanyan!?
Doesn't it look bigger than before?
It's dangerous!
What did it say?
Run away!
What was it? What was it? It wasn't potato or tomato...!
It's dangerous!
I forgot it!
No way!
A dead end!?
Azusa...
Whis?
It's everyone!
Ah, very sorry about the trouble I caused.
Well, I wouldn't call that trouble...
That was extremely troublesome!
Goodness gracious!
I was almost digested!
A part of me is a little dissolved.
Sorry about that. I went on a rampage by mistake.
But that broach...
This?
It's the same one Azusa has. When I saw it, I remembered why I did this.
(Splitting Face Woman)
Why did you become Kaosake Onna and scare everyone?
What did you mean by "It's dangerous?" You said it while chasing us.
I tried to protect Azusa...
In what way?
Let's go somewhere else.
Alright!
I'm a carnivorous plant for sale at the flower shop Azusa works at.
Carnivorous plant?
It's a plant that gets nutrients from eating insects.
In other words, you're a Pakkun Flower (Piranha Flower) right?
Let's call you Pakkun then.
Pa... Pakkun?
So Pakkun loves bugs!
Huh...? Well... I wouldn't say love... I just get nutrients from them.
It's like nutritional supplements that humans take.
Do you like lollipops?
No. I don't particularly like them.
Well then... Pomade pomade pomade...
What is pomade?
Everything in that Usuramera article was false?
Pakkun, what did you mean by wanting to protect Azusa?
Well...
*sigh* What a bother. If we can't sell you, you're going in the bin.
She says such mean things!
Does she hate us?
Then why is she working in a flower shop?
If she hates it, she should quit!
Azusa is hated by all the plants in the flower shop...
How long are you going to stay unsold? You leftover.
"Leftover" That's the nickname that she gave me.
That's how Azusa is.
Would it be nice if we had a room like this?
Isn't it a chore to water them though?
Well... It's really bothersome isn't it?
I guess so?
That's why I recommend this: an automatic watering machine!
If you have this, you won't need to worry about watering every day!
Wow! That's a thing!
And even if you forget to water, your plants will never dry out. Isn't that right?
Uh... Sure...
Azusa might say mean things...
But she always makes sure that customers take proper care of us.
She once yelled at a customer at their house for letting their plant dry out.
Incredible.
She seems to really love plants.
But why did you need to scare Azusa?
To be honest, I saw Azusa's future.
Future?
That old building.
She walks in front of that building every day on her way to the flower shop.
In a future not long from now...
I wanted to protect Azusa. No matter what.
When I focused hard on that thought...
(Splitting Face Woman)
I became Kaosake Onna, a form that's neither Lightside nor Shadowside.
Can you really see the future?
That's incredible!
It's like how catfish can predict earthquakes.
It's an ESP power that some plants and animals seem to have.
It surely is one of life's mysteries.
You sure do love Azusa, right?
Yep!
Hey you!
(Splitting Face Woman)
Kaosake Onna!
Azusa?
Where are you? Show yourself!
She came back with a weapon!
You call a watering can a weapon?
That's rather bold...
Hiding is just cowardice!
Pakkun!?
Show yourself and figh-
Watch out!
Azusa!
Pakkun!
Are you okay?
Don't tell me...
This is... from my store...?
There's no mistaking it...
It's the leftover...
Pakkun...
Pakkun sacrificed it's own life to save Azusa...
Umm...
It's nice that you people were unharmed...
Goodbye...
Azusa...
Hey Touma, if we used Omatsu...!
That's right!
Alright!
Possession!
Genma Omatsu! Lend me your strength!
I am the healer of all living beings...
I will lend you the power of Omatsu.
What's this?
We found one that looks the same. Is this okay?
Sure.
Please excuse us.
Hey wait!
Oh well...
Welcome back, Leftover.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Akinori's
Yo-kai Watch Shadowside
Trivia
Today is going to be about lightside and shadowside!
Yo-kai have two faces: A lightside and a shadowside.
Lightside mostly represents a relaxed calm side.
On the other hand, shadowside yo-kai reveal their true nature in their formidable combat role!
The contrast between lightside and shadowside is way too intense!
Hey, have you all heard?
It's this rumor about this cleaning robot that everyone's been using.
It's the one that moves and cleans on its own, right?
That's right.
It's just the right place for the popular Almighty,
...a place no one sees or notices.
It seems to be trying to do something...
Aaah! All the Almighty robots are rampaging in the streets!
What are they trying to do?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Almighty's Rebellion