Previously, on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside...
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
(Yo-kai holy swords)
Once we obtain the five Youseiken,
We'll be able to awaken the princess's power.
I've got a bad feeling about this...
Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 13 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou, lend me your power.
Why do you desire my power?
I'm offering a trade.
If you lend me your power,
(Swordsmen Spirits)
I'll offer you the chance to fight the other Kenbumajin.
How about it? Still want to fight against me?
Very well.
I accept your offer.
(Colossal Inferno)
Together with Douketsu's Ashira Gouenmaru,
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
now we have our second Yoseiken, Fudou Raimei Ken.
Who are you?
Where is this?
The Yo-kai Watch is...
Touma!
Natsume! Akinori!
Are you okay?
Why are the two of you here?
We were also headed for Sendo Rei's offices.
And that's when the Youma Radar reacted in a way I've never seen before.
Huh? That's...
Your Yo-kai Watch is...
I get it!
So it was showing us where the Yo-kai Watch was.
But why?
I'm sure I was at Sendo Rei's office just now...
Seems like you don't remember at all.
W-Who are you?!
Huh? You're that person from before!
I am Serpent King Kaira.
Wouldn't it be better if we called you the Great King Kaira?
Uura, was it?
At any rate, Lord Kaira, Enma has entrusted to you the Yo-kai World's throne.
You're still young.
But you're not much different from Lord Enma.
But what is the Great King Kaira here for?
What happened?
I've...
Something was stolen from you.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Your Fudou Raimei Ken is missing.
What?!
No way!
It's gone!
For real?!
Did Sendo Rei steal it?
That person was just a pawn.
The one who was using her is called Shutendouji.
Shutendouji?
Shutendouji is an Oni Tribe Yo-kai, boasting the highest class of power within the Yo-kai World.
It appears that he has disguised his presence and is now hiding the Human World somewhere.
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
(The Mountain of Prayers)
The Strangeness of Inori no Yama
Shutendouji of the Oni Tribe?
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Why does he want the Fudou Raimei Ken?
The strong gather under strong people.
With this new power, Shutendouji threatens not just the Yo-kai World,
but the Human World as well.
What?
It was my fault...
Touma...
Now is not the time to mope, Touma Tsukinami.
You must remain confident in yourself.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
You're the original wielder of the Fudou Raimei Ken, after all.
But how?
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Since the Fudou Raimei Ken is gone,
(Acala)
that also means Fudou Myouou can't help us either.
There is one other way.
What is it?
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
The Fudou Raimei Ken is a legendary Youseiken.
The only thing that can oppose a Youseiken is another Youseiken.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
You must obtain a new Youseiken.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
There are others besides the Fudou Raimei Ken?
(Yo-kai Holy Swords)
There are five Youseiken.
What?
Five?
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
The first is the Fudou Raimei Ken.
(Colossal Inferno)
You already fought against the second one, the Ashura Gouenmaru.
Because of their great power, the remaining three have been sealed away in unknown places.
(Colossal Inferno)
Asura Gouenmaru?
Ah-ha!
The guy who called me a piglet? His sword?
That's right.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
The whereabouts of another Youseiken has been discovered.
It has a sharpness like a phoenix soaring in the sky.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
It's a Youseiken that can cut through all.
Its name is...
(Azure Heavenly Slayer)
Suzaku Soutenzan.
Suzaku Soutenzan?
(Azure Heavenly Slayer)
For you to obtain the Suzaku Soutenzan,
you must go to the Yo-kai world and find the Kenbumajin, Suzaku...
(Swordsman Spirit)
...and form a contract with them.
Suzaku is in the Yo-kai World's Kurane Valley, at the Sacred Birds Waterfall.
To get there from the Human World,
you must enter a gate within the deepest part of the Mountain of Prayers.
The Mountain of Prayers is one of the most dangerous spots in the world.
Stop it with those stories!
(Colossal Inferno)
Together with Asura Gouenmaru,
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
we've obtained Fudou Raimei Ken.
There are three left now.
I will search for the whereabouts of the next sword.
In that case, allow me to...
You'll keep looking for the princess.
Yes.
It'll be too much for you either way.
No... I'll do it for sure...
Huh?
W-What's that?
What happened?
It's a fork?
Which one is the correct way?
Agh! Something's coming!
An.... old lady?
U-Um...
Which way do we go to get into the mountain?
Thank you.
This person's kinda scary...
Hey, that's rude!
T-This is...
It's the same place we were before!
Huh? What does that mean?
Even though she was pointing this way,
now she's pointing to the path over there!
Huh?
The old lady is pointing to herself?
Look at the old lady's fingertips.
Doing it like this might mean she's pointing at herself.
No way...
It's true!
She's pointing right at herself!
What does that mean?
You know...
...This is what I mean!
S-Stairs?
Maybe it means that this is the right way.
Alright, let's go!
Huh? For real?
I'll go too.
Wait! Let's stop...
C'mon. You too. Let's go.
Alright, I get it. Stop pushing.
They got through the first gate.
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
Where's this?
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
What does that sign say?
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
A bus?
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
So this is a bus stop?
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
Three
Headed
Mountain
Pass
It looks like a normal bus from the outside.
Compared to the outside, there's a lot of Yo-kai energy here.
Tsuge Ophthalmology
Natsume...
This button...
Stop
The stop button?
That thing bites, right?
What?
What's going on?
They're all closed shut!
Are they trying to trap us in?!
Oh no! Oh no!
We're gonna fall off the cliff!
Seriously?!
SHADOWSIDE
Huh?
We fell off the cliff, right?
What's going on?
Woah! Again?!
What is this...?
I see! It's doing the exact same thing as before.
Huh? Akinori?
Tsuge Ophthalmology
Hey! Driver!
Get it together, and drive properly!
I've got no eyes! I can't see!
Ouch, it hurts!
Um... actually, it doesn't hurt.
Are you okay, Akinori?
That's right, the driver is a straw man.
What?
He's got no eyes, so he can't see!
Tsuge Ophthalmology
Why is there an eye?
I get it!
How about this?
Woah! I can see fine now!
I did it!
Now they've passed through the second gate.
Welcome to the Kurane Valley in the Yo-kai World.
What's that?
What is it now?
Kurane
Valley
That's the Sacred Birds' Waterfall.
Suzaku must be there.
Alright, let's go!
Suzaku!
-Suzaku!
Now then, let's play with them for a while.
Suza...
Hey!
Suzaku, where are you?
There's no way we'll find them like that!
Huh? Akinori? Woah!
What was the point of you even coming here, Keisuke?
Answer me!
Hold it, what's gotten into you all of a sudden?
You too, Natsume.
Huh?
(Colossal Inferno)
Weren't you able to beat Ashura Gouenmaru's wielder
and save Touma all by yourself?
Is there any point for you to have a Yo-kai Watch?
Stop it, Akinori!
Shut up!
And by the way, Touma!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
It's all your fault the Fudou Raimei Ken got stolen!
Isn't that so?!
Yeah.
That's exactly right.
If only you never went to that fortuneteller in the first place!
These are the seeds you've sown! It's all your fault!
Yeah... That's right...
Akinori, get a grip!
Natsume!
It was a mistake. All of it.
For you to have a Yo-kai Watch...
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
...for you to own the Fudou Raimei Ken...
...for you to not be lonely anymore...
...for you to have met Natsume and the rest of us!
All of it... was a mistake!
You're wrong!
Touma!
It wasn't... a mistake!
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune! Lend me your strength!
Touma!
Yoshitsune... has arrived.
I understand...
...the true nature of what has inspirited Akinori.
You're Suzaku.
What?
Suzaku?
As can be expected of a Genma.
Huh? What was I...?
Whoa! What's that?
That is Suzaku.
For real?
(Swordsman Spirit)
It doesn't look like a Kenbumajin at all!
Yes. For some reason, I don't take the form of a Kenbumajin.
(Mythical Beast)
I am a Genjuu.
Genjuu?
(Mythical Beasts)
Genjuu are Yo-kai who are equal in power to Genma.
(Swordsman Spirits)
And Genjuu can be more ferocious than Kenbumajin sometimes.
You who seek my power...
...show me what strength you have!
It's coming!
Even though Suzaku's big, it's also fast!
Is Touma going to be ok?
We need to help him.
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Jibanyan, back Touma up!
Leave it to me!
Micchi has arrived!
Huh?
Whisper has entered the stage!
Awaiting your orders!
I didn't even ask for you!
Oh no!
What?
Touma! Jibanyan!
Very well!
I'll be the one facing you now!
Woah, you can take it!
How unexpectedly tough!
That's it, Micchi!
What?!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
How could it can fly even with the weight of Micchi's huge body?!
Micchi!
He's a Yo-kai.
He won't die.
Let's leave him.
That's cold!
What's wrong? Is that all?
Not yet!
I can still fight!
That's the spirit!
Very well.
Come at me with all you've got.
Possession! Genma Goemon!
Lend me your strength!
12 o'clock. Goemon.
Goemon has arrived!
(Heavenly Ascension Wild Dance Cut)
Tenshouranbuzan!
We've won!
Well done.
I am now certain of your courage and power.
I will now grant you my power.
Touma!
You did it, Touma!
I will now grant you my power. Please step forward.
Here it is, Touma.
Go ahead.
Now don't be too hasty.
Huh?
The power that I shall lend does not belong to you.
The noble lend their powers only to the noble.
The one who I will entrust my power to...
...is you.
What?!
Me?
Akinori's a noble?
Does this bird know what the word "noble" even means?
I sensed it while I inspirited you before.
The one I shall entrust my powers to is you.
Akinori, I will bestow unto you something you can use to summon me.
Something special?
Woah! Don't tell me! Don't tell me!
W-What's this?!
(Animasu Tenjou Kyou)
Come forth! Animus Tenjou Mirror!
So this is... Animus Tenjou Mirror.
(Animasu Tenjou Kyou)
Awesome! So this is Animus Tenjou Mirror, huh?
Going with the naming pattern we've used up 'til now, let's call you Yo-kai Watch Animasu!
(Mythical Beasts)
Animasu can be used summon Genjuu like myself.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
I see! So with this, I can summon and use Youseiken!
Umm... where is your Youseiken?
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
As for my Youseiken, there isn't one.
Huh?
There isn't one?
(Yo-kai Holy Swords)
The Animasu isn't used with Youseiken.
(Mythical Beast)
It's used with these Genjuu discs.
Genjuu discs?
Isn't that great, Akinori?
(Mythical Beasts)
(Swordsmen Spirits)
Are Mythical Beasts different from Kenbumajin?
Yes. That's right.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
(Swordsmen Spirit)
I was a Youseiken-wielding Kenbumajin once before.
(Mythical Beast)
For some reason, I've the body of a Genjuu now.
Even so, I still serve you.
Let us take it back together.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
The stolen Fudou Raimei Ken!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Trivia
Akinori's
SHADOWSIDE
Today, we'll be talking about this! The Yo-kai World!
Yo-kai World
The Yo-kai World is the world where the Yo-kai live.
Right now, it's ruled by Serpent King Kaira.
And the world where we live is called the Human World.
You can enter the Yo-kai World from the Mountain of Prayers.
But there's said to be other gates as well!
But if you ever get lost in here, there's no guarantee you'll leave unharmed!
Let's be careful, everyone!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
We know where the Fudou Raimei Ken is!
It's in the shopping mall!
That's a completely normal place!
Wait! That's a completely scary place!
And the one waiting for us there is Shutendouji's underling, Fukurou!
(Acala)
And Fukurou's forcing Fudou Myouou to possess him!
Something bad's gonna happen!
And also,
(Mythical Beast)
after summoning Genjuu Suzaku,
something happens to Akinori?!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou, Wicked and Heavenly.