Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 9 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Hey, Mom... I'm hungry... Let's have some sushi!
Ah! I wanna eat sushi too!
♬Sushi, sushi♬
Guru
guru
Sushi
I see. It's getting a little late, so let's have some and go right home.
Alright!
Sushi sushi!
I wanna eat tuna and grilled salmon!
I'll have the rolled omelette and onion tuna roll!
In that case, Mom's going to have the tuna rice bowl, then...
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
(fatty tuna, medium tuna, lean tuna or minced tuna)
Whether it's Ootoro, Chuutoro, Akami or Surimi...
People love eating tuna.
But watch out for tuna who are a little too big.
Lest you suddenly be swallowed whole!
It Is Called a Man-Eating Tuna
Hey, Natsume!
Want to go to Guruguru Sushi next Saturday?
You really do love Guruguru Sushi, don't you?
Yep! And if I give them this flyer, I'll get this Guruguru Sushi keychain I've been wanting.
Guruguru Sushi is nice, but I prefer the Maguro Zanmai next door.
(tuna rice bowl)
That's right! Their zugedon is really delicious!
Right?
Maguro Zanmai's zugedon, huh?
Jii doesn't know! What's zuge? Is it tasty?
Well, zuke is...
Well... zuke is...
...a sushi topping made of lean tuna meat seasoned in a soy sauce base.
It's a topping that's loved by both children and adults alike!
It's a new post.
Umm... Let's see...
Ah... A flying man-eating tuna?
M-Man-eatting tuna!?
Oooh, such an appropriately timed topic!
Wouldn't a shark be a more plausible man-eater than a tuna?
T-That's right!
What's next? Perhaps a man-eating sunfish?
No. This looks like it might be real.
According to this eyewitness's post...
"It suddenly appeared overhead... and tried to swallow me whole!"
"Luckily, I was able to get away, but..."
"...I saw a family get swallowed right before my eyes!"
T-That's gotta be an urban legend, right?
Because tuna generally don't eat humans.
And I've also read that tuna only eat smaller fish!
More importantly, tuna can't fly at all, can they?
This is definitely the work of a Yo-kai!
I call it the "Flying Man-eating Tuna Yo-kai!"
That's just what it is...
Fatty's style gets 0 points!
I told you, I'm not fat! I'm big boned.
Zero points! Zero points!
-Anyway, as the Yo-kai Detective Agency, we can't ignore this.
Let's start interviewing!
Alright!
I've got some homework to do...
No need to be afraid, Keisuke!
When you get huge muscles and become a burly guy like me, there will be nothing left to fear!
Let's start training!
Lend me your body!
S-Something smells a little sour, though!
It appeared while I was coming home from campus.
It was eerie... And it came from the grey clouds above...
What's that?
GURORORORORORO
No way!
All I could focus on was on finding refuge.
Before I knew it, it had disappeared.
Hey, Mom... I'm hungry... Let's have some sushi!
Ah! I wanna eat sushi too!
Guruguru Sushi
I see. It's getting a little late, so let's have some and go right home.
Alright!
Sushi! Sushi!
When a family caught its attention, it appeared again.
In that case, Mom's going to have the tuna rice bowl, then...
It swallowed up the entire family and disappeared into the sky.
I have no idea when it'll appear again.
You should stay away from the shopping district too.
Goodbye. That's all I have for you.
Hmm? What's that?
Is that the keychain from Guruguru Sushi?
That's a tuna sushi keychain.
I think I've seen it somewhere before.
Hey, Keisuke. About the man-eating tuna...
W-What about it?
What if this tuna Yo-kai is acting to get revenge on humans for eating tuna all the time?
Ha, ha, ha... What are you saying?
Th-Th-That can't be true!
It'd be awful to die by getting eaten by a tuna, though.
Well, there's no way that's possible.
And now we're reporting on the serial kidnapping incidents.
More victims were found kidnapped in Sakura-motomachi's shopping district  by an unknown perpetrator.
What was your situation?
We were trying to have some sushi for dinner,
but as soon as the kids tried to enter the restaurant...
-Huh?
...we were all knocked out before I even realized it.
-That's the Guruguru Sushi keychain!
It seems pretty popular.
All victims since have found themselves regaining consciousness in the same fishmonger's storehouse.
But no victim has any memory of the perpetrator's appearance nor the exact moment of their kidnapping.
My fellow detectives!
Let's analyze the clues we have so far.
We contacted the college student yesterday.
The family that was swallowed whole was the one on TV.
Everyone who was kidnapped at the shopping district was carried to the fishmonger's storehouse.
And for some reason, the victims don't remember the exact moment of the incident.
But the college student saw the moment the family was attacked at Guruguru Sushi.
That's right! And the perpetrator is a tuna!
So as far as the clues are concerned...
We'll definitely find our next lead at Guruguru Sushi!
Okay. Let's go.
It's been decided.
What? We're going?!
Of course! If we're lucky, we'll find the tuna Yo-kai.
You call that "lucky"?
Lucky in another sense, you see.
Well... We're here. So far so good.
Guruguru Sushi
Let's see if the tuna will come as well.
Hey... Maybe we should go home?
Don't get panicky! We're here with you too, you know.
Ah, by the way...
Maguro
Zanmai
Maguro Zanmai is just next door, right?
That's right.
My family often orders deliveries of tuna zugedon from there.
Mine too.
But...
Ever since the son inherited the business recently, the recipes changed.
It hasn't tasted the same at all.
Come to think of it, Grandma said the same thing.
This is all wrong...
That man-eating tuna isn't appearing, even though we've waited for it.
It's not like we'd definitely meet it just by coming here.
There should be something that provokes the man-eating tuna into coming out, right?
Come to think of it, that college student also had a Guruguru Sushi keychain, right?
That's the same one as the family who was interviewed on the news had!
So does this mean that hanging that keychain while passing through here causes you to be attacked by the man-eating tuna?
We can't say for sure...
...but we could try testing that theory out.
Keisuke...
No no no no! I won't be your guinea pig!
You have the flyer to exchange for that keychain, right?
Huh? Umm.... yeah.
I'll get that keychain then.
Welcome!
Here.
Aaaaaah! I don't want it!
So you've finally appeared, man-eating tuna!
It's coming this way!
It's coming!
It's coming back!
Leave it to me! Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
C'mere!
Fool! As if a fish can win against a cat!
Don't underestimate me!
Hey Jibanyan! Don't eat it!
Light!
What's with this?!
Geez.
That happens when you feed a cat fish, right?
Then just leave this to me!
With these trained muscles, even Yo-kai...!
One-hit KO, huh?
I didn't even ask him to do that.
W-What do I do with this keychain!?
Hide it for now.
Huh?
Just hurry and do it!
Ah, uh-huh...
Sakura Shopping District
There's no mistaking it.
That man-eating tuna is after that keychain!
But why?
People who have that keychain have been to Guruguru Sushi, so...
Maybe that Yo-kai  holds a grudge against people who've eaten tuna from Guruguru Sushi...
That means that all the victims have been inside that restaurant.
That's right...
Maybe it's just hungry, and it mistook that keychain for food?
Even if it's a Yo-kai, a tuna wouldn't eat a tuna.
Ah... I see.
Anyway, that keychain is the key.
It's a KEYchain, after all...
"The KEYchain is the key," he said!
Nice joke!
I don't think it's that funny, though.
They sure do love dad jokes...
That person is...
I've seen that person before...
Who is he?
He's Maguro Zanmai's young master.
He's the one who recently inherited the store?
Damn it...
Does that owner hate Guruguru Sushi?
It's because they took away his customers.
That's...
That's the Guruguru Sushi keychain!
Why does the young storeowner have that?
That can't mean that he's also a customer, right?
Ah, I just remembered! That's...
Not good! That guy's going to be attacked next!
That's right!
Hey you, Maguro Zanmai's owner!
What is it, you guys?
Hurry and hide that keychain you have on your belt!
Huh?!
That's Guruguru Sushi's keychain you have there, right!?
Ah, you mean this?
This is a memento of my father, the previous owner.
What? That's not from Guruguru Sushi?
So that keychain was made before Guruguru Sushi went into business, right?
Yeah.
How did you know, Touma?
When I ordered out from there, I saw it on his bike keys.
Ah...
Guruguru Sushi's been giving out identical ones.
That's exactly right. So...
What was that?!
It's come back, huh?
It found that keychain!
Lend that to us, please!
Huh...? Ok...
What are we doing?
Keisuke!
Huh?
I leave it to you!
Whaaat? Gimme a break!
-Aahhhh... What a splendid tuna...
Whisper.
-Whis?!
Pass.
-Whiss!? Midair toss!!!
...And attack...!
Watch out!
What is this!?
What's happening?
He doesn't have the keychain, but it's still after him?
Maybe it was after him all along?
H-He got eaten?
But we know where they're going next.
Yeah.
The fish market.
It's here, right? The kidnapped victims are always brought here.
That's what the news says.
It's the young master!
Is he dead?
Don't worry. He's fine.
Young master!
Master, get a hold of yourself.
You guys...
Good thing you're okay.
I'm sure that tuna...
This place...
I get it...
My dad used this warehouse...
Aaah! It's coming!
It's my dad's truck.
This is...
What is it?
Notes?
My father's zugedon recipe is written here.
No matter how many times I tried... I couldn't make the same flavor my dad did.
Hey there, Noboru!
Huh?
It can't be... Dad?!
Hey there!
Whaaaat?!
The man-eating tuna was Maguro Zanmai's previous owner!?
Did you bring me here to read your notes?
Well, I didn't know for certain...
But I was sure I'd bring you over here somehow eventually.
As soon as I died and became a Yo-kai, I couldn't tell the difference between people anymore.
I thought I could identify you by your keychain...
I wound up targeting people with that tuna keychain and bringing them here.
By swallowing them whole, right?
Well, that was my fault.
Who could have known that so many people would have a keychain just like the one I made?
It couldn't be helped that I mistook complete strangers for you. Bwahahaha!
But why did you turn into a tuna Yo-kai, though?
That's the biggest mystery right now.
For sure.
It's like you said, Dad.
You wanted to be reborn as a delicious tuna and be part of the finest zugedon bowl.
That's right!
A customer's smiling face makes me happy!
Looks like I've become a tuna for real! Bwahahahaha!
"Bwahaha," he says...
But actually... Father...
Ever since you've died, the store's customers have been dwindling...
It's because of the sushi bar nearby...
...That's the excuse I've told myself.
I've realized that there's another reason there's fewer customers.
It's because my zugedon is terrible...
I couldn't replicate your flavor... I always knew there was something missing, but...
I didn't understand what it was...
Noboru...
The marination temperature of the tuna for zuge is most important.
The most comfortable temperature for tuna is also the best temperature for marination.
Comfortable...? You've even become a tuna for this...
I can't compete with you, Dad.
Obviously!
Noboru, I know you can be a great sushi chef.
Ever since you were little, you've always preferred my sushi.
Without question!
Father...
Take care...
Why did the ark come to me?
Isn't it because you have the tuna keychain?
It's the Guruguru Sushi keychain though.
Even so, he sure caused an uproar.
That Maguro Zanmai master chef...
He swallowed people whole just to bring his son to him...
Tuna dad's smelly mouth is smelly!
Did you mean that he works in roundabout ways?
Well... A master craftsman can be especially tactless sometimes.
But everyone is still okay in the end, though.
Case closed, right?
Somehow, I kinda feel like I want to eat sushi now.
Me too! Me too!
It's been a while since I've wanted to eat Maguro Zanmai's zugedon again.
Huh?
Yes?
Hey, Akinori!
Young master!
I've finally recreated my father's flavor!
I want you guys to try it out first!
Mmmm.... It's delicious!
It's so good!
It's my dad's original flavor.
So good!
This goes straight to the muscles!
I'm biting more that I can chew!
Have some, Jii!
Jii loves zuge!
This is the best, young master!
Thank you! Feel free to have more!
Excuse me.
Clues to the princess are...
Very well...
There are other things to do.
I'll be playing with you soon.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Akinori's
Yo-kai Watch Shadowside
Trivia
Today, we're talking about the arks!
An ark is proof that one has made a connection with a Yo-kai and became their friend.
When you use the Yo-kai Watch Elder with an ark, you can summon friendly yo-kai.
You can choose between the Lightside or Shadowside forms based on the direction you turn it.
Geez! I wanna try summoning too!
Hey, have you all heard?
About a man who swoops down to attack women at night?
I don't know and I don't want to know!
They say he screams, "Let's chop!" while attacking people.
The victims are all women, right?
Then I'll lure it out.
Don't do it!
Then let me lure it out!
Huh? How?
Don't worry. I've practiced for this!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Terrible Ripping Joker