Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 3:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
See you later!
Bye!
And after this...
Yes! I've got it!
Once I've gathered this key card, I can complete the combo!
Ah! Yes! I've got it!
Hey...look at me...
Wha... What is it?
Play... with... me...
C'mon... let's... play.
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
This time, it's a tale of a fearsome boy who attacks children.
If you let your guard down, he might steal something important from you.
(Plundering Demon)
Ryakudatsuma Red Head
Woah!
What's this? Everyone's gathered together here!
Keisuke, so you've finally realized that you belong in the Yo-kai Detective Agency after all!
I haven't realized anything. I don't remember joining.
You don't know when to give up.
Anyway, what are you guys doing?
I'm thinking of a strategy.
Strategy?
(Lighting Speed Era)
It's for the Denkousekka Card game.
The one with the TV commercials about it?
I know nothing about it.
Speaking of card games,
There were posts about it for sure...
It's here!
(Plundering Demon)
The Roaring Ryakudatsuma Red Head?
Yeah.
(Lighting Speed Era)
He steals cards from other players of Denkousekka.
He's a boy who wears a red cap.
(Plundering Demon)
His nickname is the Roaring Ryakudatsuma Red Head!
Roaring?
Yeah.
When Red Head attacks people, he's said to let out a scream.
It's said that he made his victims scream as well.
It's possible that if you're challenged to a duel with Red Head,
...unspeakable things happen during the game.
Unspeakable things?
I don't know the details, but...
...this smells like a savory mystery!
"Smells savory," he says.
Ah!
Looks like you guys are at it again!
That urban legend is definitely fake! It's nonsense!
For someone takes that position, you're here quite often.
What!?
(Lighting Speed Era)
I'm just here to play Denkousekka with Touma.
Let's leave Keisuke behind and go investigate!
See you later, then.
You're Jouji, right? On the mystery website "Usuramera,"
you wrote the article about Red Head, didn't you?
I know it's scary, but can you tell us what happened?
So...
That day, I was at the card shop sorting my cards.
And then he...
Hey.
Duel... with me...
Huh? Who are you?
If I win, give me your card.
In the end, he got me to duel with him.
We continued the game for several turns, and then..
He drew that card...
Red Dragon!
He drew the Burning Dragon card!
What!?
Burning Dragon?
(Lighting Speed Era)
In Denkousekka, it's an extremely rare and powerful card.
That Burning Dragon card...
It was terrifying. I don't want to think about it again.
(Plundering Demon)
Roaring Ryakudatsuma Red Head... Who is he?
Let's see...
Perhaps it's the spirit of a dead boy who couldn't get a rare card,
And underneath his red cap, is a skeleton filled with malice...
T-That's certainly frightening.
Or perhaps it's...
A mother ghost wanting kids to stop playing card games.
She possesses kids... and makes them eat cards...
That seems less like a Yo-kai, and more like an evil spirit!
At any rate. It doesn't matter who's fault it is. We need to do something.
Yeah.
♪ Yo-kai are just a dream ♪
♪ There's no such thing ♪
Hey.
You... over there..
Look here.
R-Red Head!?
Let's play!
Huh... How do we even find Red Head?
Jouji's story was pretty surprising.
I can't believe that someone actually had the Burning Dragon card.
You're surprised by that!?
The supernatural phenomenon is more surprising, though!
Of course, that's kinda surprising too...
"Kinda"!?
But the Burning Dragon is rarest among the rare cards.
($10,000 USD)
It's said to be worth one million yen.
For real?
That expensive!?
Natsume!
Keisuke!?
What happened!?
M-My card....
Don't tell me...
Was it Red Head?
Yeah.
Are you feeling better?
Yeah, thanks.
At any rate, Keisuke's always getting mixed up with these incidents, isn't he?
Perhaps he's predisposed to this kind of thing?
N-No way!
Hey Keisuke, can you tell us anything about Red Head?
Umm... Sure...
Give me... the white... dog!
That's what he said.
White dog?
Yeah.
It's not a dog,
(Blizzard Wolf)
But I've heard of a card called the Fubuki no Ookami or Blizzard Wolf.
Ah! I know about that too! It's an ultimate super rare card, right?
Is Red Head looking for that card?
(Blizzard Wolf)
Fubuki no Ookami? Blizzard Wolf?
-That seems to be likely.
However, the Blizzard Wolf,
just like the Burning Dragon, is a legend.
These cards are fantasies.
That's right.
A legend huh?
Hey, guys...
Huh?
Do you mean this card?
What!?
The Blizzard Wolf is real?
Why do you have it, Natsume?
You guys were so obsessed with it, I bought one for myself.
I just remembered that I was keeping it inside this book I'm reading.
Geez! Don't use rare cards as bookmarks for your paperback!
But it's perfect for this though.
But if we have that, we could use it to lure out Red Head!
Huh!?
Then let's do it.
Um... Let's do something before that.
There... That's better.
Touma, you're unusually obsessed with this...
Don't use it as a bookmark anymore, okay?
Please treat it carefully.
You guys are so fussy.
Well, you're just too careless, Natsume!
-A new post?
It's too risky letting you hold it. Let me hold on to it.
No, let me take care of it.
This is bad!
Huh?
Red Head has appeared!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Huh?
What is that?
What are you guys doing!? Get the hell out of the way!
Hey, jerk! Are you listening, you brat!?
Shut... your... mouth..!
It's him! He's the one who attacked me!
Natsume, the card.
Yeah.
Red Head!
The card you're looking for... is right here!
Give me! White... dog!
(Lighting Speed Era)
If you want it, then let's have a game of Denkousekka!
I'll... win. And take... White... Dog.
Let's go. Battle Start!
It's my turn first. I'll draw a card.
I'll set my Slime on the lock field.
I declare my attack and end my turn.
My turn.... Draw...
I use my Goblin's ability to preempt your Slime's attack.
Oh no!
Does it look bad?
Against monsters of the same or lower rank, Goblin card has an ability...
...to nullify preceding declarations of attack and do a preemptive strike!
Sorry, I didn't understand a word you said.
It's my turn. I draw a card.
I use last standby while setting my Pegasus on the flash field. I end my turn!
My turn... Draw...
I set my Basilisk on the flash field while declaring my attack. I end my turn.
It's my turn. I draw a card.
I've won!
Blizzard Wolf!
I set my Blizzard Wolf on the lightning field.
On my next turn, I'll initiate my ultimate attack, Great Ice Age!
Dr...Draw.
Heh... Heh heh heh... Heh heh heh heh...
Red... Dragon!
Burning Dragon!?
Heh...  Heh heh heh heh...
Heh... Heh heh heh heh... Heh heh heh...
This looks really bad!
Give me... White dog!
Is that a transformation ability? I can do that too!
Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
Possession! Genma Goemon! Lend me your strength!
Twelve O'clock. Goemon!
Here's Goemon!
W... What is that!?
It's the Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
Yo-kai Watch Momangre!?
You only got the "gre" part right.
It's Ogre!
This Yo-kai Watch can summon high ranking Genma Yo-kai.
You select a Genma based on the time on the watch and have it possess you.
What's this sensation...?
Attacks aren't working!
Huh?
It's as if... Ah! I get it!
Touma, try blowing away the smoke around it!
Yeah.
Huh?
Somehow, it seems a lot less impressive now.
What was that?
That Burning Dragon is a balloon.
It's the same as a blimp!
Swinging a sword at it won't damage it.
In that case...
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
Six O'clock. Yoshitsune.
Yoshitsune has arrived!
He... He changed again!?
That's Genma Yoshitsune!
He can find an enemy's weakness with calm reasoning!
I've found it. There is just one way to defeat you!
Prepare yourself!
It has a valve?
What? It's coming here!
Wait... What is this? It's sticky!
Now it'll never attack anyone ever again.
-Geez! Stay still already! Stay still!
It feels warm...! Disgusting!
-I'm peeling it off, stop panicking!
It's so sticky! I can't take it off!
-Doesn't it kinda stink?
Ah geez!
It's... It's off...
It's an ark!
What is this ark?
It says "Junior."
Here! Here!
I'm Jii!
Huh? It's cute!
Are you Junior?
I'm Jii!
Is Jii short for Junior?
Yeah!
I'm Natsume.
You're... Natsume!
What's with this tiny...
Ouch! Let me go, you!
Begh! Fatty's salty!
Hey... Th-that's mean...
Get thinner, fatty!
That's none of your business!
Huh?
Hey, hey, hey...
Is it turning into a dragon again!?
It's me?
Cool, it's just like you!
What's it doing now?
That was scary!
Get thinner, fatty! Or you'll pop!
I'm not popping!
Anyways, I'm not fat! I'm just big-boned.
Perhaps it's concerned about your health?
Maybe.
So is Jii able to transform into anything?
Jii swells. Becomes... Becomes dragon!
Why a dragon?
Jii wins! Jii gets cards!
There's games where if you win, you also win the opponent's card.
But Jii got too excited for game. Jii became a dragon.
So when you're excited about a game, you accidentally transform.
Anyway, why did you want the Blizzard Wolf card, anyway?
Gimme white dog!
This?
But why this card...?
My Blizzard Wolf!
Wait! My Blizzard Wolf!
It's really mine, though!
Candy Shop
Motomachi
Here's your change.
Candy Shop
Motomachi
Thank you.
Careful on your way home.
Oomph.
Old lady's here! Old lady!
Old lady?
The old lady over there?
It's rude to call her old lady.
Old lady... doesn't have long.
What are you saying?
That's why old lady meet Pochi.
Meet Pochi?
What do you mean?
Old lady and Pochi always together.
Old lady loves Pochi!
But...
Pochi died.
Old lady not happy.
Old lady sad.
Jii sad.
Jii decided.
Jii become Pochi!
Old lady become happy!
So you wanted to become Pochi for the old lady's sake?
Jii, you're so kind.
But... what does this have to do with Blizzard Wolf?
Pochi white dog.
If Jii has template, Jii can become!
But no template for Pochi
But but!
There's white dog!
Jii found it! White dog on TV!
NEW!
CARD
Ah, that's the commercial for it.
STRONGEST!
BLIZZARD WOLF!
But Red Dragon came on.
SIMULTANEOUS
RELEASE
BURNING DRAGON!
Jii made mistake.
I see. So you wanted to become Blizzard Wolf, not Burning Dragon.
Jii found template!
Jii become Pochi!
Do your best!
But wait, Pochi is an ordinary white dog, right?
Is it really okay for him to use Blizzard Wolf as a template?
Huh?
Well...
Hey old lady.
Huh?
Not good!
It looks just like Blizzard Wolf!
Oh dear, you look just like Pochi.
Huh?
Oh dear, you're cute.
Though I love the little white one who looks just like Pochi...
I love the small round red one too.
Small red one?
Was that old lady able to see Junior?
I had you worried, didn't I?
I'm not sad because you're here.
Old lady! Old lady! Old lady doesn't have long.
Together with Jii! Always here!
Thank you.
Good for Jii...
That's right.
So do you want come in and have some candy?
Which do you want? Spicy red snack? Chocobar?
Chocobars!
Alright.
Oh dear.
Did this picture fall down?
Sorry about that, Pochi.
That was Pochi?
That could've been a template really close at hand...
All our efforts were...
I'm a white dog, too.
The boy named Touma Tsukinami.
It appears that he has the power of being possessed by the Genma.
What shall we do?
Leave him alone.
Instead of that, hurry up the search for the usual.
Understood.
Touma Tsukinami...
I'll play with you before long.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Hey, did you guys know?
The story about a man who appears if you leave behind food.
What about it?
If you leave behind food, he'll say “what a waste.”
...and starve you to death while possessing you!
That's got to be fake!
All witnesses have been ramen shop owners.
In that case, we’ll all have to eat some ramen then!
Ahh! Natsume! It's here!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
(What a Waste Man)
Mottainai Otoko