Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 6 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Hey, do you know about Jinmenken?
(Manjimutt)
Jinmenken? What is that?
There's a dog that dumpster dives along the road on dark nights like these.
When someone shouted, "Hey, you!" at him...
...he looked back...
...revealing that his face wasn't a dog's face, but a human's face!
What? That's creepy!
And then after that....
"Leave me alone!"
That's what he said!
Let's stop talking about that creepy thing and leave it be.
Right.
A stray dog?
(Manjimutt)
Could it be a Jinmenken?
Isn't that just a rumor?
That's doggone scary! But it's a story with more bark than bite!
Whoa, that's a terrible pun!
You gonna PUNish me for that pun?
Huh?
Heh.... Heh heh...
That's got to be a normal dog, right?
O...Of course, right?
There's no such thing as an animal with a dog's body and a human face...
Huh?
Woof! Woof! Woof!!!
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
If you see a dog on the roadway, be very careful.
It might not really be a dog.
If it has the face of a dog but the body of a person, it will attack you.
What is it hiding behind that broad grin?
Its name is...
Smiling Dog Man
And that's what the feudal lord said to his vassels...
Ah, but why?
They used a cleanser to wipe the fry basket used for salmon.
But this was supposed to be the Edo period!
The Comedy M-1 Grand Prix this year sure is funny!
There were a lot of new performers this year too.
Why are you taking notes?
I'm doing a skit for the school festival.
I figured I would go this year.
I've been practicing with Tank and Kouji.
It's been pretty fun!
No way. You're gonna bomb. Just stop.
What? You don't know until you try!
I know. You'll bomb. Lame! Lame!
C'mere you little...
Don't run around in other people's houses!
Geez...
This isn't a playground for little kids.
S-Sorry.
Understand?
Members of the Yo-kai Detective Agency should always be...
-Ah! The next two performers are Universal Television!
What? For real?
That's the hottest group these days...!
Hold on a second!
Woah, that's incredible!
That's the perfect delayed punchline!
Huh?
Show me more!
R-Really?
Ahem...
Well... as the senior comedian around here...
Hold it! Who cares who's the senior comedian!?
Incredible! Akinori, you're perfect at this!
Excuse me...
(The Yo-kai World)
I can teach you the muscle gag comedy I learned in Youmakai...
Be quiet!
I guess no one asked...
Muscles got dumped!
Natsume's roasts are good too!
Quit fooling around!!!
Stop look at comedy skits! Get working on cases!
For example, how about this?
Smiling Dog Man?
Is it some kind of dog?
(Manjimutt)
Is it not Jinmenken?
No way.
(Manjimutt)
Jinmenken is old news. I put it at a low level of strangeness.
Old?
Did you just say "level of strangeness?"
Take a look at this.
Isn't there a superhero movie called "Mr .Dog-Man"?
Because Dog Man looks similar to this character, he was named after him.
I know about this.
However,
The Dog Man on the Usuranura website isn't the same gentle canine as the one in this superhero movie.
Huh?
The Smiling Dog Man...
...is said to swoop down on passersby with sharp claws while howling.
After cutting them all to pieces, he laughs as he disappears, they say.
A...All of them?
No way! There's definitely no such thing!
W-What was that?
What was that sound!?
That was an alert from the Youma Radar.
There's a chance the Dog Man might appear.
If you're so afraid, why are you following us?
I've got to prove to everyone that Dog Man doesn't exist.
You're really just afraid of being left alone.
Huh?
That's...
What...
What the heck is this?
Can you tell us what happened?
So we were walking home together...
While telling puns...
Uh-huh.
Puns?
It wasn't anything special. We were just telling puns.
Aluminum foiled my plans!
My kangaroo feels so hoppy!
Huh?
And then that's when the Dog Man appeared with its creepy smile.
We were so scared, we couldn't even move!
But then he ignored us and just walked away!
I honestly thought that we were about to be killed.
Me too.
Was it Dog Man's goal to try to scare them?
Maybe it was just upset for some reason?
In any case, he's a dangerous Yo-kai.
W-Well, I guess I'll leave it to you self-proclaimed Yo-kai detectives.
Are you thinking of going home just to hide under the blanket?
This case might be too rough on scaredy-cat Keisuke.
M-me? Scared?
Since when? At what hour, minute, and second?
What... What's that sound!?
It's just the Youma Radar's alarm tone.
That's the second time today, too.
Alright, it's close.
Woah.
What's this?
That electronics store got messed up!
How awful.
Gimme a break!
Don't tell me, Dog Man did this too.
But it's true!
I really did see the Dog Man!
Is that so? We officers saw it too!
Please wait here.
We're going to find your mother.
Do you have a moment?
Was Dog Man really here?
Uh-huh.
You see, when he was over there...
So on May 4th, two Jedi Knights met with each other,
Are you trying to say, "May the Fourth be with you"?
Nah. They were just saying hi.
Wait, that wasn't a joke?
And then he started breaking all the other TVs.
Is that so.
That seemed frightening.
You weren't hurt, were you?
I'm fine.
It doesn't look like anyone else was attacked.
What was his goal, anyway?
So after stuffing himself with plain cereal, he explained that he doesn't drink tea.
The heck!? Doesn't he mean milk!?
-Huh?
If only we had some other clue...
That's right.
-Um, hey, guys...
I think I understand what Dog Man is trying to do.
Seriously!? That's incredible, Keisuke!
So what is the Dog Man after?
Hey, Keisuke...
Is Dog Man really going to come?
I don't know. Maybe he'll come.
Hey! Keisuke!
What did you want to do with us here?
Hey! We were waiting for you two!
And now...
...we will be starting our skit!
What?
A skit?
A comedy routine?
That's right!
We assembled as a trio to perform at the school festival!
We're doing this now?
But we don't have enough practice!
Nah, we can do it! Let's just try!
Now if I'm right...
If we do a comedy routine here in public, it should lure out Dog Man.
He's definitely gonna come... He'll come out... He's coming...!
Dog Man?
Your legs are shaking.
What's the connection between Dog Man and comedy?
Well... once we do the skit, that should be clear.
I don't know what's going on, but let's do this.
Right!
Eh...whatever.
And now...
I'm Keisuke!
I'm Kouji!
I'm Tank!
And together, we are... Keisuke-Kouji!
Tank!
What? Oh, me?
But I'm not even in there!
Ya got me!
This already smells like trouble...
Seems like they need to work on those jabs.
Ah! Sorry about that! We forgot to include you in the name, Tank!
Alright! Let's say it again!
I'm Keisuke!
I'm Kouji!
I'm Tank!
And together we are... the Walking Tank Man!
But that's just one person! You're only talking about me!
Oops! We messed up again!
It just got a little colder.
Maybe it's climate change?
They definitely need more work on this.
Geez, who are you calling a tank man?
-What's that?
At least call me a human tank instead!
Keisuke!
W-who the heck is that?!
So that's Dog Man?
But why did he appear?
I...I thought that maybe Dog Man was drawn in by jokes and puns.
What?
From what we heard from those two...
...they were attacked as they were joking.
And the TV at the electronics store was playing a comedy routine.
I get it.
So it's a Yo-kai that's drawn in by comedy.
Incredible! That's better than how you usually do, Keisuke.
What's up with that?!
Was that a comedic jab just now?
Seems like it! It's like he's trying to say "What's up with that!?"
I knew it!
Let's finish this once and for all!
Natsume! Use my Ark!
Got it.
Summon!
Light!
Come on out my friend! Charlie!
Huh?
The Yo-kai's not coming?
Did the summon fail?
No... No way! But why?
Sorry for the wait!
Charlie has now arrived!
Charlie rode a bike here...
And it's my bike too!
I'm so sorry!
Aagh! My bike too!?
We're not finished yet!
Let's go! Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
That hurt, nyaa!
Woof!
Ah! So cute!
Is this Dog Man's Lightside form?
Dog Man? My name is Lucky. Woof!
Lucky?
Do you remember when you were Dog Man?
Beats me.
I don't remember anything about breaking power poles or TVs at all.
Oh! But I do remember, though!
Ah! A delayed punchline!
Woof woof? That's right!
I've got something to do!
Huh?
Long ago, that Ucchan used to love me so much! Woof.
You mean that store clerk?
His real name is Uchida.
Uchida?
Ucchan was aiming to get to the top of the comedy world.
I still remember the day I met Ucchan.
Hey. Are you alright?
Ucchan adopted me after I was abandoned.
Even though Ucchan was struggling and didn't have much money,
he was able to take care of me.
Aren't you cute?
Your name is now Lucky.
Maybe some of your luck will fall on me and I'll become famous someday.
Well, being able to meet you was lucky enough, though.
We were so happy!
Ucchan was always so nice to me!
He was always together with me.
And one day, Ucchan thought up of a new gag.
Huh?
I'm back.
Did that surprise you, Lucky?
Looking at you inspired this.
I'll make it with this character!
I think I remember a performer with a dog mask...
His stage name is Inumamishi Sandaiyu.
Ah, really? I know that guy!
Me too.
Wasn't he quite famous for a while?
That's right!
He was a sharp-tongued solo performer in a dog mask.
What are you, a dog?
But now...
He hasn't appeared in a while, has he?
Like they say, television is all-or-nothing.
Ucchan did his best to get another chance.
I was cheering on for him so hard.
But then, around that time...
...I was involved in a traffic accident...
All I wanted to do was to repay Ucchan for his kindness.
Even though he had his own troubles, Ucchan was always kind.
I wished it was possible for us to do comedy together.
All of those thoughts piled together as I became Dog Man.
So that was why you were jabbing all over town...
That's right!
"What's up with that?" I said.
I was practicing straight man jabs.
I knew you were saying, "What's up with that!"
Looks like you were hitting a little too hard though.
Sorry about that.
Ucchan... I'm glad that you seem well.
Hey, Lucky...
Woof?
Wanna try talking with Ucchan again?
Huh?
Are you Lucky?
Woof!
Really? Here of all places?
I turned into a Yo-kai, but I've come back.
This goes for when he was Dog Man, too...
...When a Yo-kai tries to be seen, even normal people can see them.
That seems to be true.
Come to think of it...
Whenever I practiced in front of you, you always barked at just the right time.
You were trying to jab back, weren't you?
That's right.
Ucchan, let's get into the M-1 Grand Prix together!
I'll do my best to jab any wise guys!
Your routine would be much more interesting as a duo!
Let's fulfill our dream together!
In this form, I can stand together with you!
That's a little too much. It's hard to work with.
So this is no good?
Haha... I was joking. Strong impressions are good.
How about our group's name?
Nothing's better than "UcchieWoofie"!
That sounds pretty good.
Seems strangely fitting.
Since we're two dogs, how about "Two Woofs?"
That's good!
It sure is hot!
It's freezing, but I'm so sweaty!
What's up with that?
And that's why I'm such a hot dog!
Cut it out!
That looks fun.
Uh-huh.
Huh?
Isn' that guy...
♪ Here, there hot dogs everywhere ♪
Oops...
...hot dog...
Excuse me...
Huh?
Sorry for the interruption, but...
Would you like to form a group together?
Huh?
You don't mean...
Weren't you part of the South Pole Brothers?
That's right. I'm Nanjou.
I knew it!
I was aspiring to be like you!
I'm so happy to be able to speak with you!
Well, it's just that your skit is so amusing!
Is that true?
I'd like to enter the M-1 Grand Prix with you.
What? With me?
Yeah. Together, I feel like we might reach the top!
No... we'll definitely reach the top!
Umm....
But my partner is...
Huh?
Lucky?
Isn't that nice, Ucchan?
You've finally found a human partner.
WIth this, I can be at peace.
Ucchan, you'll definitely make everyone happy with your comedy!
I'll always be watching over you.
Lucky!
Thank you so much, Lucky!
This is all thanks to you!
I got through hard times because you were here for me, Lucky!
It's thanks to you that I am who I am now!
Ucchan...
We'll make it to the top!
Please watch over us!
Of course!
I always have, and I always will!
I'm your number one fan, Ucchan!
Lucky's going to Heaven...
That's right.
And right after that...
Uchida's comedy duo became a hit.
That's so funny!
Uchida and Nanjou... and Lucky too!
Yeah! That's Lucky...! Wait, he didn't leave for Heaven in the end?!
Ooh, that delayed punchline wasn't that bad.
Really?
These darts aren't hitting the target...
It's because your aiming is terrible.
That's why I'm training!
(Yo-kai Conversion Toxins)
If we can hit with these darts covered with Kaishin no Yodoku...
...we'll be able to tell who our princess is.
No matter what form she is in.
I understand.
Huh? Who are you guys?
What are you doing in my house?
I'm calling the cops...
Be silent.
Please excuse me...
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Akinori's
Yo-kai Watch Shadowside
Trivia
Today's trivia is about the Yo-kai Watch Elder!
The Yo-kai Watch Elder is the Elder Sorcery Mirror created by ancient people but modified by King Enma.
When used with the key-like Ark artifacts, you can summon friendly Yo-kai.
Natsume is its owner, but for some reason, Keisuke can use it too.
There might still be other features in it we don't know about!
Grrr..... I want one too!
Hey, have you guys heard?
There's this story about a woman who wears a long coat.
Eeee! I don't wanna know.
She'll ask you, "Do you think I'm pretty?" while lifting her hair.
And then her face splits vertically down in half!
This definitely sounds like an urban legend.
The bottom of this investigation reveals a surprising and touching episode.
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Split-Faced Woman