Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 15 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
This sign...
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
The girl sure is cute!
Huh? Which one?
There, the girl in the pigtails.
Ah! She really is cute!
Told ya!
The other girl in pigtails must be her friend.
Let's try chatting them up.
Ah. They were talking about the girl next to me.
She really is cute.
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Since ancient times, the hearts of people have been charmed by beauty.
But sometimes, things that are too beautiful invite conflict.
What a terrible thing this can be.
A Cute Girl Who Comes Once Every One Hundred Thousand Years
That girl that just passed by was so cute!
Seems like she's transferred into class A.
That girl...
Someone new is transferring into our class today.
Nice to meet you!
My name is Ayame Himeno.
Let's get along!
So cute!
She's beautiful!
Your desk should be...
Ah, there's an empty desk next to Touma.
Let's have you sit there.
Yes.
Let's get along.
Likewise.
Did you hear about the transfer student in class A?
I know about her.
She's Ayame Himeno, right?
That's right!
She's super cute!
She's the kind of girl who only comes along every 10,000 years!
Himeaya, wanna come walk home with us?
Himeaya?
Yep. Himeaya is short for Ayame Himeno. Himeaya.
That's not bad!
Friends of
Himeaya
Unite!
Fanclub
Recruiting new
club members!
Those applying to Himeaya's fan club, line up here!
Recruiting new
club members!
Thank
you
very
much!
New members may line up for free photos with Himeaya!
She's even got a fan club?
She's become quite the idol.
Himeaya, wanna go for karaoke after school?
Sorry. That doesn't work out for me today.
Bye!
Excuse me.
I've met you before at the intersection, right?
You remember me?
Yes.
I'm Natsume Amano.
I'm Ayame Himeno.
Let's get along, Natsume!
Likewise! And thanks!
It's really amazing!
The new girl got really popular overnight!
She's that cute?
Let's see...
She's gotta have pictures online.
Here she is.
Whoa, she's cute.
She's not bad!
This again?
There's no reason to make a huge fuss.
-Look here.
She's gotta be the sort of cutie that only appears every 100,000 years!
Now hold on!
Natsume's the only one who deserves to be described as a "cute girl!"
Well, just take a look.
How lovely...
Muscles is having an affair!
Y-You've got the wrong idea!
I, Micchi, am completely devoted to Natsume!
I don't care either way.
She might be targeted as the next victim!
What do you mean by "targeted?"
This post has gotten popular recently.
Serial Disappearances of Beautiful Girls?!
Author: Yosshii
Recently, the prettiest girl at school hasn't been showing up to class, so I’ve been
asking around to try to find out the reason, worried that she might be missing.
There are reports that a girl who looks just like her has been seen at the department
store, but she still hasn't shown up to class. I’m wondering if she really has
gone missing?
I’ve tried asking one of her friends who has commuted to school with her, but since
she’s also one of the prettiest girls at school, it seems that she’s also disappeared.
Beautiful girls seem to vanish continuously.
Could they be mixed up in something bad…?
See Comments(56)
Disappearances of beautiful women?
There are incidents of women suddenly going missing.
And it's only beautiful women, too.
Are they being kidnapped?
No.
According to Usuranura, supernatural phenomena might be involved.
For example, it might be a monster who rejuvenates their youth by devouring the beautiful!
Or it might be a reaper who leads women astray with some enchanted flute, and then steals their souls!
I'm not listening! I'm not listening to any of this!
We can't stand for this!
We must protect Himeaya!
You're just using that as an excuse to try to meet with Himeaya.
Alright, Touma! Let's go!
Me?
Whatever! Just come!
Hey... Akinori!
I might as well come along! Whis!
Oh, dear.
I hope we're not being too much of a bother to Ayame.
Whoa.
She's not one in 10,000! She's a beauty of one in a 100,000 years!
Akinori, settle down.
Shall I carry your luggage?
Oh, dear!
Kindness
Patience
Please support our fundraising campaign!
Please!
Philanthropy
She's too perfect!
Her moral character is also one in 100,000 years!
Together with her cuteness, she's a beauty of one in 200,000 years!
What kind of math is that?
Anyway, she's super important, Touma!
Touma?
I knew it was you, Touma! What a coincidence!
That's right.
Who's sitting next to you?
Ah, he's my friend...
A...A-A-Aye'm...
A-Aye'm Akinori Arihoshi, a student at Momijijima Middle School!
"Aye'm"?
My name is Ayame Himeno.
Ayame, we have something very important to tell you!
...And that's why we think you might be targeted as the next victim.
How do you know this?
That's because our job is to investigate the world's vast mysterious phenomena.
We're the Yo-kai Detective Agency.
Detective Agency?
S-Sorry for bothering you all of a sudden.
Not at all. It sounds really interesting!
I'd like to join as well!
ALL RIGHT!
You're very welcome!
Yay!
Let's get along, Akinori!
And us too, Touma!
They said that all the disappearing victims were last seen around here.
The other thing they have in common is that they all aspired to be idols.
So were they all scouted in front of the game arcade?
Do those scouts have some connection to the disappearances?
It doesn't seem to be related to the supernatural.
Natsume!
If you ever... get stumped... I highly recommend... doing some squats!
Keisuke, do you have any ideas?
Huh...? Um...
Why don't you try luring out a scout while Micchi and I look from afar?
What?
Nice idea!
OK.
How beautiful!
Awesome. I've never seen Natsume like this before!
It's a nice style, isn't it, Keisuke?
I've prepared it just for this moment. It's the Micchi Lovey Dovey set!
Natsume, that's awesome!
In what way?!
Take a gander at the Slimamander! Just kidding! Ha, ha, ha!
-Hey, There's no way a scout would be impressed with this...
Stop taking pictures! Geez!
This'll be easy-peasy! A conspicuous outfit is gonna attract scouts in no time!
Easy for you to say!
Geez. This is embarrassing.
Do you have a moment?
Would you kindly take this picture for us?
Ah, sure.
'Scuse me!
Which way is the station?
Oh, the station? The station is over there.
I can't take it anymore!
There's no way I can attract any scouts in this outfit!
Maybe that outfit is way too avant-garde for this era!
You don't even know anything...
Why not take a break? We’ll go buy something for you.
Just get me some refreshing soda to drink, then.
Alrighty.
You can count on me to do your errands anytime!
Away!
Must resist hurling insults...
W-What?
I've found you...
Smile.
W-What was that just now?!
With my passion and expertise, any girl can become an idol.
W-Who are you?!
Nice to meet you.
This is who I am.
IDOL PRODUCER
Idol producer?
Don't tell me this is the guy...
Mmmmm! You're good!
You're really good!
Your height, your hairstyle, and even your looks!
You're a really plain girl!
That sounds like faint praise to me.
Here's what I meant by "normal."
Like a perfect piece of porcelain pottery clay, you can be molded into any shape with infinite possibilities!
But not with these on, though.
Away! Heh, heh, heh, heh.
Of course...
Now then...
There, there. No need to be afraid.
Just leave everything to me.
Now let's kneed! Kneed and bake!
I'll turn you into a shiny new porcelain idol!
And it's done!
What?! What just happened to me?
Everyone's so beautiful!
Let's welcome our new member.
H... H-Help me!!!
SHADOWSIDE
Did you find my sister?
No. I couldn't find her.
Same here.
Let's try looking somewhere else. We'll definitely find her.
Thank you, Ayame.
Hmmm... This is really strange.
There's no response from my Natsume Sensor.
Sensor?
It's a bond of love between Natsume and me.
There you go with that nonsense again...
Nevertheless, this case seems to be connected to Yo-kai as well.
We've arrived.
Arrived? Where?
Isn't it obvious?
Where else do idols belong?
This...
is...
...the stage!
What....?!
A concert at the mall?!
What are you trying to do?
Don't forget to smile passionately!
Yes!
No way...
My body is moving on its own!
Hey everyone!
Nice to meet you!
We're a freshly formed idol group!
(Arita Porcelain 46)
We're Aritayaki46!
So, everyone, please listen to our debut song,
"A Young Lady's Heart Shatters Easily, So Do Be Careful!"
No! Stop it!
Someone help!
What's wrong?
That was Natsume's voice!
So his bonds of love sensor finally picked something up, huh?
Well let's notify the gang for now.
Seems like Micchi headed for the shopping mall.
Let's go there as well.
That was great!
That was a great concert!
But you girls should be capable of more!
But you were just controlling us the whole time!
Alright! Let's start practicing for some new performances!
Lessons! Lessons!
Ah! Natsume!
Who's that guy?!
Maybe he's the scout that has something to do with the disappearances.
Let's go after him!
Uh-huh.
Where'd he go?
Natsume!
"Bonds of love?" Looks more like a stalker's stubbornness.
Umm...
Who was that purple person just now?
You were able to see him?
Yeah.
One! Two! One! Two!
Smile and turn!
Yes! And stop!
Hold it, everyone.
You're not smiling enough!
Ewww. This is humiliating.
Hold it right there, villain!
Who was that?
Alright!
How the heck does that work?
E-Everyone's here! Ayame is here too!
Who are you people?!
You're the one who kidnapped all those girls, didn't you?
G-Give me back my sister!
That won't do.
I won't let you interrupt my lesson.
You've come to steal away my idols, haven't you?
W-What?!
He's...
He was a Yo-kai all along.
What's this?
Shadowside
Yo-kai KamaDOUma
Umm... It's the Yo-kai Kamadoma?
Pleased to meet you!
Okay, it's my turn!
Possession! Genma Benkei!
Lend me your strength!
Benkei... has arrived!
Producing idols is my mission!
Those who stand in my way shall be burned in the fires of my kiln!
Natsume! Hey, Natsume!
Natsume!
Ah! I'm finally back!
Thank you, everyone.
Anyway, what's with those clothes?
Did you get a makeover?
It's not like I wanted to wear this!
I won't forgive him for this!
Micchi! Shadowside!
Shadow!
Alright, Micchi, finish him off!
You're finished.
I didn't expect Natsume to be this intense.
She's scary when she's angry.
Huh?
You can't make me give up.
I must produce the best idol group ever!
I won't ever give up!
Mr. Kamamoto?
You're Kamamoto the producer, right?
We were so worried when we heard that you went missing!
Long time no see!
Who are you girls?
Don't you remember?
It's been more than twenty years.
Twenty years ago?
You're the first idol group I produced for!
(Seto Ceramic 46)
The founding members of Setoyaki46!
Hana! Yuki! Tsuki!
That's right.
I was raised in a family that made pottery for generations.
But then, one day.
I found something that moved my heart even more than pottery.
And it was idol groups!
I'll create Japan's most glamorous idol group ever!
And to fulfill that dream, I produced for a group.
Setoyaki46
debut single
"Please, Round &
Round Shampoo
Heart"
And that group was Setoyaki46.
(Seto Ceramic 46)
Setoyaki46
debut single
"Please, Round &
Round Shampoo
Heart"
Let's
take
over
the
nation
And then after that came Shigarakiyaki46, Kutaniyaki46, and Bizenyaki46.
The
good
ol'
Traditional
Idols
I realized my dreams of producing all of Japan's pottery idol groups!
But then, a rival appeared.
NyaaKB48
It was the famous idol group, NyaKB48!
They beat us and forced us to shut down.
And then my dream was shattered.
There was nothing left but despair.
No. Not yet.
Next time, I will absolutely create the best idol group ever!
I see.
So the reason you disappeared was because you became a Yo-kai.
Don't you think you took things too far?
Sorry.
So I've failed again.
I'm sorry.
If only I was able to do a little better.
There's no need to apologize.
That's right.
Kamamoto, you helped us so much back then.
Huh? You don't still hate me?
Well, it was regrettable that we were forced to shut down...
But we shined beautifully while it lasted.
We never told you before, but we're finally telling you now.
Thank you so much, Mr. Kamamoto!
So everything I've done wasn't for nothing after all?
Thank goodness.
I am so sorry for the trouble I caused.
I am now retiring from being a producer.
Excuse me...
May I have a word?
I've always wanted to be an idol.
But I lacked confidence and gave up.
But...
When I stood on that stage,
hearing the audience cheer me on gave me the confidence I needed!
Mr. Kamamoto, please.
Please be my producer!
What?
Got it! Just leave it to me.
I'll turn you into a shining star!
What do we do now that Ayame knows all about Yo-kai?
Let her be a member of the Yo-kai Detective Agency, of course.
I vote yes!
But dealing with Yo-kai can be dangerous as well.
In that case, I'll do all I can to protect...
C'mon!
Huh?
Just come have some fun with us!
Please stop it!
Ayame!
We've got to help her!
Just cut it out!
I've been studying karate, you know.
We're very sorry!
Incredible.
She's super strong!
She's a cutie with the perfect personality, and she's also strong!
She's a beauty of one in a 300,000 years!
How are you even calculating that?
Ayame Himeno, was it?
Hey, big guy, whatcha doing?
That's a secret.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Yo-kai Watch Movie News!
Yo-kai Watch The Movie: Forever Friends will open on December 14th!
This time, your theater ticket pre-order comes with this: My Yo-kai arc!
And my Yo-kai arc is a super rare and glitters like gold!
As you can expect from me!
It's a bonus that's only available in limited quantities!
(July 13, 2018)
Theater preorders for getting my arc open starting today!
Contact your theaters soon!
Hey, have you all heard?
At the beach recently,
cases of pale white hands trying to drown people are multiplying!
Huh?! What is that?!
They say multiple hands emerge from the ocean all at once!
That's so scary!
We need to head to that beach right now!
And of course, Ayame's coming along too!
You're trying do THAT aren't you?
N-N-N-Not at all!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
A Deadly Swim in the Ocean