Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Welcome.
Come... Welcome.
Let me dote on you...
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
People always want to know the future.
However...
Never carelessly approach those who can predict the future for certain.
They might only open the door to calamity for those around them.
Touma's Imprisonment
Oh.
What's everyone gathered here for?
Ah! Take a look, Akinori.
There's an incredible fortuneteller out there.
Fortuneteller?
Everything she sees within this mirror is true.
A fortuneteller unlike any other, whose predictions are 100% correct.
And her name is... Sendo Rei.
It's gotta be an exaggeration!
A fortuneteller unlike any other is still just a fortuneteller.
Nah... Sendo Rei is known as the perfect fortuneteller.
Hmm...
I... see it.
The dog you loved died last year.
Yes...
The sounds in your room at night have been from the spirit of your dog.
It's a Shiba Inu named "Shiba."
How did you even know its name?
Shiba loves you so much that it's watching over you even now.
Did you see that?
Awesome!
It smells really fishy.
Akinori, even though you believe in urban legends...
...you don't believe in fortunes?
It smells like they've scripted everything.
If it was a real miracle, I'll believe in it.
By the way, even without consulting a fortuneteller, I know the future where I protect Natsume will never change!
I never asked for that future.
Even I foresaw that coming.
Ah! Look!
Fortune
Sendo Rei
Sendo Rei's official website?
It says she's giving perfect fortune tellings at the central plaza!
It's true!
Hey, let's go get our fortunes read!
Ah... Sure.
Whatever!
And Keisuke, since when did you believe in prophecies and stuff?
You believe in fortunetelling?
Well...! It's irrelevant if I believe in fortunetelling!
It's just a form of... whatchamacallit... enterchangement!
Did you mean "entertainment?"
Whatever! Let's just go!
Wow...
She seems to be really popular...
Ah! Look, Natsume! She's the real Sendo Rei!
Well, it's her show. Of course it'll would be her.
The wait in line is three hundred minutes?!
Three hundred minutes is... five hours?!
Let's line up?
That'll take all day!
I know, right...
Seems kinda unreasonable. Let's go home?
Weren't you the one who wanted to come?
Hey, you.
Me?
You over there.
Please come forward.
Me?
Yes.
Let me tell you your fortune.
Sure is good for Touma...
Sure is nice...
Sure is nice...!
Umm... But why me?
"Why are you giving me my fortune?", you wanted to ask, right?
Touma Tsukinami.
Yeah...
She just predicted his name!
No way! He's got a name tag on him, right?
Of course not.
He's not wearing his gym uniform.
Well, let's have a look at everything about you.
Now I've seen it.
You live in an apartment on top of a small hill.
Yes.
You're often by yourself in your spacious house, right?
Your parents are both working.
She got that right?
Yeah. It's perfect.
For sure.
And I also see something in your eyes.
That's right.
You always feel lonely.
Your loneliness, anxieties, and the cause of all the calamities that have happened to you until now...
I saw it all.
Wha.... What is it?
Something that's clung to you...
(spirit)
A majin.
A majin!?
(spirit)
(Acala)
By majin, does she mean Fudou Myouou?
At this rate...
This majin will bring calamity to you.
(spirit)
However...
...there's no need to worry.
Touma...
I'll see you again.
This is bad! This is bad! This is bad!
She's more than just a perfect fortuneteller!
She's more of a super sexy perfect dangerous fortuneteller for sure!
What's that mean?
The point is, she's dangerous!
(spirit)
(Acala)
The majin that she's talking about must be Fudou Myouou!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
The guy Touma summons with the Fudou Raimei Ken?
That's right! Nobody would think that...
...a middle schooler would be connected to something like that!
Maybe...
...she's a spy for a secret organization, disguised as a fortuneteller!
We must investigate immediately.
A... A secret society?
Ah, by the way, Touma.
Rei whispered something into your ear, didn't she?
That's right!
What did she say?
"I'll guide you along the correct path. Come to my office tonight," she said.
She'll "guide" you?
Tonight?
What?! That's bad! That's so bad! In various meanings of the word!
Akinori, your face is red.
I feel like we should stop.
It seems like something dangerous.
We should have the Yo-kai Watches ready in case something happens.
That's right.
It's best if I don't go.
(spirit)
At this rate, this majin will bring calamity to you.
I'll guide you along the correct path.
Sendo Rei, just who are you?
SHADOWSIDE
I've been waiting for you.
You naughty child.
Just what were you hoping for?
W-What was I hoping for...?
Don't worry. There's no need to be anxious.
I already know.
You're wondering about it.
About what I said before.
Yes.
(Acala)
(spirit)
By "majin", you must be talking about Fudou Myouou, right?
Don't be so impatient!
I'll explain everything clearly to you
Huh?
You should take off your watch.
This?
No need to know the time when you're having fun.
A-Are you okay?
Y-Yeah. Must have been static electricity.
This... isn't an ordinary watch.
That's fine, Touma. Whatever you're comfortable with. Carry on.
That's the Yo-kai Watch Ogre.
Is it trying to protect Touma from me?
I can't take it off unless he does it himself.
If not, we won't be able to steal it away.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Nor the Fudou Raimei Ken that Touma Tsukinami possesses.
Say, Touma.
Yes?
I'm feeling a bit sweaty.
Why is she going out of her way to take a shower, even though I'm here?
What could it possibly mean?
Come to think if it, I've heard of something.
In Kyoto, serving a guest tea means that you want them to leave.
Well, taking a shower in this case must have another meaning.
Don't tell me, Rei the perfect fortuneteller...
Has she already foreseen everything I'm thinking of right now?
Does it mean she's seen it all?
Touma!
What is it?
It looks like I've forgotten to bring my towel, shampoo and bodywash.
Sorry, but can you get them for me?
She forgot to get everything she needs to take a shower?!
What does this mean?
Sorry about that. Just hand it over through the opening.
Ah - Yes.
Ah, and try not to get your watch wet!
You wouldn't want to ruin its finely tuned machinery.
Maybe you should take it off first.
It's fine.
Here you go.
Tsk!
Sorry for the wait.
Now then, Touma.
Let's play together.
Wouldn't taking off that watch make it easier to move your hand?
-I'm fine.
Oh, really?
Why don't you take that watch off so it's easier to control...
-I'm fine.
Why don't you take off that...
-I'm completely fine.
That Touma Tsukinami sure is stubborn.
In that case...
Let's get down to business.
Please take a good look.
Here! Take a look!
You couldn't stand being alone.
On that day!
Please
order out
OK?
This again?
We're home!
What's going on? What about work?
I couldn't care any less about it.
That's because today is...
It's your school entrance ceremony.
Dad! You both came?!
Of course!
Touma! Congratuations on your admission!
Here.
It's a present from your mom and dad.
Do you like it?
Father... Mother... Thank you.
Here. Try it on.
Yeah. Take off the other one first.
Uh-huh.
That's right. That's good.
That's right. There's now one more precious thing for me take care of.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Now take out your Fudou Raimei Ken.
Thanks a lot, Touma.
And now I see it.
I see your future.
It's going to be pretty tough for you now.
Yes.
Everything begins now.
Hello?
Um, Akinori?
What do you want at this time of the night?
I've got a bad feeling for some reason.
Touma isn't answering any of my texts.
Well, it is nighttime, after all.
I've been thinking.
Maybe Touma went to Sendo Rei's place anyway.
What?
Here it is.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
So this is the Fudou Raimei Ken.
(Acala)
Show yourself, Fudou Myouou!
No reaction, huh?
That's to be expected.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Even if one steals the Fudou Raimei Ken,
(Acala)
without forming a contract with Fudou Myouou within it,
one doesn't gain full possession of it.
Would you form a contract...
...with me?
Who are you?
You will not interfere.
What are you?
Are you Sendo Rei's ally?
There's no need for you to know.
How arrogant!
You think you can stop us here?!
No way!
Piglet. Your magic won't help you here.
I'll do it!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
So you've summoned a Yo-kai?
How interesting.
We did it!
Nice!
(Acala)
If Fudou Myouou won't come out,
then we'll make him come out.
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou. If you won't come out, then I'll tear out his neck.
So you won't come out, no matter what?
Then I'll kill him.
So you've finally shown yourself.
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou, lend me your power.
Why do you desire my power?
I don't simply want to take it.
I'm offering a trade.
If you lend me your power...
(Swordsman Spirits)
...I offer the chance to fight the other Kenbumajin.
If you defeat all other Kenbumajin,
you'll take the title of being the strongest.
(Yo-kai Holy Swords)
And I'll be able to take all of the Yoseiken for myself.
How about it? Still want to fight against me?
Very well.
I accept your offer.
Then it's decided.
(Colossal Inferno)
Together with Douketsu's Ashira Gouenmaru,
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Now we have our second Yoseiken, Fudou Raimei Ken.
Hey! What's wrong?! Face me!
We've finally got it.
Huh?
Tsk! He ran.
Let's go!
Right!
Now then.
You've served your purpose.
Poor dear...
I wanted to play with him just a bit more...
As have you, Sendo Rei.
You were just an ordinary fortuneteller before I gave you power.
You've had your fun in this fleeting dream, haven't you?
Goodbye, Miss Perfect Fortuneteller.
Where is this place?
Fukurou, get rid of Touma Tsukinami and his Ogre.
Yessir.
He's so heavy...
Well... Whatever.
Better luck in the next world.
You're...
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Trivia
Akinori's
SHADOWSIDE
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Today, we'll be talking about the Fudou Raimei Ken.
(Acala)
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Fudou Myouou resides in the Fudou Raimei Ken, which is used by Touma.
Fudou Raimei Ken
When put into the Yo-kai Watch Ogre,
it can adjust its energy wavelength,
(Acala)
then Fudou Myouou can be called into the human world via possession.
He can defeat any Yo-kai with his ultimate technique, Iron Hammer Thunder Slash!
Grrr! He's way too strong!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Fudou Raimei Ken
Touma had his Fudou Raimei Ken stolen!
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Serpent King Kaira tells us that to get back the Fudou Raimei Ken,
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
we'll need to get a new Youseiken.
It's a legendary sword that cuts all.
It's called the Suzaku Soutenzan.
Let's try to get it.
(The Mountain of Prayers)
Let's head to Inori no Yama in the Yo-kai World.
Wait, why am I coming along!?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
(The Mountain of Prayers)
The Strangeness of Inori no Yama