Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 18 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Now this is why summer is great.
Ooooh... this is awesome.
You've been doing that this whole time.
Don't you think you're staring at Ayame too much?
Whenever I stare at Ayame, I am choked with happiness and I feel like melting.
Your face looks like it will melt off, too.
This is patrol. Arresting that disgusting fatty. Over.
Quit it!
Natsume! Let's take a selfie together!
Sure!
I heard this place is popular at night, too.
That's right.
It's one of those trendy "night pools."
Yay!
Let's add the face filter.
It doesn't look that different.
Umm... let's try it again.
Alright! Now we look cuter!
The photo effects in this app are super cool!
That's great for social media!
Take a picture of me, too!
Yeah, sure!
Say cheese!
Super
Handsome
Mode!
Who is that dog?
It says, "Super Handsome Mode."
They've got something like that? Let me try!
Okay!
What's this?
Woah, we look awesome!
What is this?!
Hey! Don't break my pho...
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings\
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
There is a popular smartphone app that can make your face cute or handsome.
But tampering with one's face can lead to unexpected dangers.
What will become of your real face when you meddle with a photograph of it?
Face Thief
A princess with the power to control even the Yo-kai world.
(Youmakai)
If the sakura tree reacted, she shouldn't be far.
But we won't get any more definitive clues.
I don't think so.
When the sakura tree bloomed, someone happened to come to town.
Hmmm?
Take a look.
This is...
Ayame Himeno...
She transfered to the class next to us.
Don't tell me she's...
Please, go ahead!
Huh?
It's my grandma's special shaved ice!
Awesome!
Jii is gonna eat!
Brain freeze!
Hey Junior! Don't eat everything!
Anyone would want to taste it all. They all look delicious.
Of course!
There, Junior. Taste to your heart's content.
His attitude changed so fast.
He just wants to show Himeaya his compassionate side.
Ah, I just remembered something.
He dodged the issue.
There's a mystery that has gotten a lot of attention.
There's been a series of disappearances in Sakura Motomachi.
That's the news story that's always on.
The one about men going missing constantly, right?
Yeah.
It's mostly happening in the center of Sakura Motomachi.
But it's also happening in neighboring areas and Karuiyamachou as well.
Me and my family went there for vacation.
Ah, that's right!
Just when I got there, the news said those three people went missing.
I think it's really scary.
Zap! I will protect Ayame!
And I'll protect Natsume!
They synchronized.
Fatty and Muscles acting the same.
But that's all we know from the news.
He dodged the issue again.
There's a rumor that's been circulating on Usuranura.
A rumor?
They say that the person behind this has a grudge against handsome looking men.
Why would people believe that?
Take a look at this lineup of the disappearance victims.
Handsome.
Rough and handsome.
Handsome!
Who's handsome?
All the victims here are certainly handsome looking.
W-Well, they're all somewhat good looking, but I can't say that they're all that handsome.
Fatty's jealous. So shameful.
Ha, ha, ha. What a funny joke, Junior!
Just go away.
So scary!
Well, in my opinion, a Yo-kai must be behind all of this.
There's a Yo-kai that abducts good looking men one-by-one?
Who could it be?
I wonder...
Speaking from experience as a Yo-kai mystery expert...
-Yo-kai mystery expert?
It might be a Yo-kai that eats up handsome men reflected in its mirror.
Or perhaps...
...maybe it's ramen that did these men in.
A menacing, maniacal, man-hunting ramen Yo-kai that manhandles manly men!
S-Something like that can't exist, can it?
How many times did he say "man" just now?
Six times!
But what leads do we have to start investigating this case?
That's a good question.
The witnessess are all missing.
My friends got handsome and disappeared
See Comments(0) >
Submitter: Marii
Recently, I’ve downloaded this popular app.
Some male friends of mine used this app to take a photo of themselves and
edited it to make themselves look handsome.
But then, their actual faces became handsome too, and I have no idea how
that happened…
After a moment, an arm-like thing came out of the screen and sucked
their faces right off…
They literally had no faces…!
And then they disappeared right after that…
This isn’t a hoax. This is real. Someone...anyone... please believe me.
There's a new post.
For real?
Recently, I’ve downloaded this popular app.
Some male friends of mine used this app to take a photo of themselves and
edited it to make themselves look handsome.
But then, their actual faces became handsome too, and I have no idea how
that happened…
After a moment, an arm-like thing came out of the screen and sucked
their faces right off…
They literally had no faces…!
And then they disappeared right after that…
This isn’t a hoax. This is real. Someone...anyone... please believe me.
This is...
There's someone who witnessed the disappearance of a victim?
Are you sure this isn't a mistake?
Let's hear them out for now.
It'd be nice if they knew something.
Uh-huh.
Or what if maybe we're getting pranked?
You sound too scared to be doubtful.
I wrote that post because no one would believe me.
We believe you.
Please tell us everything.
We were all fooling around together...
We took a picture with an app that got popular recently.
When we took a selfie and tried editing our faces with it...
Super
Handsome
Mode
Woah!
It says "Super Handsome Mode."
Wow. For real?
Let's try it!
For sure!
Well, the two of them looked handsome in the app, but...
Wow! Awesome!
Handsome! Right?
What's wrong?
It wasn't just in the picture, but their faces were changed for real as well.
I didn't understand what was happening at all.
Then, in the very next moment...
They look so delicious now!
They lost their faces, and then they disappeared!
No way! No way! Something like that absolutely can't ever happen!
What happened to them?
When that happened, what app were you using?
That one...
Instant beautification
for men and women
Camera & image editing app
Pretty
Handsome
Instant beautification
for men and women
Camera & image editing app
Pretty
Handsome
Instant beautification
for men and women
Instant beautification for men and women.
Instant beautification
for men and women
Camera & image editing app
Camera & image editing app: Pretty Handsome.
Pretty
Handsome
Camera & image editing app
Pretty
Handsome
Camera & image editing app
Pretty
Handsome
Camera & image editing app
Pretty
Handsome
Wasn't that featured on TV and in magazines recently?
There are kids in my class using that as well.
There's a big event for it nearby.
Then let's go to that event.
We might learn something there.
Pretty Handsome Fest
Let's use Pretty Handsome!
Pretty
Handsome
Looks like a place where they usually have events.
They've got ads everywhere.
"Pretty Handsome" sure is an impressive brand.
Their downloads have multiplied recently.
We need to solve this case soon.
And before there's any more victims.
What is with this app?
Who knows?
It must be some kind of possessed, cursed app.
Well, I've already downloaded it as well.
What? Why? Isn't that dangerous?
Akinori, don't tell me...
...Did you want to look handsome?
No, no! That's not it at all!
I-It was all so I could investigate this case!
Was it really?
Was your real motive to show off how handsome you can look to Himeaya?
That's not it at all!
Using this is dangerous, after all.
Of course...
He seems disappointed.
He wanted to do that after all.
He just can't have what he wants.
Allow me!
Please have a look, Natsume!
Such apathy!
Yo-kai can use this just like ordinary people.
How boring.
Muscles is ordinary and boring!
Now allow me.
Jii looks wild!
It'd be nice if we could find a clue here.
Pretty Girl's
Corner
"Pretty Girl's Corner," it says.
Now
Print
-ing!
This is a nice event, actually.
Agreed.
Done!
Umm... what about the investigation?
Splendid!
Natsume!
Ayame!
Don't shout like that. It's embarassing.
I knew it.
Handsome Boy's
Tryout Corner
Huh? Here!
Handsome Boy's Corner!
Handsome Boy's
Tryout Corner
There must be a clue here!
SHADOWSIDE
The camera & image editing app, Pretty Handsome, is also popular among men.
Today, I'll let you in on the secret to looking handsome.
We should take notes.
Yeah.
He didn't even say anything yet.
Let's do this, everyone!
First, take a picture.
Is this okay?
Then, tap the image.
Then, let's tap the "Super Handsome Mode" button.
Super
Handsome
Mode!
Super
Handsome
Mode!
Super
Handsome
Mode!
Super
Handsome
Mode!
Handsome!
You turned handsome for real!
What?
They all got handsome for real!
I'm so jealous!
You've all got some delicious looking faces now, don't you?
I'll eat all of your faces!
So tasty! So delicious!
We won't let him do as he pleases!
Me, too!
We did it!
Serves you right!
Even the way Ayame and I use our special attacks is exactly the same!
That's right!
What do you think, Ayame?
As fellow magic users, let's make a study group with just the two of...
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
Ah! Incredible!
Y-Yeah. Sure.
By the way, why don't the two of us...
-Come on out, my friend! Komasan!
Quit cutting in!
Very well!
Gimme everything you've got!
Jibanyan!
This is bad!
Huh?! His face is still on!
Perhaps...
He can't steal any faces that aren't handsome?
Good thing, Jibanyan!
That's no good at all!
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
Falling Dog Rock!
We did it!
Incredible!
Damn...
I'm out of strength...
Handsome faces...
I need to eat handsome faces!
There's one!
I'll feast on your face!
Akinori!
How'd it come to this?
At this rate, my face is going to get eaten off!
Disgusting!
Huh?
Akinori's face is still on?
Everything's still normal.
What?
In other words...
I-Isn't that fortunate?
That's no good at all!
Unforgiveable!
(Mythical Beast)
Descend! Genjuu Suzaku!
Suzaku has arrived!
Alright, now that I've become thin and handsome from summoning you...
Show them what you've got, Suzaku!
He summoned Suzaku just to get thin, didn't he?
Probably.
Take this!
Is that the Yo-kai's light side?
I'm Shibumenken.
Hey, Shibumenken.
Why did you do all those terrible things?
When I was younger, I wasn't Shibumenken.
(Dandoodle)
I was Ikemenken.
Wonderful!
But the passage of time isn't something you can stop.
Before I realized it, I aged over the years and became Shibumenken.
I became jealous of those who are younger.
And before I knew it, I started attacking young, handsome men.
(Man/Face Eater)
And I transformed into the Yo-kai Menkuiita.
With my power, I created an app to be my feeding ground.
What an awful old dog I am.
No, actually...
You can use your powers to create an app.
There were even ads for it.
Couldn't you have done anything else with that kind of power?
But Shibumenken, I think even an austere looking face is still splendid.
Heh, little girl.
Huh?
You shouldn't flirt with adults.
He looks incredibly happy, though...
I think you've still got some youth in you for sure.
You're so cool, too!
What?!
The nightlife is calling for me!
Ha ha!
Looks like he's cheered up!
What a straightforward guy.
Ayame Himeno.
There's no doubt.
Aaah!
Nightlife is the best!
Such high spirits for a stern-faced gentleman.
What? Did you fall for me as well?
What is this? Stop it!
Hold it right there.
You're from the class next door...
There is no need for you to keep up this act with me.
I've finally found you, my princess.
Huh?!
Wait, I'm not a real princess. I'm just Himeno.
Feel free to do as you please.
I am already at your disposal.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is going to be about the Genma.
Genma are Yo-kai that are summoned via possession with the Yo-kai Watch Ogre.
Genma
They're high-class Yo-kai.
They're chosen based on the dial's position...
12 o'clock is for Goemon, 3 o'clock for Omatsu,
6 o'clock for Yoshitsune, and 9 o'clock for Benkei.
Touma can choose which of these four to summon for possession.
And while Touma is possessed, he's still conscious.
How does it feel to be possessed by Omatsu?
Genma
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
Be careful while you're hunting cicadas this time of year.
Why? All I'm doing is catching bugs with my friends.
The number of people going missing while cicada hunting have multiplied!
They say they were kidnapped by a cicada monster!
Cicada monster?
Yeah. Especially since cicadas often pretend to be dead, only for them to suddenly start rampaging!
Be especially cautious of that!
That seems kind of scary...
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Cicadas’ Semifinal Counterattack