Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 5:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
My name is Jinta.
I'm a anatomical model living at a school
I've been at this school for 50 years already.
Many students think that I'm creepy or scary.
But even for someone like me,
Springtime has finally come!
Her name is Ma -
Ahh...
I get the creeps when I see this anatomical model.
Really? I think he's pretty cute.
Seriously?
Manami, you're pretty weird.
Really?
Oh no, that's definitely weird.
You're weird.
-That's right, her name is Manami Yashina.
She's the girl I've fallen in love with.
She said that I was cute.
After school, wanna go to Ikkokuya for some meat buns?
Sounds great!
The meat buns there are delicious.
They're not just delicious, they're delectable!
Why am I not considered human?
I'm only a little different from humans.
So what if my organs are showing?
And half of my body is missing skin...
...And you can see my brains...
Well...
...those are just trivial things.
I will have that girl for myself.
I'm sure of it.
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
A soul is said to reside within things and places with a long history.
When deep passions take hold, terrible disturbances will happen.
How terrifying!
An Anatomical Model in Love
It's done!
Let's see...
You got it.
I knew you would be able to solve this problem.
I studied ahead a little for class today.
Is that so?
Did you hear that?
Everyone, be sure to study before class just like Manami!
Okay!
It's over!
You're celebrating too hard, Keisuke.
That will be all for today.
Hey, Keisuke.
You looked so bored, you had the eyes of a dead fish.
D-Don't be ridiculous, Tank...
My eyesight is as good as Mie Makuro, the Super Eyesight Detective!
You sure talk a lot for someone who doesn't listen!
But anyway, Manami sure is studious.
That's what I call people on the other side.
"The other side"?
There's a huge invisible wall between us and people like Manami.
You can say that again.
'ello!
Yo, Keisuke!
You're here again!
Well, I was getting bored at home.
Ah, that's right!
I was going to ask you something, Keisuke.
This article involves Sakura Motomachi First Elementary school.
That's your school, right?
"I feel like I'm being watched by someone."
Ah...
So it's one of those stories about strange eyes peeking out from the broom closet?
There are a lot of urban legends at school, aren't there?
That's right...
Another possibility is...
...It might be a huge spider with just a face and huge eyeballs...
S...Spider?
That's certainly creepy.
Or it could be some suspicious person trespassing into the school.
I see!
That's not something we can overlook.
We need to get to the bottom of this.
In that case...
I'll lend you my Yo-kai Watch so you can do some investigating.
What?
No way! This has got nothing to do with me!
What are you talking about? It's your school!
"Investigating," she says...
What am I supposed to do?
Keisuke!
What's wrong, Tank?
It's about Kouji...!
He got Manami angry!
Huh?
Science Prep Room
Sorry, Manami!
I just heard that you like anatomical models...
I love you!
Go
out
with
me!
What? I do...
...but why did you draw graffiti all over it?
I love you!
Go
out
with
me!
Well... It's not just graffiti, it's a confession of love!
It looks less like a confession and more like a tasteless prank!
You're treating Mr. Anatomical Model really badly!
That's why I hate you right now, Kouji!
"Mr. Anatomical Model"...?
Kouji, we'll tell it to you straight.
Your youth is over!
Don't feel so down.
You know....
...it was you who told me that a confession needed to have impact!
Was that so?
It's all good!
Let's treat you to ice cream at Penguin's!
Oh dear.
I wonder if this grafitti can be erased...
But Manami's face when she got angry for me...
...that was cute!
Huh...? But wait... Was she... from before...?
Was I just imagining it?
Is that so?
Manami.... really hates Kouji...
Kouji... wrote graffiti on me...
Unforgivable...
...I'll kill him.
Kouji,
I'll wait for
you by the
emergency
exit.
"Kouji, I'll wait for you by the emergency exit."
Who is this letter from?
Kouji!
Huh?
T-Th... That was close!
Is that wax?
Kouji!
Watch out!
That was close!
Thank you... Tank...
Tsk...
Hey, Keisuke!
What's up?
It looks like someone's after my life!
Huh? What do you mean?
Here's how it started...
I see...
I hate to admit it, but...
Looks this is the work of a Yo-kai...
What's this the work of?
I said that it's definitely...
...possible that the act of a Yo-kai can't be conclusively ruled out.
We can't hear what you're saying!
Keisuke!
Natsume...
Did you find out anything about the mystery stalker?
Well... about that...
I didn't think it'd be that dangerous.
We need to find the real culprit.
Alright.
Let's try to solve this with a possession summon.
Possession!
Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
Yoshitsune has arrived.
Mr. Yoshitsune, what are you doing?
I'm searching for Yo-kai energy.
Whenever a Yo-kai appears, it always leaves behind a trace.
If we follow it, we will find our answer.
It's here.
This room is filled with the Yo-kai energy we've been following.
So this is were the fight begins.
I'll be reaching my time limit momentarily.
I'll give you a final hint.
Damn, I missed my target.
These fifty years have messed up my joints.
What's this...?
I hear residual thoughts from the past from this place.
Perhaps the culprit said this.
Awesome!
Fifty years?
It's time.
Welcome back!
I'm back.
Was that good enough?
Let's hurry in, then!
What?
If you're scared, just stay behind.
Where's the Yo-kai?
This is...
Natsume?
There's dirt on his feet.
And there's wax on his hands.
Keisuke,
do you remember when your school was built?
I think it was about fifty years ago...
And these fifty years have messed up his joints.
I think I know who the culprit is.
Really?
The Yo-kai that's been troubling this school is... you, isn't it?
What?
The anatomical model?
That's impossible no matter how you...
You found me out.
It's him!
Is... Is there seriously an anatomical model Yo-kai?
Well... To be precise,
I am a Yo-kai type human anatomical model.
Ah, it fell off again.
Yo-kai type?
I fundamentally am a human anatomical model, but...
...it seems like I have emotions.
Sometimes I feel down. Sometimes I get sad. And sometimes I cry.
They're all negative emotions!
Anyways!
You've been putting my friend in danger, haven't you?
Why?
That's because Kouji is... a rival for my love.
Wait, that means you like Manami too?
Even though you're just a model?
You think it can't happen?
Since when was it decided that a dummy can't love a human?
That's just...
Ah...
What?
Huh? What?
Again...?
Are you okay?
Kouji...!
KOUJI!
What?
Kouji!
What are you?!
I'll kill you!
Stop it!
Don't you dare lay a hand on him!
Don't get between personal affairs!
Keisuke!
Summon a Yo-kai friend for help!
Alright.
Summoning!
Shadow!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Come on out my friend, Boureibanchou!
Stop him, Boureibanchou!
Die!
(Ghost Gang Leader)
Boureibanchou!
Leave this to me.
Possession!
(Sword Warrior Demon)
Kenbumashin!
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou!
(Immovable)
Fudou!
Lend me your strength!
(Immovable Thunder)
Lightning! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Sword!
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou has arrived.
I-Incredible...
We'll win this time!
If we forced him to summon Fudou Myouou,
Fukurou's failure was useful to us after all.
(Immovable Thunder)
The Fudou Raimei Sword....
...is being wielded by Touma Tsukinami.
Using weapons is cowardice!
How absurd.
Since you've taken that monstrous form,
it would be obvious to fight you with a suitable weapon.
What?
What happened?
Thunder Hammer Slash!
Stop it!
Manami... You can see me?
At first, I thought I could see you moving just a little.
But the more I looked at you, the more I felt that you were alive.
But no matter how cute you were,
you were still an anatomic model that's not supposed to move.
That's what I tried to tell myself.
Manami, it's okay.
If I do this...
-But...!
The way that you rage in this form...
...That...
...That isn't cute at all!
I'm... not cute at all...?
I see...
Have I gotten Manami to hate me completely?
I can't do anything right...
(Anatomical Model)
Jintai Moukei...
Umm... If it's okay, I've got something to ask of you.
Please use your powers to smash me to pieces.
No way!
Please don't worry about me.
An anatomical model with a soul would just creep people out.
It would be better if I didn't exist at all.
That's...
That's my final request.
Ah...
There's one more thing...
May I settle my affairs before I go?
Manami...
I'm... not human... and there are many differences between us...
But I.... I love you.
I love the way you smile.
I love the way you walk.
I love the way you trip and fall.
I love... I love all of you!
Even if I'll be smashed to pieces soon,
these feelings can never be crushed.
So cool...!
Now this is a confession with impact!
I'm sorry.
I can't return those feelings.
His heart shattered!
What a heartbreaking unrequited love.
Of...of course...!
I'm so creepy and disgusting...
And of course, I'm not even human.
I knew that all along, though...
It's because...
...your partner isn't me, after all.
Is this...
...me...?
This is something my grandma treasured.
Grandma?
You're Jin, aren't you?
You're Jin, the anatomical model.
Huh?
My grandma told me.
She said that she got to speak with an anatomical model at school a long time ago.
And his name was... Jin!
Don't tell me you're...
So that's it...I just remembered...!
The other person that I fell in love with...
Machiko!
I got scolded by the teacher again.
Should someone like me really be in the class committee?
What do you think?
Anyway... sorry for always chatting.
I just love being able to talk with you.
Aah, if only you were a human.
I know! I could give you a name.
Umm....
(anatomical model)
Ah! Since you're a Jintai Moukei, I'll call you Jin!
How's that, Jin?
That's right.
Machiko always saw eye to eye with me.
She even wished that I was human!
That's right, at the time...
That hurts! Let go!
You did it, didn't you?
You're the one who stole his stomach!
What?
It's not like I stole it!
I forgot my paperweight during penmanship class.
I was just using it as a substitute!
Return it right now!
Jin needs to have his stomach!
J-Jin?
Whatever, just return it!
Right...
I thought I saw Manami's angry face somewhere.
That was Machiko's face after all!
Machiko was always looking out for me.
How could I forget such an important person?
Even though the time I spent with Machiko... was always so much fun.
Grandma gave me this doll when she passed away.
It's a charm she made by hand.
So Machiko is no longer...
When she was talking about you, she said this at the end:
She wanted to meet you one more time.
M...Machiko...
I... I...
I want to meet... I want to meet you too...!
There he goes...
...wait, where is he going?
He finally realized true love, in a sense.
So it took fifty years to realize true love, huh?
It's kind of wonderful!
Someone who will realize your true feelings...
...will surely appear before you some day!
That's a line that appeared in a drama before, right?
Whatever, it's still nice!
Ah...
Who's this?
I've finally realized there's something people have that I didn't.
And that's... BOOM! Fancy clothes!
Wear some in the front too!
No no no!
This is the anatomical model's signature style!
Like I care!
Go home!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Hey, have you guys heard?
It's the freshest urban legend now!
Laughing Dog Man!
Dog Man?
(Man-faced Dog)
I know about Jinmenken, though.
Dog Man is a monster with a man's body and a dog's face.
It attacks you with these sharp claws!
Hey...
I think I know where you might find Dog Man.
There's a surprising reason why Dog Man's attacks were hidden!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Laughing Dog Man