Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 24 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Just
DO IT
House
Haunted
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
That's weird.
Where did big brother and the rest go?
W-What are you?
[Merry-go-round music]
-Huh?
-I've been waiting... Poncho. Hana Poncho.
-Huh? What?
I've been waiting... Poncho. Hana Poncho.
Thanks.
[Laughter]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Cute characters in amusement parks are popular with children.
They're always smiling and having fun.
But behind those cheerful smiles lurk thoughts that nobody knows about.
The Dreaming Hana Poncho
What is that?
This?
It's a Furafura keychain.
What's Furafura?
It's a mascot character from Hana Land.
Kouji gave it to me as a present.
What's Hana Land?
It's an amusement park called Hana Hana Family Land.
People call it Hana Land for short.
We went there once, right?
It's been a while since we went.
Is that so, Natsume?
How about going on a date with me to Hana Land?
Eh. Absolutely never.
No, it looks like we'll be going there after all.
Huh? Why?
There's a post about it on Usuranura.
Huh?
See Comments(2) >
Submitter: YUTO
Younger brother got lost in Hana Land...
My family and I visited Hana Hana Family Land.
After looking away for just a moment, my younger brother went missing.
I couldn’t find him at all, even after searching until evening.
But I finally found him in front of the merry-go-round.
However, he’s been acting strangely.
Something must have happened while he was gone.
My younger brother got lost in Hana Land?
It's not too unusual for kids to get lost in an amusment park, right?
Then why did he post it on the site?
See Comments(2)
Submitter: YUTO
Younger brother got lost in Hana Land...
Me and my family visited Hana Hana Family Land.
After looking away for just a moment, my younger brother went missing.
I couldn’t find him at all even after searching until evening.
But I finally found him in front of the merry-go-round.
However, he’s been acting strangely.
Something must have happened while he was gone.
Let's go ask him for more details.
Are you Yuto? The person who posted about Hana Land on Usuranura?
Yeah.
Can you tell us more about your younger brother?
One day, my family and I went to Hana Land.
My brother went missing after I turned away for a bit.
Family Land
It got dark while we were trying to look for him.
What will we do if we don't find him?
Big brother!
Ikuo! You idiot! Where'd you run off to?
You had us worried!
Ikuo, what are you doing?
Eh-heh! I played with Hana Poncho!
Hana Poncho?
Yeah! It was really fun!
[Laughter]
Oh!
Hey, Hana Poncho!
Whatcha doing? Wanna play?
[Laughter]
Ikuo!
Ever since that day, Ikuo hasn't been the same.
He's always been a little cheeky and bickers with me often.
But now, he acts just like a baby!
Do you know who Hana Poncho is from your little brother?
I heard that it appeared momentarily ten years ago.
I don't remember anything else about it.
Do you know anything?
No. Not at all.
Hana Poncho? Hana Poncho...
Natsume, do you know anything?
I feel like I might have heard of something like that before.
Hmph!
I've found it!
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy-cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
So this is Hana Poncho!
Ugh.
So this is it.
It's really unbearable to look at.
Where did its right eye go, I wonder?
"Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land."
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
"This peculiar character had children in tears one after another."
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy-cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
"Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen."
Retired in just 2 hours!!
Creepy Cutie Comes & Goes
Hana Poncho, as it first appeared in Hana Hana Family Land.
This peculiar character had children in tears one after another!
Within two hours, it was nowhere to be seen.
But as far as fleeting creepy cute things are concerned,
it’s become a legend among enthusiasts.
"But as far as fleeting creepy-cute things are concerned..."
"...it’s become a legend among enthusiasts."
There's no question this thing is related to the case.
It's related, you say?
In what way?
Well, for example.
What if it eats kids in order to live forever?
Or perhaps Hana Poncho is actually an alien life form.
Maybe they capture humans to bring back to their home planet.
[Whimpering]
There's several more posts about children getting lost...
...and behaving like babies afterwards.
Alright.
Let's go to Hana Land tomorrow!
Family Land
It's been a while!
Same here.
Ah! Look over there!
So that's Furafura!
She looks really popular.
Ah!
There's Furafura merch everywhere!
There's nothing with Hana Poncho on it.
Let's go look for anyone who knows about Hana Poncho.
Uh-huh.
Hana Poncho?
Ah. So this is about a post on the Internet.
Yes.
These strange rumors are troublesome for us.
Hana Poncho disappeared a long time ago.
I don't know who writes these posts,
but they've caused a lot of trouble for us. Geez.
What do we do now?
They keep telling us that Hana Poncho is gone.
All the kids that got lost played with Hana Poncho, they say.
Papa!
Huh?
Did you find him?
No.
Just where is he?
Let's check the lost children area.
They lost their kid?
Mei!
Where are you?
What do I do?
What's wrong?
My younger sister went missing.
Hey!
Where are you?
Is everyone missing their children?
That's terrible!
Did Hana Poncho do this?
Let's split up and find them.
Uh-huh.
Just
DO IT
House
Haunted
[Panting]
Huh? There's no one here.
It's...
It's here!
[Merry-go-round music]
I've been waiting... Poncho. Hana Poncho.
I-I don't want it!
I told you, I don't want it!
I said, I don't want it!
I've been waiting... Poncho.
Oh, no!
[Keisuke whimpering]
Keisuke!
[Laughter]
No!
SHADOWSIDE
[Children's voices]
[Babbling]
Where is this?
[Keisuke babbling]
-Keisuke!
Keisuke! Are you okay?
Natsume! Look! It's an airplane! Vroom!
I see.
This is what they meant by acting like babies.
So just where is this place?
Po, po, po! Hana Poncho!
Let's play like everyone else! Poncho!
But before that...
...You'll be a kid, too!
[Natsume screaming]
From one morning until the next,
I am the knight who watches over Natsume!
Micchi has arrived!
And going with the flow, I make an appearance, too!
Jii goes ta-dah, too!
Guys!
Deal with Hana Poncho and bring us back to our world!
Leave it to us!
Let's beat 'em up fair and square, three versus one!
You can't go home yet!
[Babbling]
P-P-P-Poncho!
[Giggling]
[Shrieking]
[Gasps]
I'll protect Natsume!
And I'll have Whisper protect me!
Hey! Wait! Quit fooling around!
Unhand me, you meathead!
Muscles is a dork. What a noob.
Jii got mixed in too?!
Hmm. It's pretty rare for all three of them to get sent flying.
Alright, in that case...
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out, my friend! Jinta!
You rang?
Jinta, please!
Do something about that mannequin Yo-kai!
Huh?
W-Whoa! T-That mannequin's talking and moving!
Umm... So are you.
It's scary, but I'll do it!
It's a monster!
-I'm scared!
I'll crush it all!
Quit moving around!
Hey, Jingeki!
There's kids around! Quit smashing everything up!
Shut up! Quit telling me what to do!
What?
Everyone!
Gather around!
Drop dead!
Hana's room is...
Nooo!
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch!
Hana's room...
Stop it!
We're gonna get hurt, too!
In that case...
Light!
Huh? What was I doing?
Huh? Natsume?
Keisuke! You're back to normal!
Where are we?
What was I doing?
[Weeping]
Who are you?
Oh, good!
We're back!
Natsume! Keisuke!
Are you OK?
Yeah.
What happened?
I don't really remember.
But it felt really fun.
You were playing in Hana Poncho's room.
W-What's that?
Is that so?
That's what Hana Poncho's room was like?
Geez, Jinta! You went crazy!
Whenever I'm Jingeki, I just feel like wrecking things like a raging giant.
Sorry about that.
No need. It was my fault from the beginning.
Hey. As fellow mannequin Yo-kai, maybe we should talk it over.
Before I became a Yo-kai, I was just a normal doll named Hana.
Back then, I was happy to be surrounded by children.
But then time passed.
Hana
Important
Cultural
Asset
I was sealed shut behind glass like a work of art.
I became something people stared at to satisfy their curiosity.
Hana
Important
Cultural
Asset
I couldn't stand being away from the children who I love. That's when my spirit split from my body.
Hana
Important
Cultural
Asset
While wandering around, I was lead by the voices of children.
Family Land
Then I found myself at Hana Hana Family Land.
I thought that I would be able to play with kids if I stayed here.
New Friend
Coming Tomorrow
PONCHO
HANA
Opening
Tomorrow
And then I learned that a new character was debuting the very next day.
New Friend
PONCHO
HANA
I thought that it must have been fate.
EMPLOYEES ONLY
NO TRESPASSING
I decided to debut as the new character by borrowing Hana Poncho's body.
HANA PONCHO
New Friend
But then...
Sorry for keeping you waiting!
I present to you Hana Hana Family Land's newest mascot character, Hana Poncho!
[Applause]
I've been waiting. Poncho. Hana Poncho.
Ew!
It's scary!
Stay back! Disgusting!
[Screaming]
Hey, kids! Come to Hana Land to shake hands with Poncho!
Hey! We're taking Hana Poncho back! Hurry!
A-Alright!
See you again, Hana Poncho!
And that was how after only 2 hours, Hana Poncho was retired.
All I wanted to do was play with kids, just like I used to long ago.
I am so sorry for troubling you.
I won't cause you any more problems.
I've decided to hide myself from children forever.
Hana...
I'm heading back to the warehouse.
Goodbye.
Umm...
I think I've seen it here somewhere.
Maybe we threw it away?
Huh?
I found it! It's here!
Family Land
Aaah! It's a Hana Poncho doll!
After retiring me within 2 hours, they also stopped selling my merch on the same day. It's a good thing you have this!
Apparently, I loved it so much, my dad bought it for me.
Is that so?
I'm so happy!
Hey, Hana.
Can you show everyone Hana Poncho one more time for us?
Huh?
T-That won't work.
It'll be fine.
It's said that Hana Poncho is a creepy cutie who got put away too soon.
Now that times have changed, maybe they'll accept you.
S-So that's why.
By the way, we've got a great idea.
We call it, "Catching Up With the Times: Hana Poncho's Comeback Campaign!"
Leave it to us!
Whis!
Jii can do it!
YO-KAI
HOUSE
Huh? Was this always here?
Did they just put it up?
YO-KAI
HOUSE
I wanna go in!
Alright.
Yay!
Alright!
Hana Poncho's Popular Comeback Campaign Part One:
Guerrilla Yo-kai Haunted House! Now open!
[Screaming]
Hey.
Play with me!
Stop right there, evildoers! Poncho!
Huh?
W-Who is that?
Leave it to me! Poncho. Hana Poncho!
Augh!
It got me!
For peace and safety! Hana Poncho!
I'm getting nervous!
It's scary.
It's not just scary! Poncho!
Just like my face, it's also fun! Poncho!
Huh? What?
Campaign Part Two: Poncho flying in the sky!
Here you go!
Welcome!
How about a special Hana Poncho rice bowl?
There's also ramen with special Poncho toppings!
Bon Appétit! Poncho!
Campaign Part Three!
Kitchen Hana Poncho!
Looks like everyone's having fun.
Thank you! Poncho! It's all thanks to Natsume and friends! Poncho!
Nah.
You've always had appeal, Hana Poncho!
See?
Everyone's smiling just like you are!
Have faith in yourself!
Poncho!
Hey! Look at this!
It's about Hana Poncho's comeback!
Let's see!
It's real!
Hana Poncho is Back!
Former Creepy Cutie Now a Hit with the Kids
Looks like Hana Land's staff listened to the people who want Hana Poncho back.
Isn't that great, Hana?
Hana Poncho!
I love you!
I'll be back!
I'll be waiting. Poncho. Hana Poncho.
Princess, I think you should stop fraternizing with humans.
Sure.
Ah. I sure am hungry.
Please, have some food.
Here's some Hana Poncho ramen.
What is this?
This is Hana Poncho ramen.
You know that this isn't what I wanted, don't you?
My apologies! Do you dislike the toppings?
That's not it.
Of course! It's because it's missing soft-boiled egg, isn't it?
I must keep it together.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Whisper!
Even though he calls himself a competant Yo-kai butler,
Whisper
he doesn't do anything worthy of being called a butler.
He's in charge of keeping the arks in the Yo-kai Detective Agency.
And also...
He likes dad jokes...
His voice is annoying...
He's got no fighting ability...
Huh? There's nothing good about him at all!
Whisper
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
I heard that something terrible happened to Micchi!
Huh? What happened?
A Yo-kai who has a grudge against Micchi is lurking in town!
Huh. Is that so.
Natsume! Now is no time to relax!
That Yo-kai's target isn't Micchi,
It's someone Micchi cares about most! It's you, Natsume!
Huh?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Farewell Micchi
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs