Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 31 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Previously, on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside...
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
You hag! You're not the princess!
[Laughter]
Ah.
I am now one with my beloved's soul.
[Screaming]
A-Ayame?
I've finally regained my true powers.
Jorougumo might have bitten her soul when she separated from her body.
Grandma, can you tell us how we can save Ayame?
You must defeat Jorougumo and bring back Ayame's soul.
There is only one Youseiken that can cut Jorougumo's webs.
(Axe of Law)
You must find the Genbu Houtenfu.
Heed my words.
(Treasure Sword Palace)
The Genbu Houtenfu is in the Yo-kai World's Houkenden.
Obtain it at all costs.
Why are you telling us this?
Aren't you trying to get the Youseiken for yourselves, too?
I only wish to protect my master.
You know what to do.
Let's go to Houkenden.
Uh-huh.
Ayame.
We'll save you, no matter what.
Is this the right place?
This is some thick fog.
Houkenden is straight ahead here in the Yo-kai World.
Houkenden.
The Genbu Houtenfu is there.
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
A Fierce Duel! Suzaku vs. Genbu
That gag never gets old.
Let's go.
Uh-huh.
There should be a lake up ahead.
Houkenden is on a floating island in the middle of the lake.
(Yo-kai Holy Swords)
Genbu Houtenfu is one of the Youseiken, right?
Yes.
(Immovable Thunder Sword)
Fudou Raimei Ken.
Asura Gouenmaru.
(Azure Heavenly Slayer)
And after the Suzaku Soutenzan,
there is a fourth Youseiken.
(Genbu Axe of Law)
Genbu Houtenfu.
To cut Jorougumo's webs, we must obtain the Genbu Houtenfu, which is said to split apart oceans.
We must get our hands on it.
I just realized something.
Why was Mr.Shimanouchi...I mean, Douketsu...protecting Sakami?
Who are those two?
Huh?
Here.
It's the lake.
I can't see the opposite shore though.
Houkenden is right up ahead.
But without a bridge, how are we supposed to get across?
If only there was a boat.
Hey, Natsume, you're good at swimming, right?
Why not take a quick dip and come back?
Well, even if she did...
Don't be silly.
Huh?
Somebody stop him.
Hmm?
Akinori?
Are you seriously swimming?
We must hurry.
Wait, for real?
You don't know how deep it is. It's too dangerous.
Akinori!
We don't have time!
While we're here, Ayame is...
[Granny Mitsue and Komajiro chanting]
Frogs are stronger than spiders!
My prayers can hold back curses too, ribbit!
Please hurry, Akinori!
Huh?
Hmm?
Something's approaching.
Who are you two?
(Swordsman Spirit)
They appear to be subordinates of Kenbumajin Genbu.
What is your reason for going to Houkenden?
[Keisuke shrieking]
That was sudden.
We want to save our friend.
We need to go to Genbu Houtenfu to do it.
It's a boat.
It wasn't there before.
Very well.
If you desire the Genbu Houtenfu, then come and take it.
But you shall be silent while aboard this vessel. Or else.
What happens if we don't stay quiet?
Genbu intends to test us before we make it ashore.
Let's go.
[Keisuke gasps]
[Keisuke screaming]
Huh?
You've broken the silence.
[Keisuke whimpering]
[Snakes growling]
That's it.
[Keisuke whimpering]
I'm the gorgeous and macho guy! Micchi has arrived!
I'm the black and white Yo-kai butler! Whisper has arrived!
I'm the super great Junior!
Have no fear, for we are here!
You may be in troubled waters, but have no fear, Natsume!
-Shhh! Shhhh!!
Hng!
Wait a sec, whis!
Natsume!
[Muffled speech]
Hmm?
Ahh. We're safe.
Thank y -
We're off the boat already. It's okay to talk.
Ah, of course.
Thank goodness.
Thank you, Akinori.
It's nothing.
Looks like we're here.
Hmm?
That's...
Genbu Houtenfu is here in Houkenden.
I'll go scout ahead.
Huh?
I see. It seems like this is an illusion.
Illusion?
But it looks so real.
Where's the real one?
Let me explain!
Hero Landing!
Natsume, I have returned with some great news.
The Houkenden that you see here is...
An illusion!
-It's an illusion, right?
As expected of Natsume.
You've probably already figured out where the real Houkenden is as well.
No. We haven't figured that part out yet.
Ha, ha, ha! Then leave it to me!
You know where it is?
Of course!
The real one is over there!
Of course. The real Houkenden is under the lake.
For real?
For real.
We found it while we were underwater.
Now let's go to the real Houkenden!
C'mon!
Huh?
Yes. Let's go.
Uh-huh.
Wha?
I'll be going.
If you're scared, you can just stay behind.
Huh? No way. I'm not doing that.
I was kidding. C'mon, let's go.
Uh-huh.
SHADOWSIDE
Huh? There's air in here.
The air seems breathable here.
It's beautiful.
Let's hurry and find the Genbu Houtenfu.
But where should we start?
Good question. Looks like we can climb down over there.
We'll go look elsewhere.
Micchi, go search outside.
But I should be by your side, Natsume.
We'll be fine. You need to hurry and look for Genbu Houtenfu.
Please!
Leave it to me!
We're counting on you.
There might be traps set up to protect the Kenbumajin Genbu Houtenfu.
Don't let your guard down.
Understood.
Now then, Natsume, I'm heading out!
We should go, too.
Uh-huh.
It's too dark to see.
This is usually when something creepy pops out, right?
Huh?
Octopus!
Run!
Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
Well, then...
Agh!
Keisuke!
Thanks!
Hurry!
Uh-huh.
Over here!
Alright.
Let's hurry along.
What's this?
W-Why are there turtle heads on the wall?
Since long ago, Genbu has usually been depicted with turtle imagery.
Ugh. It won't open.
What?
Oh!
Whoa!
Waterfall?
Eep!
We're trapped!
Damn it!
What are we going to do?
Whis!
Da ze!
Whisper! Junior!
We were stuck under the lake until we drifted here.
Jii, too!
Save us!
That's right! Transform into a boat, Junior!
No way. Jii needs a template.
Whatever! Just give us something to float on!
Understood! Jii's gonna make do!
Jii...
Hmmm...
[Jii inhaling]
Why me?!
Thanks, Junior!
Let's hurry, everyone.
Uh-huh.
He looks just like Akinori.
I'm not that fat.
Whew. Thank goodness.
If only we could open that door.
Agh!
Oooh. Four people... Too much...
What?
Oh dear. What do we do?
That's right! Let's summon Magurodon!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Magurodon!
Micchi has arrived!
Materialization!
Hyper Micchi!
Eh?
Landing.
Whis!
I didn't ask for you!
Did you find Kenbu Houtenfu?
Not yet!
Because saving Natsume is the highest priority!
After all, I am a superher -
Whatever! Just do something about this!
You can count on me! Ah...
Unfortunately, time's up.
That was fast!
Muscles is useless!
No! My fight has only just begun!
[Micchi grunting]
[Mitsumatanozuchi growling]
He's trying to drink it all?
Looks like an effective strategy.
Fight on, Muscles!
Whoa, the water's going down.
We did it!
Amazing!
Da ze!
Micchi, you finally did something useful!
It's the least I could do.
It's sad that you're useless most of the time, though.
This door is troublesome.
How do we leave this room?
Micchi?
Huh?
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't tell me he's...
[Screaming]
Ugh. Ouch!
Ugh.
Where is this?
This floor is like a turtle's shell.
Are you all okay?
Geez, that was a disaster!
Do you know where the Genbu Houtenfu is?
Yeah. It's right over there.
So that's the Genbu Houtenfu.
Augh!
Are you the Kenbumajin Genbu?
Indeed.
Why do you desire my power?
We want to save our friend!
Her soul was eaten by Jorougumo!
Even though...
Even though I couldn't protect her...
I must save her, whatever it takes!
A tower in our city is covered by Jorougumo's webs, too.
We need Genbu Houtenfu to free them.
Is that so?
Then...
...show me your power!
Very well. Touma.
Uh-huh.
Possession!
Kenbumajin Suzaku!
Suzaku!
Lend me your power!
(Blooming Flowers, Suzaku Azure Heavenly Slayer)
Hyakkaryouran Suzaku Soutenzan!
Suzaku has arrived!
Hmm?
Kenbumajin Suzaku, is it?
It's been very long since I've seen you.
Ha!
Suzaku!
Take this! Heavenly Cross Attack!
It takes tremendous skill to cut off my attack like that.
There is nothing that cannot be cut by the Genbu Houtenfu!
Genbu. Why don't you see if your peerless axe can cut Jorougumo's webs?
Jorougumo's webs?
Yes. Not even Fudou Myouou's Fudou Raimei Ken can cut it.
The only thing that can cut it is Genbu Houtenfu, the axe that splits apart oceans.
Very well.
Let's see if the Genbu Houtenfu can cut Jorougumo's webs.
Genbu Houtenfu.
We can save Ayame with this.
Huh?
What?
Allow me to explain.
These tremors are caused by the moving turtle underneath.
Turtle?
Houkenden sits on top of a huge turtle!
What?
For real?
Let us depart for the Human World.
Have a safe journey.
Motomachi Tower
Huh?
What's this?
Ayame...
Let's go.
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their best
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Charlie!
Charlie was created from the remaining memories of an abandoned bicycle.
Charlie
Charlie's light side may look ridiculous,
but Charlie's shadow side, a ghost bicycle, is terrifying.
Which you'd expect of the Yo-kai behind the "Bicycle Ridden by the Dead" case, of course.
Charlie, let me give you one piece of advice.
A bicycle isn't supposed to ride other bicycles!
Charlie
Next Episode
Preview
Make haste, Akinori!
Ayame doesn't have much time left!
We need to stop Jorougumo fast!
Possession! Kenbumajin Genbu! Lend me your strength!
Jorougumo, I won't forgive you!
You may have hurt Ayame, but I'll save her!
And during that fierce battle, something unexpected happens!
Who is that? That's not Fudou Myouou, is it?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Life-Eating Jorougumo