Youkai Watch Shadow Side 17 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Let us begin.
Spirits, oh spirits...
Ayame Himeno, Year 2 Class A. Who is the boy she in love with?
Is it me?
YES
NO
You moved it just now, didn't you?
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
No way.
Oh spirits, is she in love with me?
NO
YES
Himeaya loves me, right?
NO
It's not moving.
In other words, the answer is "No?"
NO
YES
Geez. Why don't we stop?
Well... in that case...
Spirits, oh spirits, we bid you farewell.
YES
NO
Hold it, Ukyou, you moved it!
No, it moved on its own!
NO
NO WAY
"No Way"?
What does it mean by "No way?"
I AM NOT LEAVING
"I am not leaving?" What does it mean?
We have unfinished business.
Hand them over.
Your bodies...
Give them to me!
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings\
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
This is a tale of summoning the fox spirit in seances.
Such forms of divination shouldn't be done in jest.
Should you summon the dreadful cursed fox, you may lose your life.
The Cursed Fox and the Ouija Board
Hey... what's going on here?
Half of the boys aren't present!
Are they slacking off just because it's still summer?
Ouija board?
Yep. Ouija board.
What is it?
Was it not popular in your elementary school? It's a board with an alphabet that can tell fortunes.
Ah. Yeah, yeah.
Is it the thing used with a 10-yen coin?
I've heard that it's gotten popular with the boys in a neighboring class.
They say that people are disappearing one by one because of the ouija board's curse.
What do you think?
Is there really such a thing as a ouija board curse?
I don't know about a curse, but...
They say that all the absent boys in my class were using an ouija board.
For now, let's have a talk with Akinori about what to do next.
Uh-huh.
In that case, let's have Ayame come with us too.
Umm... sorry, but...
The thing is...
It's over...
Huh?
What?
Hey, Akinori?
Ayame's going on a family vacation for an entire week...
My summer is over.
The End. Game Over.
My save file's been deleted.
What's he talking about?
Talking about Ayame might be a bit difficult.
You might be right. He's become so unmotivated.
Fatty's useless.
It's from Ayame.
It's Ayame!
What?!
Hello? Is this Ayame? It's me, Akinori!
Settle down. It's not even a phone call.
Calm down, Fatty! House!
Hurry up and read it, then!
Let's see...
I’m sorry that I can’t
help with the
investigation of the
ouija case. I know
you will solve this
case because I
believe in you guys.
Please give it your all.
"I’m sorry that I can’t join your investigation of the ouija case."
"I know you will solve this case because I believe in you guys."
"Please give it your all."
"I believe in you guys. Please give it your all."
Ayame!
I believe in you, Akinori!
Do your best, okay?
Leave it to me, Ayame!
Alright! The Yo-kai Detective Agency is open for business!
Let's solve this ouija case in record time!
It's a complete recovery.
Ayame's influence sure is formidable.
By the way... what's a ouija?
It's said to have originated from Europe.
They say it was introduced to Japan at the start of the Meiji Era.
Foreign sailors who came ashore to Japan would surround a table while summoning spirits to have questions answered.
That's when the concept of "table-turning" was introduced.
As it spread, it became Kokkuri-san, the Japanese version of the ouija board that summons fox spirits.
It became a hit with kids even through the present day.
But since kids were fooling around with it so much, many adults started banning it.
There's no such thing as fox sprits, though...
There's a new post.
Umm...
Oh! That student who lost consciousness finally got better.
Looks like he wrote a post.
Huh?
What did he write?
"The fox spirit that we summoned with the ouija board was very malevolent."
"After school, when we used the ouija board, it appeared for real."
"It was a fox monster in the form of a cloud of dark smoke."
"It was like a curse was paralyzing us, preventing our bodies from moving!"
"Then, it told us 'Give me your bodies!' as it came to attack us!"
"I don't even remember what happened next."
A fox monster?
It's very possible that this is a Yo-kai.
Sounds right.
So it's a Yo-kai that can cast curses, huh?
("Curse Fox")
I'm naming it "Tatarigitsune"!
You didn't have to name it!
It's quite on the nose.
Wait, haven't we encountered a fox Yo-kai before?
Oh, you mean Kyuubi?
Cucumber?
Tegh! No! I said Kyuubi!
You've even summoned it before, haven't you, Natsume?!
I've only done that twice.
Whisper!
Yes?
Hand Kyuubi's ark over to Natsume.
Whis!
Kyuubi is also a fox Yo-kai. It might know something.
Alright!
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out, my friend! Kyuubi!
So this is Kyuubi?
Long time no see!
By the way, this is the first time I've seen your light side.
That might be so.
I see.
If it can say things like, "Give me your body..."
...then it can't be a low level animal type of spirit.
This is definitely the work of a Yo-kai.
Do you know of any other fox Yo-kai besides yourself?
Yes. I'm not too familiar with them, but if there are other fox Yo-kai, you'd find them at an Inari shrine.
Inari shrine?
They're shrines dedicated to the goddess Inari-shin.
Inari shrines usually have fox statues instead of lion-dog statues.
Akinori, you sure know a lot.
Ha, ha, ha. I should know at least that much.
Fatty knows useless things.
Don't call it useless! Geez.
Looks like there's a small Inari shrine next to Natsume's school.
Ah, I think there might be.
Alright. Let's go immediately.
So it's here.
Who's that?
Ah! That's the old lady from the tofu restaurant!
Do you know her?
I used to go to her tofu restaurant regularly.
Oh dear. Look who's here. It's Akinori!
You've gotten so tall.
Long time no see.
Umm.... but why would a tofu restaurant owner clean up a shrine?
My sales were well off thanks to the Goddess Inari.
I have always been coming here to clean up.
But starting today, I'm quitting this, too.
Huh?
I've become too old for this.
I've shut down my business and am moving in with my son and his wife.
I see.
Well, there's no use fighting against getting older.
Goodbye, Akinori. Say hi to your grandma for me.
So her store is closed now?
Even we can't solve these kinds of problems.
You people have the scent of a Yo-kai.
Who is it?!
So you've shown yourself!
Give them to me.
Give me your bodies!
SHADOWSIDE
This is bad! This is seriously bad!
Let me do this.
Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
Possession! Genma Goemon! Lend me your strength!
Goemon has arrived!
(Heavenly Ascension Wild Dance Cut)
Tenshouranbuzan!
What is this?
Is this is all I can do?!
Touma!
This Tatarigitsune is tough!
("Curse Fox")
Natsume, we have to save Touma!
Yeah. The enemy is a fox, and we've got a fox of our own!
Whisper!
Kyuubi's ark, is it?
Summoning!
Cucumber?
It's a cucumber.
That's not it! It's "Kyuubi !"
I can't believe you mistook "Kyuubi" for "cucumber!"
I don't want to hear that from you !
Sorry about that! How about this?
Alright! Summoning!
Kiwi?
That's a kiwi fruit.
How long are you doing this for?
Touma's going to get finished off!
Looks like you're able to have Yo-kai take possesion of you at will.
This interests me. Give me your body!
Whisper! Quit fooling around! Give me Kyuubi's ark!
And now, summoning for real!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Kyuubi!
He's so different from his light side!
That's enough!
Who dares to interfere... Huh?
Don't tell me... you're...
Lord Kyuubi?!
Kon!
Who's this? She's cute!
Lord Kyuubi, please excuse my rudeness earlier.
My name is Inari, and I serve at this shrine.
I am highly pleased and much honored to meet a great, world-famous Yo-kai such as yourself, Lord Kyuubi.
She seems to be showing a lot of respect...
It's because Kyuubi is an incredible Yo-kai.
That's because Kyuubi is the nine-tailed fox, a magnificent Yo-kai recorded in legend.
Inari, it seems you seek a human body for some reason.
Can you explain your situation?
Yes.
The people in this area pay little heed to this Inari shrine.
There are very few who bother to visit as well.
Before the shrine fell to ruin...
...there was someone who saved me from being completely homeless.
It was the tofu shop owner's daughter.
May our shop sell more tofu...
Thanks to that girl, this shrine was well maintained for a long time.
To me, that girl is a great benefactor who has always protected my home.
Even in old age, she is always coming over to visit.
(fried tofu)
The handmade aburaage she offers me is filled with sincerity and devotion.
It's a pleasant taste that fills one with happiness.
Is it that wonderful?
Please have some!
Then I shall have some.
I see. This is delicious.
I know, right?
Well, now we know why Inari is thankful for the old lady.
("Curse Fox")
But Inari became Tatarigitsune to seek human bodies.
How does that relate to this?
All I wanted to do was repay the old lady.
Repay?
The old lady and her husband have always been managing the tofu shop.
The tofu and aburaage made at the shop is so delicious, it became famous all across town.
But ever since her husband passed away,
...the old lady was left to run the shop alone.
I want to repay this old lady who is now left all alone.
But as a servant of the shrine, I can not leave it.
And as my frustration accumulated...
One day, by any means possible...
...even if it meant victimizing someone else...
...I was filled with the desire to be of some use to the old lady.
And at that time...
...in a neighboring school, summoning spirits with ouija was becoming popular.
And under its influence, I was able to break free from the shrine.
And in order to help the old lady in her restaurant...
Give me your bodies!
...I tried to borrow the bodies of humans.
Most humans weren't able to withstand the shock of possession.
They all lost consciousness instead.
I see.
So it was for the sake of helping the old lady's shop.
So it wasn't out of malice.
Inari...
I understand your wish to repay a favor by helping the shop.
But in both life and business, there are good times and bad times.
Is there any good in forcing your wishes on humans by causing trouble?
I'm sorry.
I won't cause trouble for humans anymore.
I'm very sorry, everyone.
But can't you just visit the old lady in that form?
Unfortunately, she can't do that.
Yo-kai serving in shrines are prohibited from revealing themselves to humans.
Is that so?
Ah, I got it! Even if she can't show herself, there's another method!
Huh?
What?
Handmade
TOFU
Thank you for your
regular patronage.
-Owner
Thank you for your
regular patronage.
-Owner
Mom, let's leave soon.
Okay.
Grandma! Are you coming home with us?
That's right. I'll always be together with you now.
Together with grandma!
Wait a second!
Ah, it's Akinori.
May I have a bit of your time?
Oh dear. This is...
Are you familiar with the ouija?
Yes. I used to do this a lot.
It's a bit sudden, but do you mind doing a seance together?
That's not a problem.
Good. Now then...
Alright.
Spirits, oh spirits. Please come before us.
Spirits, oh spirits...
Is there anything you wish to say to the tofu shop owner?
Thanks for the
aburaage.
(fried tofu)
"Thanks for the aburaage?"
I love you!
This is...
I love you, old lady!
It's me who should be thanking you.
My dear, cute little fox.
Good thing you got your message to her.
Yes! Thank you so much!
It's an ark!
It's warm.
Is the Inari shrine reallly getting torn down?
Yeah.
How could it be?
What happened to Inari?
When their shrines are destroyed, Yo-kai that serve the gods of those shrines lose power and disappear.
So that means Inari is...
Oh, dear...
Old lady? Why are you here?
I had a strange dream last night.
At daybreak, go to the Inari shrine and touch the fox statue.
Someone will be waiting there to show herself to you.
That's what he said.
That dream...
Would you like to come with me?
Dear fox?
Yeah. I love you, old lady!
Kyuubi must have used his powers so that the old lady and Inari can live together even without the shrine.
Maybe.
He can be kind sometimes.
We solved the ouija case
without incident♪
P.S. Don't forget to
get souvenirsー<3
That's a relief.
They've solved the case.
And now with the news.
MULTIPLE MISSING PEOPLE
In Sakura Motomachi, a number of people have gone missing.
Near a resort in Karuiyamachou, similar disappearances are also occurring.
MULTIPLE MISSING PEOPLE
The number of those missing in this incident is estimated to reach ten people.
Karuiyamachou is right here, isn't it?
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Yo-kai Watch Movie News!
Have all of you gotten your hands on the movie preorder tickets yet?
Nekomata
Today, I'll be showing you the movie poster!
It's got me and Shin in it!
"I thought that we'd always be together?" What does that mean?
I'm so anxious that I can't even sleep!!
Movie ticket preorders are now officially on sale!
My special Yo-kai ark is included!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
About the app that can morph the shape of your face in your photos?
Ah. Did you mean the one that can make your face look cute or cool?
It's gotten popular recently.
But be cautious about using it!
Something terrible is happening to people!
Something terrible?
What do you think happens to your actual face when you mess with it in the app?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Face Thief