Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 10 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
What would you like today?
Let's get chopping!
Everything in this this world, always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
This time, we have a story about a frightening man armed with huge sickles in both hands who attacks women at night.
He has the appearance of a clown, and his victims mount one after another.
His name is...
(Senritsu no Kirisaki Jōkā)
The Terrible Ripping Joker
Huh!
So this is in fashion this year.
It's pretty! The hairstyle is in good taste too, don't you think?
That's right!
Hey, what are you girls excited about?
Ah!
Natsume, which hairstyle do you think is best?
Hairstyle?
"Popular and Fashionable Summer Hairstyles: Special Report?"
Natsume, you should try changing up your hairstyle sometime.
Huh?
A makeover! A makeover!
Hairstyle, huh?
That's certainly a serious issue for us young adults!
Isn't that right?
You're happy with your hairstyle now, right?
Huh? Uh... Nah.
I was thinking of getting a different hairstyle soon, actually.
Something like Touma's.
Huh?
Mine?
Uh-huh! Touma's haircut is so cool!
Well, I guess Touma's style could work for you...
Huh?
Heh, it's kinda weird, though.
Natsume! What did you imagine just now?!
Hey, Keisuke, how about my hairstyle?
Huh? What about yours?
How about getting the same hairstyle I have?
It's kinda weird.
-It's kinda weird.
What's with the matching response?
Geez. You don't even get how good this hairstyle is.
Fatty's lame! Learn from Jii!
Ha ha! Awesome!
Jii, what'd you do to your hair?
Jii's afro! Makeover! Makeover!
Afro! Afro!
Hair flip!
So I hear that everyone's been talking about hairstyles. Hair flip!
So we've decided to also... Hair flip! ...get a makeover as well. Hair flip!
Quit it with the hair flips!
Natsume! Do you think this crew cut is suitable for a musclebound beauty such as me?
Nope. No idea.
Muscles is lame! Smells sour!
Well, he certainly is a little sour-smelling...
Wait! This isn't the time to be talking about this!
-Wouldn't it be weird for you to have hair?
Only if I were in my Shadowside form!
There is a Yo-kai mystery to solve!
Here!
The Ripping Joker?
Huh? This one seems kind of dangerous.
Yep. This case is pretty dangerous.
According to this post, he appears before women...
...and he shouts, "Let's get chopping!" before chasing down victims with sharp sickles.
W-With sickles?
This isn't a Yo-kai case, it's a serial killer!
That aside, what's the "Joker" part about?
The witness says that he looked exactly like a joker on playing cards.
So he looks like a clown. That's what was meant by "playing card joker."
I see. So he's a clown that chases you down with sickles at night.
That's scary! Why clowns?! Seeing that on the streets at night is scary enough!
Well, that's for sure.
What happened to the victims?
They were attacked, but they weren't injured, it seems.
Ah. That's fortunate.
But the Ripping Joker's victims were...
Hmm?
Perfect time to get a reply.
"Reply?"
Yeah. I've made contact with one of the victims to set up a meeting.
Did they agree to meet?
Hmm... Um...
"Sorry, but I'm too ashamed of my appearance to meet with you right now."
Huh?
For a girl to be too ashamed to meet with anyone...
Does it mean he cuts up his victim's faces?
No. They say he doesn't wound people. It must be for another reason.
Ah... I see.
Something other than physical wounds that cause embarrassment...
It might be a deep emotional wound instead.
That's cruel. I can't let this happen again.
Yeah! We can't leave this to anyone else!
Let's go find this Ripping Joker and eliminate him!
Right!
All the victims are girls, right? I'll serve as bait to lure him out!
Huh?
Natsume!
No way! You're gonna get attacked by someone with sickles!
That's right. It's too dangerous.
Then what do we do then?
Heh. My fellows.
As leader of the Yo-kai Detective Agency, you can leave this to me!
Since when did we decide on having a leader?
Who knows?
Umm... You know...
There's no way.
He's definitely not gonna pass for a girl.
How can he walk around so confidently like that?
But if seen from behind, he looks just like an ordinary shrine maiden...
If you give an inch... right?
I wouldn't give up any inches!
How are you today?
Shall we get chopping?
H-H-H-He's...
You've finally shown yourself, Ripping Joker!
Shall we do it? Chop!
Pardon me!
Akinori!
Are you ok?
Leave it to me!
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune! Lend me your strength!
Six o'clock. Yoshitsune.
Yoshitsune has arrived!
Prepare yourself!
Please come again!
Akinori, are you okay?
Akinori!
Wow... That was surprising! I thought I was cut!
Are you okay?
Hmmm....
It doesn't look like I've been cut anywhere.
That's good...
It's getting late.
Let's gather again tomorrow and think of a plan to deal with Ripping Joker.
That's right.
Ah...
Ah... I still have this on.
What does the ma'am mean by "emergency situation?"
Ma'am?
She's Akinori's grandma.
She knows a lot about Yo-kai.
When did you get her number?
It's been a while. Touma. Natsume.
It has been a while.
Hello.
Huh? You must be Keisuke.
Yes. Nice to meet you.
You seen pretty energetic.
Huh? This is my first time meeting this person, right?
In a way, yeah.
Ah, that's right... what did you mean by "emergency situation?"
To be honest, Akinori's been staying under his bedcovers all morning. He hasn't come out at all.
That's the same as Ripping Joker's victims!
Akinori! What happened?
Come on out and tell us.
Just go home! There's no way I can show anyone how I look now!
I wonder what happened.
He's closed himself off.
Maybe it's a wound that he doesn't want to show anyone.
Ankinori. We're your best friends!
It doesn't matter how you look. You're still Akinori to us!
Please. Trust us. Come on out.
Cut it out!
Get up already!
Gah?! What is with that haircut?!
A mushroom cut...
You laughed! You're having a laugh, aren't you?!
Whatever happened to "It doesn't matter how you look?!"
Touma, even you're with laughing!
Sorry...
Geez. That's why I didn't want to show you guys!
Well... at least it's clear now.
The reason why all of the Ripping Joker's victims are hiding...
...it has to be because their hair was cut into the mushroom cut!
Just like me.
Fatty looks like a fungus!
It's not a fungus! It's a mushroom haircut!
Stop laughing!
It's here.
I heard that this haircut salon was famous for beautiful mushroom cuts.
So is that why Ripping Joker might be here?
I don't know for sure.
The only clue that we have about Ripping Joker is that he's obsessed with mushroom cuts.
Let's just check it out for now.
That's right.
That salon isn't open anymore.
I've heard that this salon was famous for mushroom cuts.
Yeah. You must be talking about Kou.
Kou?
Around here, Kou was famous for being a skilled hairdresser.
He wanted the world to know the splendor of the mushroom cut.
But right before going to the worldwide hairdresser's convention, he died in a traffic accident.
Huh?
It really is... a shame...
There's no mistaking it.
This Kou person must have turned into the Ripping Joker.
This is...
Welcome!
What can I do for you today?
Ripping Joker!
Everyone's here for a mushroom cut, right?
If we're not careful, we'll get cut.
Natsume!
Summon this Yo-kai!
Wait...
You want me to summon them?
We can fight against Ripping Joker's sickles with it!
Agggh... Jeez.
Alright, fine!
Summon!
Light!
Come on out my friend! Zundonmaru!
I am... Zun! Don! Maru!
You made the right choice by summoning me!
Let's just cut you!
What?
My body is made of tough Molybdenum alloy!
Attacks like that are nothing to me!
And on top of that!
Fooo!
Here's some special hot water to help rust you up!
Special move! Sprinkler!
What a weirdo.
Now's the time!
Possession! Kenbumajin Fudomyou!
(Sword Warrior Demon Acala)
(Immovable)
Fudou!
Lend me your strength!
(Immovable Thunder)
Lightning! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Sword!
(Acala)
Fudomyou has arrived!
Let me show you the real way to handle a blade!
Hello!
Oh.. Hello.
We're inside the hair salon?
Wait, so this is the Ripping Joker's Lightside?
My name is Mushbarber! Mush!
Mushbarber?
Right!
Hey! Akinori's hair returned to normal!
It's true!
Whoa! Good thing!
My timelessly handsome hairstyle's back!
Fatty's wrong. It's not timelessly handsome at all!
What?
Why did you attack people and give them mushroom cuts?
The mushroom cut isn't a very popular haircut.
That's why I want to show the world the greatness of the mushroom cut!
Why are you so fascinated by the mushroom cut?
That's because...
Because my memory of my first love involves the mushroom cut.
When I was a child, my hairstylist thought it would look nice to give me the mushroom cut.
But my classmates were like...
Eeww!
Kou is a fungus head!
Hey, you guys!
Mushrooms are going to save the world!
Kino?
Oh yeah, Kino's got the same fungus haircut as Kou!
Kino + Kou means fungus! You two deserve each other!
Don't call it fungus! It's called mushroom!
Whatever!
Stop yelling!
Whatever, you mushroom.
-Kou...
Wanna save the world with mushrooms too?
Sure!
And from then on, the mushroom cut became my favorite haircut.
And right until I died in the traffic accident...
...I continued to practice the craft of mushroom haircuts.
Even after dying, my love for the mushroom cut grew so big...
...that I became the Ripping Joker and started attacking people.
So that was why.
So that was how you became so obsessed with the mushroom cut.
I wish that while I was still alive, I could have shared the mushroom cut with Kino.
Umm... Excuse me...
Welcome!
I didn't set an appointment. Is this fine?
Sure! It's no problem.
That person can see Yo-kai!
And she's not even scared! What does this mean?
Please have a seat right over...
Umm...
Please! Have a seat!
Thank you very much!
Of course!
She must be seeing Kou the barber and not Mushbarber's current form.
But why?
Any reason for coming here in particular?
I decided to get a haircut and happened to find this salon.
I see. So what would you like?
Would you please give me the mushroom cut?
Very well. Mushroom cut is it?
Huh? Have I seen her before?
That's right! She's the famous actress, Shiratorizawa Maya!
Come to think of it, I've seen her before,
She's been in commercials and TV dramas.
Uh-huh.
But she hasn't been on television recently...
It's just that work hasn't been easy to find recently.
So I decided to get a makeover.
But why choose the mushroom cut?
When I was child, I always had a mushroom cut.
Is that so?
When I was a child,
my beloved mushroom cut made me feel invincible.
I wanted to recapture that feeling.
Oh! And there was also a boy in my class who had the same haircut!
The other classmates made fun of us for being the "Mushroom Duo."
I wonder where he is now?
I'm sure he's still in love with the mushroom cut, perhaps.
That'd be nice!
That person has got to be Mushbarber's first love!
But her name's different.
I'm sure she didn't mention Kino at all.
Maybe Shiratorizawa Maya is her stage name?
Ah, that's right!
How is it?
It's beautiful!
It's better than I imagined!
For some reason, I feel as energetic as I did when I was a kid!
Good thing I came to this salon!
Do you feel like you can save the world?
Of course!
Mushrooms shall save the world!
Thank you very much!
His wish finally came true.
She's here! She's here!
Maya is incredible!
Uh-huh! She even got cast as the heroine of Space Wars!
The heroine's catchphrase, if you will.
Mushrooms shall save the world!
What's this?
During auditions, the mushroom cut gained the director's favor, becoming the deciding factor.
Its impact has resulted in an unprecedented worldwide boom of the mushroom cut.
Huh.
I've also tried on the Machoroom!
It's "mushroom," isn't it?
Doesn't it look good?
Surprisingly good!
Isn't that nice? Mushbarber?
We haven't found any clues on the princess.
I'm beginning to get bored of hearing that.
My apologies. There is no excuse.
Well, whatever.
Make preparations for the princess's arrival.
Yes, sir!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Akinori's
Yo-kai Watch Shadowside
Trivia
Today we'll be talking about the Youma Radar!
The Youma Radar is an item used to find Yo-kai.
It detects the energy emitted by Yo-kai, making hunting for them a lot smoother!
It's an indispensable tool for the Yo-kai Detective Agency.
It's a unique one-of-a-kind item made by my grandma.
That's Youma Radar!
By the way, how did Grandma even manage to make this?
Nyaa... Did ya know?
About my past...
About why there's a mark on my ear?
About why I always destroy trucks when I see them?
And about why I soften up whenever I see them...
Yeah, and by them I meant...
Pretty. School. Girls.
It's my episode for me about me and my story.
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
I am a Cat Yo-kai.
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs