Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 21 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Is Ayame Himeno really the princess that we are looking for?
Certainly, when Himeno surfaced...
...the sakura tree, which reacts to the rebirth of the princess, reached full bloom.
But I still think she's just an ordinary human.
Then how do you explain this sakura branch?
Himeno caused the flowers to bloom when I waved this branch at her.
On top of that, she is able to use magic.
She certainly has some unusual abilities, but...
...even that piglet is able to perform the same sorcery.
Perhaps those flowers were blooming in response to that magic?
What an interesting debate.
Who are you?
Take me in as your comrade.
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Revive! Kenbumajin Suzaku!
(Swordsmen Spirit)
Ayame Himeno.
Are you actually Himeno?!
You should already know.
Of course, Princess.
I see that you've finally acknowledged yourself.
Whoa. That guy is no good, right?
Indeed. This person is incredibly bad news. And they've appeared so suddenly!
But I don't know.
Who is this person...?
Alright. I'll go see who it is, then!
They might be be hiding incredible power.
Please be careful.
Well then, Princess.
Your orders, please.
What a cute child.
But too bad.
Soon, I'll have to return to being human as Ayame Himeno again.
It looks like I lack the power to continuing being the princess.
I understand.
(Yo-kai Holy Sword)
You need the Youseiken, right?
If we don't gather all five Youseiken,
...you won't be able to reawaken your powers.
Youseiken, huh?
Well, that's one way.
But the thing I want the most right now...
...is a man.
A man?
In order to gather power,
I need a beautiful man.
But fear not.
The man I need is a human man.
Human man?
That's right.
I've been searching since long ago for a legendary man.
He is the being necessary for me to restore my power.
We will find him.
Yeah, it's someone really dangerous!
You need to come quickly!
Understood. I'll let Natsume know, too.
Please!
Just who in the world are you?
Huh?
The reaction disappeared!
Why am I here?
When she returns to her human form,
she has no memory of her time as the princess.
Until she completely reawakens, the princess will remain sleeping within that human.
Let's hurry.
We must find what she seeks.
That piglet.
Let's ward off that nuisance.
We must not let him near the princess.
Yes.
What was that?
It's you!
My name is Douketsu.
Douketsu?
Go away if you don't want to die, piglet.
You bastard!
Don't call me a piglet!
Descend!
Mythical Beast Suzaku!
Suzaku has arrived!
Mythical Beast Suzaku, huh?
If it weren't for you, this piglet wouldn't be here right now.
Can you really win against me and my Ashura Gouenmaru?
(Colossal Inferno)
Why don't we try and see?
Oh?
How surprising.
Good!
Let's end this now!
Don't get so cocky!
Akinori!
Suzaku!
Suzaku! Suzaku!
Suffer!
I'll end it all now...
Akinori!
Everyone!
Suzaku!
What happened?
Suzaku took a hit for me!
Alright, leave this to me.
Possession!
Genma Omatsu!
Lend me your strength!
I am the healer of all living beings...
I, Omatsu, shall lend you my power.
Omatsu's powers aren't working!
It worked on Akinori, though!
Why?
I'm sorry.
But the reason you can't heal me...
...is because I've taken the form of a Mythical Beast.
What do you mean?
Originally, I was a Kenbumajin, just like Fudou Myouou.
I remember you said that before.
So if we returned you to your Kenbumajin form, we can heal you?
Yes.
What should I do? I'll do anything!
Where is that?
Something that I need to return to being a Kenbumanjin is there.
It's just ahead.
I can still survive in this form with the power I have left.
Let's go.
A-Are we really going now? Can't we go tomorrow instead?
What is this place?
(Azure Heavenly Slayer)
In order to obtain Suzaku Soutenzan,
We need to go to the Yo-kai world through the Pond of Twisted Necks.
No! No! No!
We're going to get our necks twisted out here!
We can get to the Yo-kai world through here?
Ouch!
Look, Akinori.
The Suzaku Soutenzan rests within there, the Twin Sword Mountains.
Woah, it's tall.
Which mountain is the Suzaku Soutenzan at?
Sorry. That I do not know.
I just know that the sword is at the top of one of them for sure.
Alright, let's go.
By the way...
Suzaku, how did you wind up becoming a Mythical Beast?
The Mythical Beasts are already high ranking Yo-kai even in the Yo-kai world.
But even higher still is a king who rules the Mythical Beasts.
Only those recognized by the Mythical King can become Kenbumajin.
But then one day, I was turned into a Mythical Beast by the Mythical King.
Why?
I provoked the wrath of the Mythical King.
It was a furious rage that burned throughout the Yo-kai world.
But even so, I would have needed to return to my Kenbumajin form eventually.
Is that so?
Akinori, you become thinner whenever you summon me, right?
Yeah. I kinda like that.
Even that phenomenon is a side effect of me becoming a Mythical Beast.
What do you mean?
The power that's required to summon me is unrivaled.
So I've made use of the abundant extra calories within your body.
Abundant calories?
He sure has a lot of extra calories.
That's right.
So that was your plan the whole time!
Just what do you guys think you know?
Ha. Sorry.
How many times do I have to tell you?! I'm not fat! I'm big boned!
Umm... Can I point something out?
Akinori, aren't you a little thinner?
It's true!
What? Why?
Actually...
I've been using your calories as we speak.
Seems like our lives are connected.
Ah! He's getting even thinner!
Just how thin are you going to get?
Until I turn back into a Kenbumajin, it won't stop.
If this continues, eventually...
Give me calories!
What?! Getting that thin doesn't look cool at all!
But more importantly, getting too thin will kill you!
We need to get Suzaku Soutenzan before Akinori runs out of calories!
What? What?
What is it?
Hey, everyone!
Where did everyone go?
We've been separated.
We'll have to climb, even if it's just us two.
SHADOWSIDE
The Suzaku Soutenzan cannot be pulled out by anyone other than you, my contractee.
It'd be nice if it was on this summit.
But what if it isn't here?
Then I will continue on.
Me too.
That's... food!
We've got some calories here!
Restored!
Heave ho!
We're here!
If the Suzaku Soutenzan is here, you can turn back into a Kenbumajin, right?
Yeah.
So a human has finally come this far.
Who is it?
So is that bird Suzaku?
I see.
So you're trying to turn back into a Kenbumajin, right?
Mythical Beast Kirin.
So you've been protecting the Suzaku Soutenzan?
Humph. But it isn't even here.
For real?!
You've failed this trial of luck by choosing the wrong mountain.
This trial will now take your life.
Huh? They disappeared!
Wait! Kirin!
No use for words!
This is Suzaku Soutenzan.
I wonder if we can pull it out.
What was that?
That's...
Don't tell me that's Akinori?
That was close!
Bastard! How dare they!
I won't lose!
It's useless!
Without the power of the Suzaku Soutenzan on the other mountain...
...we can't win.
So those other humans are attempting to pull out the Suzaku Soutenzan?
Huh? Touma and the others?
But it is for naught.
The Suzaku Soutenzan can only be pulled out by those it has chosen, namely you, Akinori.
You are ruined, Suzaku.
What?
Handing the Animus Tenjoukyou to a novice like him was a mistake.
I can't bear to look at a fellow Mythical Beast reduced to this.
I shall bury you here!
Akinori, get it together!
Damn...
If only I could fly, I'd be able to get to the other mountain.
That's it!
So you still have this power?
But what can you do with that half-dead body?
I'll show you!
Akinori!
Whoa! W-What?!
Fly!
W-Wait!
Ouch!
It's no use.
How do we even pull it out?
What was that?
It's a bird!
No, it's a plane!
No, it's Akinori!
What?
Whisper, please!
Akinori! I'm here to...
Akinori!
Micchi!
Roger! Jump!
Catch!
Natsume!
How was that?
I have wonderfully...
Ouch...
Suzaku Soutenzan!
The sword isn't pushing him away!
I see! Maybe Akinori can pull it out, since he's been acknowledged by Suzaku!
I won't allow it!
W-Who is that?!
Is that Yo-kai Suzaku Soutenzan's protector?
We can't let it interfere with Akinori!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
Too slow!
Jibanyan!
It's my turn!
Possession!
(Acala)
Kenbumajin... Fudou Myouou!
Immovable!
Lend me your strength!
Lightning! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Sword!
(Immovable Thunder)
Fudou Myouou... has arrived.
So Fudou Myouou has appeared once again...
I have always wanted to challenge you at least once.
Let's go!
It disappeared again!
Take this!
What?
So you're no ordinary foe, huh?
Then how about this?
He can't block that many attacks!
Touma!
Take this!
Oh no!
We did it!
Are you okay, Kirin?
Looks like you were going easy on me.
It's my defeat.
Suzaku, you have good friends.
Yeah.
Ah, that's got to be...
(Mythical Beast)
It's a Genjuu Disc.
It's summoned with Akinori's watch...
Ah! That's right! Akinori!
Only I can...
We did it!
You've pulled it out, Akinori!
Suzaku?
Akinori.
Thanks to you, I am now a Kenbumajin once again.
You have my thanks.
No, it's thanks to everyone else's hard work.
Very well.
Let's get along from now on!
Yes.
It's a Youseiken!
That's right! The Youseiken can only be used with Touma's Ogre Watch.
This is fine.
Let's go home.
Sure.
Ah! I forgot to set the DVR to record that TV drama!
It's a shame. Mom and Dad wanted to see it too.
Geez! I want a Youseiken too!
Binge eating?
Oh, by the way, Suzaku, you mentioned that you got the Mythical King angry enough to turn you into a Mythical Beast.
What did you do?
About that...
Actually...
I accidentally called the Mythical King... "Cute Little King" by mistake.
That's it?
We went through all that just for this?
I was... quite young back then.
This Mythical King guy is so petty!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is on Mythical Beasts!
Mythical Beasts, like the Genma and unlike other Yo-kai, are high-class and high-ranking beings.
Genjuu
(Mythical Beasts)
They're super strong!
And with the Genjuu Disc, I can summon these Mythical Beasts with my Yo-kai Watch Animus!
But it seems like summoning Mythical Beasts requires calories, so I get thinner every time I do it.
(Mythical Beasts)
Genjuu
Heh. The thin version of me is pretty handsome, don't you think?
(Mythical Beasts)
Genjuu
Next Episode
Preview
Oh, no! Touma collapsed!
What is this Yo-kai energy?
This isn't an ordinary sickness! This must be the work of a Yo-kai!
Something awful must be happening within Touma's body!
It must be something lying dormant within him!
There is only one way:
We must enter Touma's body and expel it from within!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
Touma and the Oni King's Fragment.