Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 19 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
I'm sorry!
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
With the arrival of summer, cicadas always follow.
They've slumbered in the ground for years.
They finally emerge to the surface...
...only to be caught in a net and thrown into a bug cage, where it spends its short life.
But what if the anger of these cicadas were to build up into explosive rage?
What frightening things will happen?
Cicada's Semifinal Counterattack
Natsume, I'm going to catch beetles with Tank and Kouji in the mountains.
Take care...
Yeah. See you later.
W-Well... I don't think I'll be encountering any Yo-kai... but just in case.
A cicada?
Is it dead?
Oh, that was surprising.
Hey, Keisuke!
Good morning!
Good morning, Tank, Kouji.
Sorry, did you wait long?
No worries! Let's go already!
Alright!
Let's catch a bunch!
I won't lose!
-Neither will I!
When I came here last year, there were rhino beetles and stag beetles in the forest up there.
Sounds fun!
Just you wait, you beetles!
Nothing is here...
There's nothing here, either.
That's a shame. Let's look for something else.
A cicada?
Yeah! There were a lot of cicadas the whole time we were here.
I filled my whole cage last year!
Cicadas, huh?
We didn't have to come to the mountains just to catch cicadas!
How about a competition?
If you can catch more cicadas than I can,
I'll buy penguin ice cream for you all!
What? Really?
Are you sure you won't regret this?
But if I win, I want a ton of meat buns, along with ice cream.
Yeah! Sounds good!
Alright! Let's catch some cicadas by this mountain pass!
This is so exciting!
W-Why is there fog all of a sudden?
It's hot.
Why is it so hot today?
Is it due to the effects of global warming?
Unfortunately, the only thing I can do now is distract Natsume with the splendor of my beautiful body.
Muscles, too hot! It stinks! Stinky hot!
Jii won't make it. Gonna melt.
Jii?
Ah. I give up.
I wouldn't think the air conditioner would break today, of all days.
So the electrician won't be here until next week, huh?
That's right! I just thought of something!
We should summon Fubuki-hime and have her cool down the room!
No, no, no. Her idea of cooling us down would be lethal. Please do not.
It's better than being hot.
No! It wouldn't be!
It doesn't matter either way.
Keisuke took the Yo-kai Watch.
Keisuke?
He went to the mountains with his friends to catch bugs.
Elementary school students sure are energetic.
Looks like Ayame won't be here today either.
I don't really feel like doing anything.
Oh, geez... Ayame! Why can't you be here?!
-That's how people act when they're drunk, huh?
Ayame?
What? It's just Touma.
Sorry. Was it a bad time for me to come?
No, that's not what I meant.
He just thought Ayame was coming.
I see.
But Touma, you're here later than usual, right?
Yes. I was watching soccer on TV.
It was the summer national semifinals.
Ah, that's right. The semifinals were today.
I was watching it at home and came late.
Ah, I also got ice cream on the way. You should all have some.
For real? Thanks you!
Thanks!
Jii will eat! Cool down with ice cream!
May I also have one?
And just when I thought about cooling down after some hard training!
I've got enough for everyone.
A stalking cicada with a grudge?!
Submitter: Takachan
One summer morning, a friend and I went to the mountains of
Sakura Motomachi to catch bugs.
I wasn’t able to catch any, but my friend was boasting about
catching four cicadas.
Just then, a bunch of cicadas started chirping all of a sudden!
Suddenly, this unnatural looking fog came down all around us.
I got scared and ran down the mountain in tears, but my friend never
made it back.
These short-lived but vengeful cicadas are surely getting their
revenge on him!
See Comments(5) >
Huh? What about Keisuke?
He went to the mountains to catch bugs with his friends, it seems.
See Comments(5) >
One summer morning, a friend and I went to the mountains of
Sakura Motomachi to catch bugs.
I wasn’t able to catch any, but my friend was boasting about
catching four cicadas.
Just then, a bunch of cicadas started chirping all of a sudden!
Suddenly, this unnatural looking fog came down all around us.
I got scared and ran down the mountain in tears, but my friend never
made it back.
These short-lived but vengeful cicadas are surely having their
revenge on him!
A stalking cicada with a grudge?!
Submitter: Takachan
See Comments(5) >
I'll have Keisuke's ice cream! Keisuke's things are my things!
Heh, heh! Look at this!
I got this many in an instant!
I'll be having free ice cream and meat buns!
It's not over yet! It's just the beginning.
Alright!
I'll go there this time!
Hold it, Tank!
Wow! Awesome!
It's all-you-can-catch over here!
Alright!
Huh?
Why is it so quiet all of a sudden?
What's wrong?
I think I heard Tank's voice.
Just how far ahead did he go?
We need to find him fast.
Tank!
Where are you?
Stay away!
SHADOWSIDE
What's with that getup?
Okay, Natsume, this should cool you down!
Micchi Cyclone!
Stop! Stop!
Was that satisfactory?
As if!
Muscles is stupid! Strongly stupid!
Very well! This time...
Gentle Breeze Mode!
Ah! That's better.
Such praise is a high honor!
That looks pretty exhausting, though.
One summer morning, a friend and I went to the mountains of
Sakura Motomachi to catch bugs.
I wasn’t able to catch any, but my friend was boasting about
catching four cicadas.
Just then, a bunch of cicadas started chirping all of a sudden!
Suddenly, this unnatural looking fog came down all around us.
I got scared and ran down the mountain in tears, but my friend never
made it back.
These short-lived but vengeful cicadas are surely having their
revenge on him!
A stalking cicada with a grudge?!
Submitter: Takachan
See Comments(5) >
What's this?
Are you okay?
That's right! Cicada!
Huh?
Who are you?
And where is this place?
We were all attacked.
By that cicada-like monster.
This is where it imprisons people after pouncing on them.
Whoa, what is that?
They're keeping watch on us.
If we try to escape, they'll make a huge noise.
And then that monster will come back.
For real?
And while we're here...
It'll use its proboscis to suck all the juices out of us!
And then we'll wind up as dried up husks!
Oh, no...
Mom...
What is with the cicadas in these mountains?
There's something weird going on.
Maybe this is the work of a Yo-kai?
Kouji, watch my stuff for me.
I'm going to get Tank back.
A-Alright!
In this case...
Let's do this! Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend, Hyper Micchi!
Breeze breeze breeze...
How is it, Natsume?
It feels nice.
Aren't you eating too much ice cream?
Being useful to Natsume is the utmost honor...
Muscles disappeared!
It appears that he was summoned by the Yo-kai Watch.
Did Keisuke summon him?
Did something happen?
Natsume, Keisuke went bug catching in the mountains.
He said he went to the neighboring mountains.
This isn't good.
What's this?
Cicada's grudge?
Hyper Micchi has arrived!
Micchi! I want you to help me find Tank!
And then do something about the cicadas!
Leave it to me!
Let me explain.
There's no need to explain!
-Hyper Micchi can materialize the Hyper Micchi Cloak and Hyper Micchi Suit in only 0.2 seconds!
And also, because Hyper Micchi's suit is super rough and super hot, Hyper Micchi's transformation time is super limited!
I told you to stop wasting time explaining!
Anyway, I want you to find my friend, Tank!
Something terrible just appeared!
It appears to be a cicada Yo-kai.
Opposing Hyper Micchi is recklessness!
I'll teach you a lesson!
Jump!
Super Muscle Prince True Love Handsome Hyper Micchi!
Time has expired.
That was useless!
Not at all! Even a non-Hyper Micchi is still strong!
We did it!
That was an easy victory.
Well, Keisuke, would you like to record this magnificent feat as one of your summertime memories in your diary for posterity?
I'll have to say no.
Secret Technique: Semifinal!
Ah! Useless as usual!
Oh, no! Next one!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Ah. So the enemy is a cicada.
Always chirping and buzzing with loud noises every year!
Just die off already!
My ears!
Ha! Think you can win?
Your sonic attack can't affect me anymore.
Bastard!
Crap!
I really hate water!
You dare to splash at me with that?
Take this!
We did it!
Heh. Don't get cocky, bug.
It's over.
Wait, it's still...
Huh? It can't be.
Semifinal!
Jiba...
Jibanyan?
Oh, no... even Jibanyan?
Natsume...
Suzaku?
Keisuke!
Natsume!
We were just on time.
So that's the one behind all this!
Do you know about it?
Actually...
Hey, you!
That one is my prey.
How did I get run aground by a pissant like you?
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
I've used up all my energy.
At any rate... that's quite a big cicada!
Be careful! He might do his "Semifinal" again!
As in a tournament semifinal?
No. It's when a cicada feigns death and then pulls a surprise attack.
Ah! There are usually a lot of them laying on the roadside.
That's frightening.
I did my job this time.
That was the final Semifinal.
Final Semifinal?
Sounds kinda impressive.
Ah, this cicada Yo-kai should know where Tank is.
He got separated from us when looking for bugs.
What?
Then we have to get this cicada Yo-kai to wake up somehow.
Alright. I'll do something.
Possession!
Genma Omatsu!
Lend me your strength!
Healer of the creatures of the summer...
I, Omatsu, shall lend you my power.
Ah... I am...
Your Semifinal is pretty effective.
I-I've caused you a lot of trouble. You have my cicadapologies.
Cicada.
Please call me Semicolon.
While I'm in my shadow side form as Semilong, it's hard for me to hold myself back.
You have my sincere cicadapologies.
Cicada.
You got quite popular on Usuranura.
They know you as a cicada monster who attacks people in the mountains.
Huh? So did this Yo-kai do something to Tank?
Why did you attack people?
It's a bit of a long story...
When I was still sleeping in the ground...
...I had a best friend that I spent time with.
MY
FRIEND
ME
MY
FRIEND
ME
Hey, when you grow into an adult, what do you want to do?
To fall in love, of course!
With a cute lady!
MY
FRIEND
I know, right?
Have you thought about your proposal?
Of course, you'd have to be in semi-formal clothes, right?
ME
I wonder!
I heard there's a seminar about it!
MY
FRIEND
ME
MY
FRIEND
ME
What about the wedding ring?
My friend and I were both eagerly looking forward to the day we went out into the outside world.
MY
FRIEND
You know, I've already decided on the names of my children.
What? Tell me!
I'm only going to let you in on it.
On the names of my children.
We made a promise to go out together when we became adults, but...
ME
One morning...
Huh?
ME
What?
Hey! Where'd you go?
Don't tell me...
My best friend went on ahead to the outside world first!
ME
Afterwards, I panicked and risked my life to find my friend.
In the end, I couldn't find him in my whole short life.
ME
But my desire to meet my best friend at all costs lingered on after death.
Soon after, I was reborn as the Yo-kai Semilong.
So you became a Yo-kai from a desire to find your friend?
Yes!
So why were you attacking people?
That's because it'd be problematic if you kids caught my friend before I meet him.
So I thought about forcing you kids to settle down for a while.
So that was why.
Um... Can I ask you something?
Yes?
As a cicada, you should already know this...
...but an adult cicada's life is short.
...That's why your friend should now already be...
Yes... my friend is no longer living by now, probably...
But at the very least, I wanted to meet his children.
But if it is going to cause trouble for people, then it might be best for me to just stop.
I am truly sorry.
My cicadapologies.
Wait a sec.
If everyone looked, we should find your best friend's kids.
But cicadas all look the same to us.
How do we tell them apart?
My best friend told me the name that he was going give to his kid...
Oh! That could be a useful clue!
What's the name?
Seminude.
Seminude?
Ooh! For real?
Ah, but it's a cicada's name, right?
I think they should be around here.
That's...
What are you looking at?
It's a molting cicada.
Seminude?
Huh?
That's right! I'm Semicolon!
Seminude!
Thank goodness.
So Seminude is named for how they're half naked from molting, huh?
Ah, is that so?
Thank goodness.
He was happy, wasn't he?
This is quite the touching story.
So they can even communicate with Yo-kai?
All I can see is a cicada wriggling in its own skin, though.
I was able to meet with my best friend's child, everyone.
Here's my apology for causing you all trouble.
Ooh, it's an ark!
Umm. But more importantly, how about Tank?
Ahh! You saved us!
I'm never going to catch cicadas ever again.
Me, too.
Well! It seems like everyone's okay for now.
Let's go have some shaved ice.
Sounds good. Let's go!
Then it's settled. Let's make have Keisuke pay for it.
Just kidding!
There is no need to hide.
I already know that you are my princess.
I told you, I'm not your princess. I'm just Himeno.
Can you not make the same mistake again?
Anyway, it's unusually hot.
If only I had a yukata or if someone would sprinkle water, it'd feel cooler.
If my princess commands it, a simple task like sprinkling water is a trifle.
Princess! Please wait! Princess!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is about Hyper Micchi!
Hyper Micchi
When Micchi powers up, he becomes Hyper Micchi!
He's incredible strong!
Hyper Micchi
Or so I've heard.
He can only transform for a short time.
And even so, he spends so much time uselessly explaining things after he transforms!
Hyper Micchi
And then he always transforms back to his original form!
Micchi, can't you be useful for once?
Hyper Micchi
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
They say you should be careful going to the movies!
Huh? What do you mean?
In shopping malls and such, there are cinema multiplexes with many theaters, right?
They're separate rooms numbered as theatre #1 and theatre #2 and such, right?
That's right! And sometimes, a theater that shouldn't be there appears!
Never ever enter that theatre!
If you enter, something dreadful will happen to you!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
The Phantom Theater Room 0