Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 16 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Now is our time!
The beach is pretty nice at night, too.
Alright, let's go for a swim!
Hey, wanna go race to those buoys?
No problem!
Loser buys us all ice cream!
You got it!
See you later!
Hey, just be careful out there.
No worries at all!
Huh?! What's that?
W-What is this?
Hey!
No way!
What are those hands?!
Someone! Someone help!
They're both going to drown! No!
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
Summer is the season for going to the beach!
However, danger lurks beneath even while you're having fun at the beach.
There are places in the ocean where humans should never trespass.
And one should be especially careful at night as well.
A Deadly Swim in the Ocean
A popup store selling Hokkaido milk ice cream just opened in Sakura Seaside Mall.
I wonder which flavor I should get.
Whoa, what's with that line?
That store sure is popular.
We'd might as well line up.
W-What? Wait a sec, Natsume.
That line isn't for ice cream!
That's...
Ayame?
Himeaya is so cute!
Looking really good!
Want to come play with us?
So it wasn't a line for ice cream. It's a line for Ayame.
That's amazing.
Please give me an autograph!
Please shake my hand!
Can you take a selfie with me?
Ah? An autograph?
Me too! Me too!
That seems kind of troublesome.
Alright. In that case...
I've brought her here!
Sorry for the sudden visit.
You're always welcome!
Ayame, you're a member of the Yo-kai Detective Agency, after all.
Thank you.
H-Have this.
It's the Yo-kai Detective Agency membership badge.
This seems so official!
Did we have membership badges before?
Nah. This is the first I've heard of this.
Since when did he make that?
Fatty's such a try-hard.
Isn't that right.
If there's anything you want to know,
just ask me!
If you need anything, Natsume, just ask me!
You're kinda just copying his shtick.
It's a little modest, but please. Please. Have a seat.
Thank you. But there's no need to be so polite.
We're both equals, after all.
Of course!
What are you doing, Touma?
Huh? Oh...
This is an online bulletin board concerning supernatural phenomena occurring
within Sakura Motomachi. This site takes no responsibility for any of the
content published here, even in the case of any harm or trouble that may result.
Post
Usuranura
A website about the supernatural
That's...
That's Usuranura!
U-Usura...What?
Usuranura! It's a forum for posting about Yo-kai related phenomena and urban legends from all around the world.
We check it every day for mysterious incidents to solve.
Huh? Mysterious incidents?
Is it scary?
Ayame... do you dislike scary things?
Nah! It actually sounds fun!
I know, right?!
Well, since we can both see Yo-kai and love solving incidents, I think we'll get along just fine.
That's right!
Fatty's disgusting.
You can say that again.
This is an online bulletin board concerning supernatural phenomena occurring
within Sakura Motomachi. This site takes no responsibility for any of the
content published here, even in the case of any harm or trouble that may result.
Post
Usuranura
A website about the supernatural
There's a new post.
What did you say?!
In other words, now is the time for us to act!
Alright, everyone, let's do this!
-He's getting all worked up for no reason.
What kind of incident is it this time?
Umm...
Multiple pale-colored hands emerging from the ocean?
Huh? What do they mean?
"The arms had a strange glow and pulled my friend into the ocean."
"The Sakura Triangle of Terror."
So it's an area like the Bermuda Triangle?
W-What is that?
The Bermuda Triangle is a monstrous triangular area of ocean.
Many ships and planes that pass through it encounter mysterious accidents or sudden storms.
They wind up sinking or crashing as a result.
A-A monstrous triangular area?
So something just as dreadful is now close to home.
How scary.
Ayame, no need for you to get worked up.
That's because we'll solve this case!
But I'm so curious!
I know, right?!
Alright!
Let's move, agents!
At the time, I thought we were goners.
We got pulled in by something in the ocean.
When we woke up, we found ourselves on the beach.
We found that there were others who had the same experience in that area.
We also took footage of the those pale-blue hands.
Footage?
Ayame, you don't need to see it if you're scared.
I want to look at it!
Of course.
Please show us the video!
See you later!
Hey, just be careful out there.
No worries at all!
Huh?! What is that?
-You shall not pass!
Huh?! What is this?
Begone!
-What is this?
Damn!
No!
T-There really were pale hands!
By the way, did you hear the other voice?
Yeah. "You shall not pass" and "begone," it said.
Scary.
Ayame, maybe this is too much...
But I'm super curious!
Of course!
Alright, let's go to that beach tomorrow!
Seriously?!
It's dangerous!
It's probably best if you don't go out into the ocean there.
The tidal currents there are very strong.
Grandma!
Huh?
How's my style?
What is with those clothes?!
Since I'm going to be investigating an incident at the beach with Ayame, I thought I should go in this outfit.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
Ow!
You're being way too cheerful, idiot!
It's the perfect weather for a swim!
It sure is!
But having said that...
Did everyone forget their swimsuits?
It's not like we came here to swim.
I thought we're just here to investigate.
I got really cheerful and then Grandma hit me.
Since you've already came all this way here, might as well have some fun.
O-Of course!
Ta-dah!
It really suits you!
Is that really so?
Akinori is in high spirits.
Fatty's face and tummy are both a mess.
I've also come prepared, Natsume!
This one's in high spirits, too.
Looks like Akinori's having fun.
For real.
Even after hearing that horrible story, he sure seems eager to go into the water.
Oh, I get it!
You didn't bring your swimsuit because you're scared of the ocean.
You're a coward!
No no no!
It's because they said that the currents here can get really strong.
They said something about it at school, I think...
Natsume, are you not swimming, too?
Nah... Just seeing those two in there is enough ocean for me.
For sure.
We've waited this long, but nothing out of the ordinary is happening.
Sorry about that. Even though we came to investigate, I wound up having too much fun.
No worries! It's fine!
There were others who were having much more fun.
That's right.
Today was the best day ever.
I got Ayame all to myself.
I wonder if it made everyone else jealous seeing me and Ayame being lovey-dovey like this.
I should go home while things are still going well.
Hey! Why don't we begin investigating now?
Of course! That's what I was gonna do all along!
Will those two be alright by themselves?
Akinori firmly insisted on going by themselves.
Wait, isn't that Akinori's smartphone? Why are you using it, Keisuke?
Ayame wanted me to record the two of them together.
Well, that settles that.
The ocean feels nice at night.
I know, right?
And it looks like we're moving ahead just fine.
Looks like they're moving at a pretty fast pace.
Don't get too close to those buoys, you two!
They're being pushed out!
Whis?
The witnesses warned us about the strong currents around here yesterday.
That's right! They warned us about that in school, too!
What?!
Ayame! Akinori!
Come back here this instant!
What is that?!
What is this?!
SHADOWSIDE
They're here!
It's those bluish-white hands!
Ayame! Akinori!
What do we do?!
Leave it to me!
Akinori, you're amazing!
It isn't really a big deal...
Akinori!
Stop it!
Huh? Ayame, what did you do just now?
Something happened?
I trained for so many years to be able to do that...
That just now...
That's the same as Akinori's magic!
Whis?
There's more coming!
None shall pass!
Begone!
This voice is just like the one in that video!
Uh-huh.
We must help!
Leave it to me! Micchi Jump!
Argh! There's something sticky and slimy underwater!
There's something in here for sure!
Those arms must belong to a larger being under water!
Micchi! Bring Ayame and Akinori over here!
Leave it to me!
That was scary...
Are you okay, Ayame?
Yeah.
What was in the water?
I couldn't get a good look, but it was quite slippery. Or was it both slippery and slimy?
The Yo-kai Energy Radar also picked it up.
And it looks pretty huge, too!
And it's under the water in front of the buoys.
That must be the rest of whatever is moving those arms.
It'd be bad to get too close, especially since the current is so strong.
Maybe there's a connection between those two things?
Perhaps it's using the current to draw in and consume prey more easily!
No. I think its intention is something else.
If its goal was to hunt prey, there'd be no reason to warn people by saying "Begone" or "You shall not pass."
I see...
Certainly.
Then what is it trying to do?
Help! Stop! Stop it!
Those guys were staring at us before!
Why are they there?
Perhaps those fellows were swimming after Himeaya as well?
We must save them!
Hold on.
Seems like our foe is a Yo-kai, so just leave it to us.
Uh-huh.
My turn first!
Huh?
It's too far away!
Fatty's useless. Good for nothing.
Don't call me useless!
Stop it! Stop it!
I'll handle this!
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune! Lend me your strength!
Yoshitsune has arrived.
Get away while you can!
Yeah!
They're relentless!
Then all we need to do is find its body and strike it!
I see it.
There you are!
Touma!
Is he going to be okay?
GESO!
I-It's a squid?!
It's not just any squid, it's some sort of kraken Yo-kai!
So it has finally shown its slimy self!
Yeah.
Touma!
Good thing you're not hurt!
Alright, it's my turn now!
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
Huh?
Wagh! The heck is this?!
Don't summon me near water!
I'm a cat who hates getting wet, don't you know!
Wait... Jibanyan?!
No way! No way! Ask someone else!
He left...
Dang, what a freewheeling fellow.
Yo-kai are really something.
He's a special case.
We're not done yet!
Summoning!
Shadow!
(Ripping)
Come on out, my friend! Kirisaki Joker!
Let's get chopping!
What's kraken?
How about a mushroom cut for you?
G-Geso?
GESO?!
It's a squidding mushroom cut!
It's a mushroom cut!
Geso! Geso... Geso...
Geez...
I didn't do anything wrong!
Why'd you cut me all of a sudden? Grr! Grr!
Grr! Grr!
-It seems kinda angry.
-But it's cute!
-For real!
What's your name?
Ikarin.
Ah! It's turning red!
You feeling embarassed?
T-That's not ink!
I'm beaking mad! I'm Ikarin, after all! Grr Grr!
Ikarin, why are you so angry?
Because...
Back then, before I became a Yo-kai, I was just an ordinary squid...
That's hilarious! This squid is so stretchy! Come look!
Wanna barbecue it?
This one's too small to be tasty.
I got myself bullied by these huge humans.
I see.
So you were trying to drown people as revenge, right?
You're wrong, fatty! I would never do something like that!
I was trying to save people from getting swept away by the current!
"Begone! None shall pass!" I tried warning them!
Huh? was that so?
The current flows around here are difficult to navigate!
Especially the currents around that buoy!
It doesn't matter how well you swim, you'll get swept out to sea for good!
I see.
So you've been grabbing people who swim to those buoys.
And then you take them over to another beach away from here.
I've tried my best to squid them away, but people are aways coming!
It's dangerous here!
But why are you helping us?
You were bullied by humans. Don't you resent us?
Well, that's because...
After being bullied by those huge humans, I couldn't move.
Are you okay?
I was saved by a small human.
Cheer up, squiddy!
I'll bring you back to the ocean.
But...
But when that small human tried to bring me back to the ocean...
When he got near the buoys, he was carried away by the current.
I waited for a long time, but the small human never returned.
I poked my head through the water to get a better look.
But my body dried up and gave in.
I died right next to the buoy, just like that.
Before I knew it, I became a Yo-kai.
So you've been making sure that others don't wind up getting swept away just like that boy.
Squid is so admirable!
Wait...
Is that so...?
I'm sorry.
I never knew you felt that way.
Huh...?
Ayame...
Ayame is such a kind person!
H-Hey!
The kid who saved you... isn't this person by any chance, is he?
"Child carried away by currents while swimming with a squid rescued without injury."
Ah! That's right! That's the human!
Keisuke, how did you find that article?
He's a first-grader at my school, actually.
That's why my school warned us about the ocean currents around here.
I see.
Thank goodness!
He was okay!
Ikarin...
That sure was one troublesome squid, though.
Its light side is pretty cute, but I can't say much for it's shadow side.
It was scaring people on purpose so they don't get swept out to sea.
That might be right.
I sure was surprised that Ayame can use the same magic that I can.
I wonder how she's able to use it.
It must mean that me and Ayame are destined for each other.
Whatever.
We're continuing our report on multiple incidents of missing people.
Since last week, around Sakura Motomachi,
young men are going missing one after another.
MULTIPLE DISAPPEARANCES IN SAKURA MOTOMACHI
According to a statement by the police...
-Men are...
Ayame!
Sorry!
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Yo-kai Watch Movie News!
Preorder tickets for "Yo-kai Watch: Forever Friends" are now on sale!
This time, I've got something special to tell you all!
Nekomata
First, my special skill is sleeping.
And my hobby is sleeping.
My strong point is that I'm able to sleep anywhere.
That's all!
I want you to see me do something in the movie...
Do you even do anything?!
Did all of you preorder your tickets yet?
My Yo-kai Ark is included with the preorder, and it's on sale now!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
They do fortune telling from ouija boards.
I've heard of it. Everyone puts their finger on a 10-yen coin.
"Spirits oh spirits please come on out," they'd chant.
Then a fox spirit is summoned and gives a fortune.
But lately, the fox spirits being summoned have been quite dangerous.
They say that people being attacked!
Let's ask Kyubi about these foxes.
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
The Cursed Fox and the Ouija Board
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs