Youkai Watch Shadow Side: Revival of the Oni King, 4th Movie English Fansubs
Noroinohanako: Translation/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: Translation/QC/Editing
TSS_Killer: Raws
Thanks to Yo-kai Watch World for additional QC
Source: Blu-ray
There was once a boy who held a wristwatch that could command Yo-kai.
He would make friends with the Yo-kai and fulfill a great many deeds.
But when the boy grew up to become a fine adult,
he lost his ability to see Yo-kai.
And as for the wristwatch that could control Yo-kai,
its existence threatened to disturb the balance between the human and Yo-kai worlds,
so it was casted away into the oblivion beyond time and space.
Soon, the story of the Yo-kai controlling wristwatch...
...became but a legend.
But then, something took place after many, many months and years had passed...
"Are you still asleep, Touma?"
"We had to stay at work overnight."
"Sorry we couldn't come home."
"We're probably going to be late today, so feel free to order a pizza."
Again, huh?
The mysterious comet that is currently a topic of tremendous interest,
given the moniker "Y" by the public,
finally became visible to the naked eye overnight.
This is the first time this particular comet has come close to the Earth in thousands of years,
and since the last scientific obeservations of its characteristics,
its approaching speed has hastened immensely.
This mystery has commanded the attention of astronomers around the world.
Just my luck! I'm gonna be late!
I'm just gonna miss the bus!
What's happening?
Grab this!
Hey, what are you doing?!
He's drowning! I have to help him!
Stop! It's dangerous!
You'll die, too...
You're okay now!
Are you alright?
Yeah...
Tomo!!
What's the matter? What happened to you?!
Oh, Tomo, you can't...
You can't be saved...
Someone saved me then, too...
I wonder if I hallucinated it...
...but that was what inspired me to do this...
Natsume!
Saki!
What happened? You're totally soaked!
Hey, you weren't saving someone from drowning this early in the morning, were you?
Huh? Well, yeah, kinda...
Well, are you going to school?
Yeah. I guess I'll just change in the clubroom when I get there...
But I can't ride the bus like this,
so I'll have to walk.
I see.
Okay, I'll tell the teacher that you're gonna be late.
But hurry, okay? If you don't, you'll catch a cold.
Thanks!
Woah...that's a...
Oh, crap! This isn't good!
This really isn't good!
This is serious!
Something's happening!!
What's going on, Akinori?
Aren't you supposed to be going to school?
Forget about that, Grandma!
Look at the sky!
Th...That's...!
I've never seen something like that before.
It definitely can't be good, can it?
Indeed...it's truly terrible.
It is...
What? What is it?
The Onimaro! The Onimaro are coming!
Whaaaat? The Onimaro?!
...Wait, what are the Onimaro?
You're a member of the Arihoshi family, whose magic has been passed down to you,
and yet you don't know of the Onimaro?
They're those white, fluffy, delicious things, right?
And when you bite into them, you can taste the tender syrup...
Ooh, it's just too much!
...Those are marshmallows!
Ow!
I shouldn't have to explain each and every thing to you!
So what are the Onimaro that are headed toward us?
They will...bring about the destruction of the world!
That moon is the harbringer of doom!
Good morning!
Listen, Akinori.
Those Onimaro are tremendously terrifying beings.
The only thing that can strike back at them has existed in this country since ancient times.
It's the power of Yo-kai!
Yo-kai?
In order to use the power of Yo-kai...
I know already! You need the Yo-kai Watch, right?
It's a device that was created so that humans could summon Yo-kai.
That's right. However...
...the rulers of the kingdom in the Yo-kai world decided that it was to be disposed of,
so it is now near impossible to obtain.
So...we're done for?
Not quite. Contrary to what we have always known,
a different type of Yo-kai Watch does in fact exist.
What?
It was created by those who lived in ancient times.
Since the dawn of time, that Yo-kai Watch created by those ancient peoples
has closed the gap between humans and Yo-kai.
Even today, that watch is still out there somewhere.
Woah...a Yo-kai Watch created in ancient times...
If we can find it, we might be able to relieve ourselves of this danger.
For that...you'll need this.
If you use this Yo-kai Energy Radar that I created,
it will respond to...
It will detect the Yo-kai Watch!
Hey, wait! Akinori!
Just leave this to me, Grandma! I'm gonna track down that Yo-kai Watch!
Ugh...hey!
This should be interesting!
Just you wait for me, Yo-kai Watch!
The Movie
Shadowside:
Revival of the Oni King
Nobody has come.
But I know I called them here. What's the meaning of this?
It seems that the ministers
still do not recognize you as their new king, Lord Kaira.
So they still insist on following that Enma, do they?
Even though you brought the seven sages over to your side to usurp the king's throne,
none of the Yo-kai of the Yo-kai world
approve of you, Lord Kaira.
It's always Enma this, Enma that with them...
Is that you, Nurari?
Are you unharmed, my lord?
Yes. Don't worry about me.
Nurari, the Onimaro have gone to the Earth 300 years too early.
At this rate, the Yo-kai world will...!
Though there is a way that we can repel them...
With the Yo-kai Watch, right?
But all of the watches in the Yo-kai world have been destroyed.
There is another Yo-kai Watch.
The mysterious treasure created by the Genyou tribe,
the Elders' Black Magic Mirror,
contains a greater power than the Yo-kai Watch we know.
So it's a Yo-kai Watch created by the ancients?
Where is it?
Fear not. We already have it.
We reconfigured it into the Yo-kai Watch Elder.
However, the Elder itself has not accepted a human yet,
so we currently cannot use it.
Now go, Nurari.
Yeah. That guy looks good.
Sniff, sniff...he stinks.
Stinks of darkness, that is.
Let's test him out. Yaaaay.
Hey! Watch where you're goin'!
My bad.
Hey, buddy.
Shouldn't you give us a more sincere apology?
Aww, you're upset that you don't got no date, ain'tcha?
What, are you going to mug me?
Hey now, don't say somethin' so disrespectful.
Now you'll be more careful about what comes outta your mouth.
Only 3000 yen, huh? What are you, broke?
A face like yours just reeks of misfortune.
The garbage heap really suits a guy like you.
It's people like you that are the garbage in the world.
Huh? What'd you say?
I like that face...now!
Let's go!
Yaaaay!
What? You think we'll go easy on ya if you fake being sick?
What the?
Why, you...
This guy's a monster!
What's...happened to me?
What do you think of our power? Cool, isn't it?
What?!
You can do some pretty great things with that power, right?
Just who are you guys?
We're your friends.
Hey, do you wanna make a deal with us?
Yaaaay!
A deal with me? Why?
You carry a very splendid scent of darkness.
Didn't you like having that kind of strength before?
You're strong.
You should make the whole world know you exist.
Show them that I...exist?
My existence...
...throughout my whole life...
...hasn't mattered.
If you let us borrow your body for a little while, we'll give you that power!
What do you think?
Yaaaay.
I'll do it.
It's settled.
So it's him?
He's got a lot of darkness in him.
Indeed...he has a very pleasant aroma. Let's use him.
Don't resist. You will receive us.
Show us all your hatred...
I smell it...I smell it...
Oh...perfect.
Go on, Touma Tsukinami. Show him your strength.
Why are you coming along, Grandma?
I can find it myself.
You're only half a man, you know. I was worried.
Huh? What does that mean?
Well, now what do we do?
When we get close to the Yo-kai Watch,
the Yo-kai Energy Radar will react.
By the way, Grandma, what are the Onimaro like?
They are very, very, very dreadful beings!
Well, I thought they were from another one of those old folktales that you pass down to me,
so I wasn't really that concerned about them...
To put it simply, the Onimaro are like a virus.
They infect spiteful humans to increase their numbers.
Once they finish multiplying for the first time, it is impossible to stop them.
Why is something so awful happening now?
The Onimaro are Kaima that come from the sky once after thousands of years.
They are not extraterrestrial aliens, but extraterrestrial Yo-kai.
Like a group of sharks that gather when they smell blood,
the Onimaro savagely feast upon the hearts of people.
The person's malice becomes more and more intense until they die,
and they keep on committing great offenses.
Not bad!
I knew we'd make a good team.
Yaaaay!
It seems that he will make good use of "it."
Here's a present for you.
A present?
What is this?
That's the Kigan Gear. It's a symbol of our friendship.
Friendship...
And with that, you can control other friends.
Let's test it out. Try controlling that guy you just defeated.
At your command!
He'll do exactly what you tell him to.
Does this suit you?
The Kigan Gear is proof that you're our leader.
You are very dissatisfied in this world
because you don't have enough friends.
None of the humans around you notice you.
You're just like...a shadow.
So that's why you chose me?
That's right.
We seek the kind of gloom that lies in your heart.
Such pure darkness
originates only in genuine hearts, which is why the darkness grows so much.
With that Kigan Gear, you can recruit more comrades and build your own army.
An army?
Right.
And then you can make the whole world know you exist.
With your strength, my lord,
you should be able to destroy that easily.
I apologize for my lateness in meeting you.
Don't worry about it.
More importantly, the invasion by those wicked beings has arrived early. Let us hurry.
Yes, my lord.
Hm...it appears that he has escaped.
Damn that Enma...how annoying.
With all due respect, Lord Kaira,
given the quality of that prison you built,
there's no way that Enma wouldn't be able to destroy it.
Whose side are you on, old man?
The Onimaro's signals have begun to spread.
How do you know?
Those red dots represent where the device detects Onimaro.
Really? Well, what's this?
Hm? A white light...
...Perhaps this response means...
It senses a white butler Yo-kai that gives a Yo-kai Watch to you.
"Ewe?" Baaa.
Right! That's the mild little animal with the bushy fur.
Oww!
Where did you get that from?
"Master, please feel free to give me any order you wish."
That's what we're talking about!
Oh, that...
Now, let's go search for that Yo-kai butler, Akinori.
I can't believe it...
...you really saved a kid from drowning?
I know you like to help people, Natsume,
but you could've died jumping into a river in this cold.
I'm fine. That's because I have this.
Oh, yeah. That's the stone that you got that time you almost drowned, right?
Yeah. It's my protective charm.
Well, see you tomorrow!
Yeah!
I don't remember a road being here...
Really, was this road always here?
This place is strange...I think I might've gotten lost.
What's that?
Wh-Who are you?
This is the 444th person to come through here...
This situation must turn around before long, right?
This guy...
...is kinda weird.
Vertigo?
Is that why you're short of breath?
Yeah, whatever, here you go.
Huh? What is this?
Well then, now that I've regrouped,
let's get started.
Aptitude test, part one. First up: vocal exercise.
Huh? Wh...What?
Listen up, okay? Please repeat exactly what I say.
Come on out, my friend...
...Jibanyan!
What?
Go on, say it!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
Come on out, my friend! Kochijan!
Argh! No, not like that!
You got the general mood down right, but on that last "nyan,"
you need to sound a bit more up to snuff!
What are you talking about? You're annoying!
Oh? But wait! It isn't rejecting you!
Usually, this would be the part where it flies off your wrist.
Hm...could it be...I've found the one?!
You're the legendary hero chosen by the Yo-kai Watch!
None of this has been making any sense to me this whole time!
Well, it's only natural that you wouldn't understand.
There are countless things about the world that you humans do not understand, after all.
You couldn't understand just how gigantic you humans look to a tiny ant.
In other words, to an ant, the human world is the absolute highest dimension.
And there is a greater dimension that is incomprehensible to you humans, too.
That is our world: The Yo-kai world!
Isn't that like...the spirit world or the afterlife?
Hmm...I suppose that is an apt comparison,
but it's actually a little different than that.
Well, here is your final test. Please use this capsule machine.
The last test already?
Enough! Just go and turn that dial.
Huh?
Pop!
What's that?!
So this is what you got, huh?
If you use the Yo-kai Watch
and defeat that guy, you will pass the test. It's easy.
Use the Yo-kai Watch? But how?!
Yes, about that. There are these things called "arks..."
Huh? She's gone.
I'm gonna die!!
I did it!
Hey, you!
What?
Listen closely! I'll tell you how to use the Yo-kai Watch.
That thing is called an ark.
An ark?
Put that inside the Yo-kai Watch and turn it!
It opened! What do I do now?
Light!
Hold the ark over the top of the Yo-kai Watch and shout, "Summoning!"
Wh-What was that?
"Summoning!"
Summoning!
"Come on out, my friend!"
"C...Come on out, my friend!"
"Himojii!"
Smoothie!
You said it wrong! Although your tone was good...
"Himojii!"
Himojii!!
Oh! So that can still be used?
Himojii!
That worked somehow...
So that's the Yo-kai Watch...amazing!
Yo-kai Watch...
Oooooh!
The Yo-kai Watch has finally chosen its new owner!
Da da-da-daaah! Now I...
...have completed my misson!
Wait a minute, are you...the white Yo-kai butler
that manages who gets the Yo-kai Watch?!
Baaa...
Baaa! Indeed, I am the Yo-kai that gives watches to ewe...
Argh! What am I doing?! I'm no sheep, I'm a butler!
Though frankly, I've had that exchange many times over.
I wish it would end. I'm rather tired of it.
Really?
Anyway, let me pull myself together...
I am the highly important person
left in charge of all matters concerning the Yo-kai Watch, Whisper.
So...who are you guys, exactly? You just came out of nowhere.
Oh, of course! Yes, who are you?!
I'm Akinori. This is my grandmother.
We are members of the Arihoshi family, which has been capable sorcery for many generations.
We've been out looking for that Yo-kai Watch.
Say what?! You've been looking for the Yo-kai Watch?!
Nice to meet you! Uh...
Yeah, yeah. I'm Natsume Amano.
Well, here you go. I've got nothing to do with this.
Huh? Why?
Is it really okay?
Um, wait...
Anyone other than the owner the Yo-kai Watch has accepted
cannot wear it!
You must use the Yo-kai Watch
and save the world!
Huh?
The Yo-kai Watch is the link that connects humans and Yo-kai.
You must now borrow the power of Yo-kai to push back the imminent danger threatening the world!
I honestly still have no idea what you're talking about, though...
You mean you haven't heard?
You know, about stuff like armaggedon and the King of Terror?!
I don't believe in things like that.
Well, whether you believe in them or not, the peril is real and it's headed our way!
Peril?
What exactly is coming for us?
Huh?
Hmm...ah...um, um, um...
I'll explain.
They're called the Onimaro.
Onimaro?
They are naturally weak beings,
But by corroding and feasting on the malice present in people's hearts,
they can transform humans into monsters.
Yes, yes, of course! That's it!
That's why, before they run rampant through our world,
they must be stopped.
That's right.
Huh? I don't know what any of that means!
It doesn't matter whether understand what it means or not!
Right now, you are our savior!
That's right! You're the only one that can use the Yo-kai Watch.
You've got to do this! Come on!
Why do you hate this so much?! I wish I could do what you can!
I'm so jealous!!
-This is hopeless.
I can't communicate with these people.
Excuse me. I'm going home now.
Ah! Please wait!
Whisper.
The Onimaro have already chosen the recipient of the Kigan Gear.
You mustn't dawdle.
Y...Yes, sir...understood...
I think I've gone nuts today.
I'm home!
I must've imagined it. Maybe I was just hearing things.
Mom?
Mom? Keisuke?!
D-Don't come closer!
Miss Natsume!!
Take this!
The Yo-kai Watch...
Press the button on the right!
On the right? Uh...
What are these things?
Don't you see? Wicked things have inspirited them!
They have become like that because they are inspirited by the Onimaro.
Miss Natsume! Now is a good time to use the Yo-kai Watch!
What do I do? Should I call that guy from before again?
But Himojii will turn them into dust.
So if we do that, they might die...
I know! We can use that thing you got before!
Natsume!
That one's name is Mitsumatanozuchi.
Try summoning him!
Uh...um...summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Mitsumatanozuchi!
So...was that good enough?
He's shrinking!
This is Mitsumatanozuchi?
He looks pretty different from before...
I am Mitsumatanozuchi. But when I am in this form,
you may call me Micchi!
Micchi?
Micchi!
She took to that name easily!
Those are my mother and my younger brother! Please help them!
Not a problem!
Micchi Beam!!
Task completed!
It seems you've petrified them.
Mom! Keisuke!
Well, it seems like this won't do any harm for the time being.
So...Yo-kai change like this when they get summoned?
Not quite. There's a number of reasons for transforming.
In my case, I become like this...
...because when I'm a beast-like Yo-kai,
I just wish to turn into an active-looking humanoid.
Oh, really?
Well, see you.
He took off.
Mom...Keisuke...
So...what should we do now?
Unfortunately, we don't know how to save the people
inspirited by the Onimaro.
No way...
But do you know what all this means now?
This is the danger that the world now faces.
In order to save everyone, you'll have to make friends with Yo-kai
and get rid of all the Onimaro.
That's exactly right!
So fight alongside us, Miss Natsume!
Okay. I'll give it a shot.
Thank you so much!
Ugh...why did this all have to happen?
So that's the girl chosen by the Yo-kai Watch?
Yes. Though I wonder why it chose her, of all people...
Indeed.
Nurari. Those Onimaro are certainly troubling, but their appearance
means the resurrection of someone even more worrisome than them.
(Demon)
Oni King Rasen, right?
Correct. When the Onimaro consume all of the gathered malice,
their power increases and they form the dreadful king of all oni.
He is known as our worst enemy in Yo-kai history.
We must hurry. To the Cavern of Dreams!
Right!
Oh, Touma. Everyone is beginning to admit to you.
Yeah.
But you must not be satisfied with this.
Make your existence even more known than it is now!
Make my existence known...
First...
...how about bringing your new order to being among the people?
New order?
Here's the place! Yaaaay!
The police?
Crime just keeps increasing no matter how hard the police try.
With the Kigan Gear,
you can control the police. What do you think?
We can find criminals
and you can bring down punishment upon them in the name of justice. Sounds good, right?
I can...
Yep. You can take out the trash in society.
Mission complete.
I'm here.
Now I have an impact on society.
I'm not a shadow anymore.
The Onimaro are multiplying at an incredible rate.
We need to hurry.
What is this big dot?
I dare say that's the Onimaro's leader.
Their leader?
The leader mobilizes the Onimaro in an organized fashion.
That person seem to be the cause of their multiplying.
So if we take down the leader...
Don't be foolish! We can't defeat someone taken over by the Onimaro
just like that, you know...
Then what do we do?
We use the Yo-kai Watch.
You can call powerful Yo-kai to fight for us.
Perhaps we can win that way.
Micchi Beam!!
Himojii!!
Himojii has the ability to dry things up,
and Micchi can turn them to stone, right?
For the record, my petrification powers are not very effective against high-level enemies.
It's utterly useless against boss-like foes!
You're showing off about your total uselessness?
It would help if we had a Yo-kai on our side that was strong in battle...
Well, looks like there's no other choice, then!
I don't really want to see him again,
but I think we should try and locate an acquaintance of mine.
Let's see...just what is that Jibanyan up to right now?
What? Did you say Jibanyan?!
You know Jibanyan, the legendary cat Yo-kai
who has been said to have defeated countless great demons?
That guy has gained a reputation for such active feats?
Well, it seems that I can't get in touch with him,
so for now we'll have to try and meet up with him at a certain spot.
A certain spot?
This is called "The Evil Intersection," isn't it?
There are a lot of accidents here. It's like a cursed intersection.
For sure.
However, some of the accidents that occur here are unusual.
Sometimes trucks get crushed flat, you see.
What?!
What kind of Yo-kai is Jibanyan?
Well, basically, he's red and round-shaped...
There he is!
Huh? That's him?!
Aaah! Help me!!
Hold it!!
I will protect Miss Natsu -
Who are you lot?!
This is Jibanyan? He seems like pretty bad news!
He's certainly changed quite a bit from the Jibanyan I know...
Jibanyan! These bad Yo-kai called the Onimaro
are occupying the city!
Please help us fight them!
I've got nothin' to do with this.
You have to do something! We beg of you!
Then let's make a deal.
I want two tons of chocolate in return.
Two tons?!
That's impossible!
Then this negotiation ain't happenin'!
I will protect Miss Natsu -
Damn it! I was afraid of something like this happening!!
Thank you, Jibanyan.
And thank goodness.
Nyow I've got nyo choice.
What is there here in the Cavern of Dreams?
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
The Fudou Raimei Ken.
No way...we can use the legendary sword to defeat Rasen?
That's right.
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
But the Fudou Raimei Ken
was sealed by the Yo-kai world's most powerful sages in their most desperate moment.
Even you will not be able to free it so easily, my lord!
What we face threatens to cause the destruction of both the human and Yo-kai worlds.
I must take any risks necessary to protect them.
No matter what might happen to me.
My lord...
Enma!
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
So you intend to get the Fudou Raimei Ken?
Perhaps. What of it?
Sorry, but that sword is mine.
So you've come to get in our way again? Even on top of usurping the king's throne!
You must understand this, Kaira.
Rasen is going to destroy the world.
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
With the Fudou Raimei Ken,
I can control Rasen.
You cannot use power as great as his.
Really, now?
My lord!!
Don't get involved, Nurari!
I suppose I'll just have to settle the score with you.
You're always so cool!
You've always been such a nuisance to me!!
Without you around,
I will be recognized as king!
The reason why you aren't the true king isn't because I am here!
You speak nonsense!!
Everyone! I want you to make even more people obey me!
We will be moving on to the next step soon.
The next step?
We will occupy the airport and fly around the world with our friends.
So we're going to rule over the whole world?
Yes! Sounds fun, doesn't it?
Sure does.
We will commence our raid on the airport immediately!
What's wrong, Touma?
Are you not feeling well?
The revolution begins now...
I will make the whole world know...I exist...
Is this where that leader controlled by the Onimaro is?
Seems that way.
Let's enter through the back.
Ow...
Drat! They noticed us!
-Idiot!
Leave them to me!
Awesome! Way to go!
I got the password to the controller system.
Now the airport is mine.
Is that...Touma?
Seems like he's the leader.
You're kidding!
Well...
...I can sense a dreadfully evil air coming from him.
Touma...
You know him?
Yeah. I don't know if he remembers me, but...
If we kill him, we can stop the Onimaro, right?
Kill him?!
Well, he has a point...
No! We can't!
Although you say that, I don't see another way...
Uh-oh! We're in trouble!
They're gonna kill us!!
Don't hide. Why don't you come on out?
Oh, it's you....what are you doing here?
I should be the one asking you that, Touma!
What happened that made you do this?
You were always a really kind person, Touma!
Ow...
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm kind?
Don't you understand?
Nobody cares that I exist!
Even my mother and father...
...So I'm going to show them I exist...
I'll make them all know...that I'm here!!
Oh, no! That's...!
Um, um, um...the Kigan Gear!
So that's the guy the king was talking about when he mentioned a chosen one!
Capture them all!
Jibanyan!
What's with his arms?
Why, you...!
Jibanyan!
It's not over yet!
Natsume, use this!
Kyuubi?
I got it from our storehouse.
I guess you can say this is like a garage sale.
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Kyuubi!
Alright! That's Kyuubi for you!
Playtime is over!
Oh no, oh no...
We've been locked up!
Why are you so persistent in taking up the mantle of king?
The Yo-kai world despises me because I am made of both human and Yo-kai blood!
They've never accepted me!!
The circumstances of your birth are not the reason for that!
It's because you are filled with darkness!
(Demon)
I will gain control over the Oni King Rasen
and become renowned by everyone!
Rasen will take advantage of the darkness in your heart!
He is a terrifying being that can destroy others from the inside!
You, with all of your pent-up darkness, will fall under his control!
Don't bother saying such silly things!
I can obtain his power!
Open your eyes already...
...Kaira!
Awakened form, huh?
Looks like this is as far as my strength takes me...
To you, I'm nothing but a traitor. Just kill me.
But if only you could improve your skills...
I don't need your pity.
I've come to understand your feelings after fighting you.
Let's go together, Kaira!
I'm afraid that the Fudou Raimei Sword...
...can't be pulled out by myself alone.
And even if I could do it, it might even take over my body.
If that happens, I need you and Nurari to strike me down.
Looks like we're trapped.
Natsume. Take this.
It's a memento from my mother.
What kind of ark is this?
It's Komasan.
We've kept him at the shrine since long ago.
They say he used to be a dog named Nobushige.
He was pinned down under a fallen komainu statue and became a Yo-kai.
Hmm...
Let's try it!
Uh-huh.
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out, my friend! Komasan!
Oh! That's Komasan!
Wow!
Komasan! Get us out of here!
Are you trapped or something?
That's right. We want you to break this barrier.
Easier said than done. I have no idea how.
Whaaat?
N-No way...
Can't you do anything?
What?
Pee. ♪
Huh?
Mongee! What kind of pee can dissolve a barrier?!
We did it!
That's Komasan for you!
Touma?
Does it hurt, Touma?
What the heck is happening?
Does it hurt?
Such a strong rejection reaction must mean that...
...you have an extremely pure heart deep down.
Ah...this one's outlived his usefulness.
I've...outlived my usefulness, you say?
I have just the perfect way to end my disappointment in you.
Wait! Let us finish him off!
That's right! Leave it to us.
That's right! Yay!
You dare to oppose me?
T-That's wrong! That's not right...
You are an eyesore.
Ahh?
What were you trying to do?
Touma!
These guys...
...are my friends.
What?
Touma! Touma!
Touma!
What did you do to him?
Don't tell me...you're the one that's been manipulating Touma?
I will protect Miss Natsume!
Ouch!
Come on, Touma! Touma!
Ugh... Natsume.
Micchi! Take care of Touma.
Roger that!
Humans are so mysterious.
That's right! Mysterious!
Touma is mysterious! Yay!
My lord!
It's no good.
The seal can't be easily broken even if I try to pull it out by force.
Then let's do it together.
You fools.
Why do you desire my power?
Why?
Answer me. Why do you desire my power?
To fight a foe who is even stronger!
Is that so? Then I will lend you no power.
Begone.
My lord.
Huh. A refusal like that isn't enough to discourage me.
When I say I shall take something, I will take it.
Touma! Touma!
What? Who's that?
It's Lord Enma!
Enma?
As expected of Lord Enma!
That will last for just an hour.
Don't tell me you're the Lord Enma?!
Huh? You mean the guy who's the gatekeeper of Hell?
That Enma?
You look a lot more handsome than I imagined.
It appears that a much older representation has been more established.
Lord Enma!
Is there any way to get this off of Touma?
To remove the Kigan Gear...
...we must cut off the darkness that is corrupting his mind.
To do that, we must enter his mind.
What?
However, the magic used to enter one's mind does not exist in the Yo-kai world.
Now what do we do?
Oh. There is a way.
Magic that affects the human heart exists!
Grandma, do you know?
Yes. There is a story of a certain person passed down within our family.
Kitaro.
Kitaro?
Kitaro of the Ghost Tribe, I see.
They were a tribe that walked the earth before even humanity existed.
Kitaro is the last remaining descendant of this tribe.
Kitaro could still be able to use the magic to enter a human's mind.
I've heard that Kitaro is humanity's ally, and is able to understand them.
If we can't do it, you humans should seek his help.
But how do we find him?
In the Gegege Forest.
Where is that?
At night, a lantern-lit tunnel within Kiritachi Mountain appears.
However, you must be worthy to pass through it.
Worthy of what?
You must be someone in true need of Kitaro's powers.
Is this Gegege Forest?
It's kinda creepy.
Look at that...!
What's this...?
You can meet Kitaro after putting a letter in the "Yo-kai Mailbox."
That's what Grandma said.
So does that mean this is the Yo-kai Mailbox?
We should be careful about corresponding by letter.
Let's write one immediately!
What are we supposed to write?
You guys!
Who are you?!
They're suspicious ones, aren't they?
We're surrounded!
Let's take them for all they have!
These people...
Don't tell me...
...that one of these guys is Kitaro?
Is that so?
Which one?
Doesn't the "taro" in the name imply that he is a male?
That means...
What?!
That leaves two of them.
This one looks like a "taro," right?
And look at that! The "gold" mark!
The "kin" for gold comes before...
Taro!
And this guy's head is split down the middle. It looks dented like a rotten kiwi, right?
Oooh! The "ki" in "kiwi" sounds like the "ki" in "Kitaro."
I think we can say that this guy is Kitaro for sure!
Hey, hey, hey...!
Too bad for you, but I'm the real Kitaro!
For real?
Is that so?
What?
Kitaro, sir, we have a request for you.
Please!
As I'm sure you're well aware...
...even making a request costs money.
You'll need to pay me a good amount.
Huh?! We're supposed to pay you?
Kitaro's stingy!
Just how much will it cost?
There's a special bargain price I can offer just for you.
I'll need at least 300,000 yen...
300,000 yen?!
Err...
(Ratman)
Nezumi-Otoko. You still trying to scam people?
Ah! No, no... I'm not scamming anyone at all!
You can't be too careful!
The heck?!
That eyeball talked!
Hey! Calling me "eyeball" is rude!
Well...they're not wrong.
Kitaro. These suspicious people intruded into our territory.
So is this one the real Kitaro?
Seems like it.
Hey, Kitaro!
These guys don't seem to be like one of us!
These two look like normal human beings, but...
There's a Yo-kai with them, too.
Who are you people?
So that's why...
Please.
Please lend us some help.
Oh! What's happening?
He grew hair!
The influence of Kitaro's aura must have transformed me somehow!
Kita-nyan
That's Kitaro's formidable power for you.
I understand. Let's go together.
Huh? Is that okay with you?
You have a friend you need to save, right?
Hey, hey...
I might be able to stop the Onimaro's power.
Find the rest of the hiding humans!
This isn't enough to revive Lord Rasen!
Gegege!
The corruption of his malice has advanced quite a lot.
At this rate, he's doesn't even have a day left.
No way...
Dad. I sense a strong power.
It seems like the source is wrapped around his arm.
If we can separate that, we could save him.
However, this thing is dug right into the core of his spirit!
What should we do?
We must enter his world and then remove the darkness within his heart!
Enter his world...?
Within his memories, there is a cause for his darkness to form.
We must jump into that time and place.
The darkness there must be dealt with.
Please save Touma.
Alright.
But the one saving him won't be me.
Huh?!
The person entering his memories must be someone who is also in his memories.
I'll do it.
Does he know you?
Yes. I think...
Then how would we go about saving Touma?
I will send you over to his world.
You will erase the darkness you find there.
But if there is no goodness left inside of him...
...then both of you might perish.
If we don't do this, then even his soul will be consumed!
I'll do it. I will do anything to save him!
Let's go!
Yes.
So this is Touma's world.
"We'll be home late. Go ahead and eat first. -Mom."
Are you home alone?
I'm alone. Nobody cares about me.
That's not true.
There are people who care about you.
Hmph. You wouldn't know about that.
You know nothing about me.
Of course I do. I've known you since you were a kid.
Whats wrong? Someone's at the door. Go.
It's the mailman. There's no need for me to go.
He's so annoying! He should think that nobody's home!
Mailman, huh...?
Touma, don't you remember? On your birthday?
Or when you got sick and had to stay home from school?
Every time, you thought it was the mailman.
Yeah. He's always knocking on the door so loudly.
But you were wrong the whole time.
It wasn't the mailman at all.
Open the door and see for yourself.
Natsume!
I live close to your house, so I thought I'd give you a birthday present!
You came over for my birthday?
Uh-huh! Of course!
Ta-dah!
Happy birthday, Touma!
Happy birthday!
Thank you, everyone!
Touma! We play together more from now on!
Because you're always coming home alone.
Are you okay with me?
Uh-huh.
What's this...?
If only you'd have opened the door that day...
...you would've been smiling just like that.
There must have been a reason...
...why your mom and dad couldn't come home that day.
Next Generation DNA
Research Institute
Mafuyu!
It's Touma's birthday today. We've got to go home.
But...
Chief! Please wait...
This research depends on the presentation tomorrow!
We need more data if it is to go well.
But we promised our child that we would spend his birthday together.
We've worked on this research for ten years.
If this research succeeds...
...we could save many people suffering from incurable diseases.
All of that depends on what happens tonight, Chief!
Mafuyu, he'll come to understand.
Even if he won't understand now, when he's an adult...
...he will feel tremendous pride for us.
Dear...
Your mother and father remembered their promise to you after all.
If only you'd have came home that day.
Wait!
Open that door.
The answer you've been waiting for is in there.
Touma!
Mom...
Touma. I'm so sorry.
Sorry about everything, Touma.
Mom and I....
...we do research to help save the lives of many people.
We did it. With what we've done, we can save everyone.
You were doing important research, weren't you?
But it took a long time.
And we sacrificed time we could've spent with you.
I'm so sorry, Touma.
So you two don't hate me after all?
What are you saying, Touma?
That's not true at all.
The most important thing to us is you...
...Touma.
Mom! Dad!
I was so lonely.
I wanted to be together with you, after all!
I see. So in my isolation...
...I came to misunderstand my mom and dad's real feelings.
We became so distant...
Mom. Dad. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Now! Kitaro!
Drive the malice away from that strange thing!
Got it, dad.
Wicked thing! Begone!
He should be okay now.
As expected of Kitaro!
Touma, are you okay?
Let's go home now.
Sure.
Are you not going to join the fight with us?
Your enemies are something only you must deal with.
This is as much as we can help you.
What? You don't have to be that stubborn about it...
If we help them, we could earn so much money.
Kitaro.
(Ratman)
Shut up, Nezumi-Otoko!
Alright.
(Daddy Eyeball)
Kitaro, Medama-Oyaji, Thank you so much
Your enemy is no pushover!
Be careful!
Bye!
Thank you, Kitaro!
This is...
What? Again?
That's a new Yo-kai Watch.
I've seen that before in the Yo-kai Codex of Law.
(Seal Orb Mirror)
That's the Ogre Fuujyukyou.
It can summon Yo-kai called Genma.
The name that we shall give to is...
"Yo-kai Watch Ogre."
Yo-kai Watch Ogre...
Touma. You should use it.
Me?
With the powers of that watch...
...you should be able to free the people inspirited by the Onimaro.
Turn the dial to three o'clock.
Possession! Genma Omatsu!
Three o'clock!
And accept that which comes out from within.
Accept...
Lend me your strength!
Omatsu has arrived!
The people are freed from the Onimaro!
Touma! Thank goodness!
Lord Enma?
He's coming.
All Onimaro! Become one with me.
Why aren't we being sucked in?
Strange.
Strange! Yaaay!
(Demon)
That is the Oni King Rasen.
Oni King Rasen?
I look away for just a moment....
...just to come back and see that the human scum have multiplied much too greatly.
I can no longer stand this throbbing within my heart.
Now is the time to create my world!
So my power is still at this level, huh?
He made a throne for himself?
This is not enough. Gather within me, Onimaro!
Touma. Now is the time.
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
You might now be able to use the Fudou Raimei Ken.
Were you able to obtain that sword?
Yes. In a sense.
That's...
A sword?
Well, it's a rock with a sword stuck to it, right?
Or is it a sword with a rock stuck to it?
You've even brought the rock with you?
Enma likes to do things forcefully.
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
It's the legendary holy Yo-kai Sword, the Fudou Raimei Ken.
Touma. Try pulling out that sword.
Yes.
Why do you desire my power?
If you refuse to answer,
I shall cut you down where you stand.
W-What?
Huh?
Why do you desire my power?
B-Because...
Possession! Genma Yoshitsune!
Lend me your strength!
What is he trying to do?!
Yoshitsune has arrived!
If you mean to duel...
...then so be it!
What I desire is not power.
What?
That is the answer to your question.
What I desire is not power.
It is "harmony."
Harmony?
Harmony
Harmony means that all shall live in peace with tranquil serenity.
In order to obtain that, we ask you to briefly entrust us with your sword.
Harmony, is it?
Very well.
Then I shall entrust my power to you.
Alright!
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
This is the Fudou Raimei Ken!
Looks like the sword has acknowledged you as its owner.
Let's go!
Uh-huh.
I've had enough.
What is that?
He's way stronger than before.
Grandma!
Ouch...
I'm fine. It's just that I hurt my back a little.
Micchi! Please take her to a safe place.
No problem at all.
Not good!
Enma and Nurarihyon are...
Oh no...
I will think of a use for you two soon enough.
Witness the end of the world for now.
What do we do?
This is awful...
He's way too strong.
Everyone!
Even if our enemy is strong, we should still fight!
At this rate, everyone will die!
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
And we have the Fudou Raimei Ken.
Besides, I also want to make up for starting this.
That's why I'll fight!
Yeah! That's the spirit!
Even if it's scary, we've got to do it.
If running means death, then we might as well fight.
But we might die!
You can die?
I've died from being crushed beneath a rock before, too.
Life is a fickle thing.
I've only known you for a short time...
...but I'm glad to have made friends with you guys!
Friends? With me?
That's right! We're already friends now, right?
Call me Akinori.
And you can just call me Natsume!
Akinori! Natsume!
Alright!
Let's go!
Oh!
Yo-kai and humans standing hand in hand against me...?
Interesting.
Those are Gashadukoro! And there's three of them!
Possession! Genma Goemon!
Twelve o'clock!
Lend me your strength!
Goemon has come!
Heavenly Beheading Dance!
Touma!
Let's go!
Koma!
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
Falling Dog Rock!
Why did he only attack me?
You're not shaking on purpose, are you?
It's no good! We're no match!
No matter how hard you humans try to attack...
...there is nothing you can do.
We can do it!
Whatever it takes, we will defeat you!
Using everyone's hearts to take over the world...you're the worst!
Human lives are trivial things that disappear like a mere gust of wind.
Oh! A human magic user...
Don't trivialize us! We get things done when we need to!
Possession! Genma Benkei!
Lend me your strength!
Benkei has arrived unannounced!
Serious Sword-Stopping Grab!
With that kind of power...
...you can protect nothing.
Natsume!
Human.
Realize now the transience of your own life.
Natsume!
Your friend has died, just like that.
Is Natsume really dead? For sure?
No way...
Young man. Isn't this result your fault?
Thanks to you, I was able to gain massive power.
You have my thanks.
What did you say?
He's right. This really is all my fault.
This isn't your fault! You were just being manipulated by him!
No.
It was me.
If only I didn't start this.
Am I going to die?
Natsume!
Thanks for saving me!
But you were the one who saved me.
When I was still little...
...while I was being bullied by children...
That's wrong! Stop it!
Ever since then, I've decided to watch over you.
You're a Yo-kai, too?
(Azure Dragon)
Indeed. I am Seiryuu.
This is...
This is my ark.
It's something you've been taking good care of.
And these...
...are my kindred arks.
Use them in your fight.
Alright!
You dared to strike against us!
Now face our counterattack!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out my friends...
(Papa Bolt)
(Blazion)
(Blizzaria)
Fubuki-hime! Meramelion! Raioton!
Friends of my friends are all my friends!
Everybody!
Natsume!
Kaira!
He used up all his energy to save us.
We did it!
Awesome!
Was that no good...?
No. Rasen's armor is now destroyed.
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
Touma, it's time to use the Fudou Raimei Ken.
In order to use the Fudou Raimei Ken in the human world...
...we must tune it first.
Thrust the sword into the Yo-kai Watch Ogre!
(Demon Swordsman Acala)
Possession! Kenbumashin Fudou Myouou!
Lend me your strength!
(Immovable)
Fudou!
(Immovable Sword of Thunder)
Lightning! Thunder! Electric Attack! Fudou Raimei Ken!
(Acala)
Fudou Myouou has arrived!
We did it!
We might be able to defeat him now!
They're fast...
Nurarihyon. I have a request.
Please lend me your energy.
Very well.
Enma!
Kaira.
Join your wavelength with mine!
Alright!
They combined!
Darkness Binding!
What is this?!
Now!
It's useless!
I've already fused with many!
Is that so?
What?
With the Yo-kai Watch Elder's social media functionality,
...we can contact every Yo-kai nationwide all at once!
Calling every Yo-kai nationwide!
Please lend me your strength!
Lightning Thunder Electric Attack!
Lightning
Thunder
Electric
Attack
Iron Hammer Thunder Cut!
We did it!
Even so...
...I will protect everyone!
Touma!
Natsume...
So I guess...
...I got to make up for my actions a bit?
Don't die! Don't!
Sorry. Looks like I can't do that.
You idiot! Don't give up now!
Natsume... Akinori...
Thank you.
For being my friend.
No! No!
Touma!
Touma... Touma...
Don't die, Touma...
We'll use our lives...
We have to part ways for now...
...but let's play again someday!
Yay!
Touma! Thank goodness!
Touma! Touma!
Snow, huh?
It's beautiful.
Enma. I'm sorry.
I'll hand the Yo-kai World back to you.
No.
I'll leave the Yo-kai World in your hands for now.
You are now the official king of the Yo-kai World.
What? What are you planning to do?
There's something new for me to do.
When I'm finished with what I need to do...
... and if you turn out to be a terrible king...
...I will take the Great King's throne back.
Enma...
Whatever you need to do, my lord...
...I, Nurari, will also follow.
Is that so? Very well.
You may come along. But it might be a bit of a long journey.
As you please.
Well then. I leave it to you, Kaira!
Yes. I understand.
Until you return, I will protect the Yo-kai World.
So what do we do nyow?
Maybe I'll go on a journey to expand my territory.
So you're gonna pee all over the place?
From now on, I will be protecting Miss Natsume.
You're way too weak for that.
Well... I'm not that weak!
You're weak.
I'm not weak!
体が宇宙を
karada ga uchuu wo
A body through space
彷徨いながら
samayoi nagara
While wandering
百年前に
hyaku nen mae ni
A hundred years ago
出会ったね
deatta ne
We met
同じ今に生きている偶然だから
onaji ima ni ikiteiru
guuzen dakara
Because we live in the same moment by chance
僕らの証を
bokura no akashi wo
The proof that we're here
記しておこうよ
Shirushite okou yo
Let's make a record of it
いつの間にか人々は
itsu no ma ni ka hitobito wa
Before I realized it, people were
大切な事を忘れてく
taisetsu na koto
wo wasureteku
..forgetting important things
もういちど時を戻り
mou ichido toki wo modori
Turning back time, one more time
純粋とかを探そう
junsui toka wo sagasou
Let's find purity
再び僕らが会う日には
futatabi bokura
ga au hi ni wa
The day when we meet again
きっと真っ白な雪が降る
kitto masshiro na
yuki ga furu
Pure white snow will certainly fall
済んだ静寂
sunda seijaku
A final stillness
しんしんと
shinshin to
Silently passing
決してくれるよ　過ちを
keshite kureru yo
ayamachi wo
I will definitely have it, make no mistake
♪Yo-kai Watch Exercise #1 Gegege no Kitaro Ver.
♪「ようかい体操第一ゲゲゲの鬼太郎Ver.」
Ge ge gegegerapo
Kitaro! Don't tell me those are Yo-kai!
No, no, Dad, we're Yo-kai too!
Anyway, as fellow Yo-kai, let's get along!
youderu youderu youderu youderu
Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming!
youkai deruken derareken
Yo-kai are coming out, coming right out!
youderu youderu youderu youderu
Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming!
youkai deruken derareken
Yo-kai are coming out, coming right out!
rooire rooire nakama ni
Put'em in! Put'em in! Put your friends right in!
Friends are important!
rooire tomodachi daiji!
youkai youkai youkai uocchicchi
Yo-kai! Yo-kai! Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
kai kai kii kii kui kui kei kei
Kai Kai Kii Kii Kui Kui Kei Kei
koi koi youkai uocchi chi
Come on, come on, Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
kyou wa asa kara nebou shita
Somehow once again I overslept today
yume no naka de wa okita no ni
It seems I was just awake inside of my own dreams
doushite asa wa nemuin da?
Why am I feeling so tired this morning?
doushite asa wa nemuin da?!
do wa ha ha!
DWA-HA-HA!
youkai no sei nano ne
sou nano ne
This is the work of a yo-kai, right? That's right!
uocchi! imma nanji?
Watch! What time is it?
Ge ge gegegerapo
Kitaro!
This is fun too, sometimes!
That's right, Dad!
Even though my voice and form have changed, who cares?
Let's have fun dancing, everyone!
youderu youderu youderu youderu
Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming!
youkai deruken derareken
Yo-kai are coming out, coming right out!
youderu youderu youderu youderu
Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming!
youkai deruken derareken
Yo-kai are coming out, coming right out!
rooire rooire nakama ni
Put'em in! Put'em in! Put your friends right in!
rooire tomodachi daiji!
Friends are important!
youkai youkai
Yo-kai, Yo-kai,
youkai uocchi chi
Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
kai kai kii kii kui kui kei kei
Kai Kai Kii Kii Kui Kui Kei Kei
koi koi youkai uocchi chi
Come on, come on, Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
Let's go! Let's go! C'mon!
doushite ano ko ni furareta no
Why did that girl just dump me?
kon nani ikemen nanoni
Even though I'm such a handsome guy?
doushite bokuchan furaretano?
Why did I just get dumped?
doushite bokuchan furaretano?!
do wa ha ha!
DWA-HA-HA!
youkai no sei nano ne sou nano ne
This is the work of a yo-kai, right? That's right!
uocchi imma nanji?
Watch! What time is it?
youderu youderu youderu youderu
Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming! Yo-kai are coming!
youkai deruken derareken
Yo-kai are coming out, coming right out!
youkai youkai
Yo-kai, Yo-kai, Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
youkai uocchi chi!
kai kai kii kii kui kui kei kei
Kai Kai Kii Kii Kui Kui Kei Kei
koi koi youkai uocchi chi
Come on, come on, Yo-kai Watch-chi-chi!
So what was your proposition to us?
Look at this.
Huh? What's that?
There's reports of Yo-kai related incidents in the streets.
Huh.
There's that many?
That's right. And we're here to solve them.
Let's use our Yo-kai Watches!
Why us?
There are people who are too scared to go outside.
We'll be helping those people too.
Together, we'll be able to solve these Yo-kai cases.
We have to do this!
By the way...
...can we bring this guy along, too?
Huh?
Lord Shutendouji, Rasen has been defeated.
Even though he's been flying for 300 years...
The powers of the elderly have their limits.
And I thought such a gaudy show of destruction would have been enough for "the princess" to show her face.
Manji-Hanako
Fansubs