Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 32 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Previously, on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside...
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Farewell, Haruya Sakami.
You were a good lackey until the very end.
[Laughter]
Please hurry, Akinori!
If the spiderweb mark spreads throughout her whole body, she will lose her life.
This is terrible.
People inside the tower are like this, too.
Natsume, we've got to do something.
Uh-huh.
Oh, my.
Eep!
Huh?
That voice!
Have you all come to offer me your souls?
Huh?
[Laughter]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
The Life-Eating Jorougumo
How did she get so big?
Touma, it's time to use Genbu Houtenfu.
Uh-huh.
Possession!
Kenbumajin Genbu!
Genbu!
Lend me your strength!
Meikyoushisui Genbu Houtenfu!
(Clear and serene, Genbu Axe of Law!)
Genbu has now arrived!
[Laughter]
Here's another worthy opponent!
Finally, a chance to test my skills!
He sure seems eager!
His personality appears to change when fighting.
Here I come!
Huh?
He couldn't cut it?
Oh, no!
Not even Genbu Houtenfu can do it?
[Laughter]
Even with that axe, you couldn't even leave a single scratch on my cocoon of webs!
Hmph. Such resilience.
It's no wonder you turned to me for help.
Allow me show you my true strength!
Ah!
[Genbu roaring]
It's an axe made of water!
Incredible!
Here I come!
Eat this!
Taste the sharpness of Genbu Houtenfu, the axe that can split the oceans!
(Lawful Execution Slash!)
Houten Dangoku Zan!
Wh-What is the meaning of this!?
We did it!
What was I doing...?
That's right...
She decieved me into thinking she's the princess.
It appears that Touma Tsukinami and friends have obtained the Genbu Houtenfu.
Douketsu.
Yes?
Where is Jorougumo?
Tch! Such impudence!
We did it!
So this is Genbu's power.
Hmph. It's been a long time since I've felt satisfied by using my full power.
Thank you, Genbu.
I've used too much of his power too suddenly.
What does that mean for Genbu?
I don't think I can summon Genbu for a while.
But we've still got Fudou Myouou and Suzaku.
That's right.
Good. It's time to charge in.
Summoning!
Shadow.
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
[Jibanyan hissing]
Come on out, Komasan!
[Komasan growling]
Let's go, Natsume!
Alright.
Er... Um... What about me?
It's too dangerous for you. Go hide somewhere, okay, Keisuke?
Natsume.
[Laughter]
So you've made it all the way here, huh?
Nya?
Huh?
Wh-What's happening?
Jorougumo's manipulating them with her webs.
Wh-What do we do?
Just leave this to me!
What?
Landing!
And now, Micchi Beam!
Whoa!
They turned to stone!
That's right! Let's do this!
But we should hurry.
Micchi's ability won't last long.
Exactly! My petrification ability lasts only 10 minutes!
So you're only stopping them temporally?
At least we're not hurting anyone.
Good thing your power is harmless.
Muscles is harmless! Nice harmless muscles!
I have some mixed feelings about that.
Huh?
They're relentless.
Micchi Beam!
Natsume! Go on ahead. I'll keep them busy.
Uh-huh.
Micchi's cliché line came right out of a superhero movie.
The characters who say that always die, though.
Muscles is gonna die?
Drat! I just set off a death flag for myself!
Oh, no! Natsume!
Tch! I only killed off one of them.
Hmm?
That brat.
[Giggle]
[Panting]
Where are Sakami and Douketsu?
A lot of energy was drained from them. Maybe they ran away.
Jorougumo is up there.
Alright. Let's go.
Thanks, Jibanyan.
Yeah.
[Laughter]
Jorougumo!
We're going to defeat you and save Ayame!
Let's go!
Posession!
Kenbumajin Fudou Myouou!
Fudou!
Lend me your strength!
(Lighting Strike! Immovable Lighting Sword!)
Raigou Dengeki Fudou Raimei Ken!
(Heaven Acala)
Fudou Myouou Ten has arrived!
Hundred Cat Paws of Fury!
Falling Hound Rock!
[Laughter]
Ora, ora, ora!
Ah!
No good?
Then face the edge of my sword once more!
It's useless! Useless! Useless!
Now it's my turn!
Jibanyan! Komasan!
Damn it! Does Jorougumo have no weaknesses?
Spider is strong.
What?
Huh?
[Laughter]
I have you!
Wow! There's a handsome guy right over here!
What?
Wow! He's super handsome!
Ngh? What a beautiful man!
Give me your soul!
Whoa!
Hmm?
The more I look at you, the more handsome you look!
Before I devour you, let me know your name.
Hmm?
[Junior deflating]
It's Jii!
J...Jii?
Da ze!
Now do it, Junior!
What are you doing?
Fresh Wasabi
Wasa-beam! Da ze!
[Jorougumo shrieking]
My eyes! My eyes!
Shooting wasabi directly into her eyes? That's a sneaky attack.
Good thing you thought of that, Natsume.
Heh. Let's just say that happened to catch my eye.
Hmm?
Huh?
I get it! You had Junior use that billboard as a template.
Fresh Wasabi
C-Curses!
Attack now, everyone!
Alright!
She got smaller!
We did it!
This ends now.
Stop it!
Interfere with me any further,
and who knows what will happen to this one.
[Whimpering]
Keisuke!
Sorry, Natsume.
That's not fair, Jorougumo!
Unfair?
That's so flattering!
There it is! One of those cliché lines said by villains!
Now then.
I shall rejuvenate myself with your energy.
Hgh!
[Laughter]
Touma!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
[Laughter]
Those who oppose me shall regret it as they leave this world!
Huh?
Ugh...
[Yawn]
That was a long sleep.
Huh?
Where am I?
SHADOWSIDE
Hey, answer me!
What is this place?
Umm...
Who are you?
What? You don't know who I am?
Don't forget this time! I am...
...Mega Ultra Super the Strongest, born from the Fudou Raimei Ken!
From the Fudou Raimei Ken?
That's right! I was born from the Fudou Raimei Ken!
Born from...?
Well...
Hey, what was my name again?
That's what we wanted to know!
So Fudou Myouou becomes a kid when his energy is drained?
Huh?
So he's like Fudou Myouou Junior, right?
He can't be Junior! I am Junior! Da ze!
Whis.
How about we call him Fudou Myouou Boy?
You shouldn't really decide for him...
Whoa! That's not a bad name!
What?
(Fudou Myouou Boy)
Fudou Myouou Boy! That cool sounding name is perfect for me!
I can't believe he approves of it!
He's okay with this?
[Laughter]
It doesn't matter if you're a "boy" or "lad" or whatever! I shall take your energy all the same!
Jorougumo!
Huh? You tryin' to pick a fight with me? Sounds fun!
Ah?
I win this fight!
Ha! Do you think a child is any match for me?
-Ready, and...Smash!
[Jorougumo screaming]
W-Whoa!
Tch, you're always a handful.
Ah, thank you!
Alright!
[Jorougumo screaming]
Ora! Ora! Ora! Ora!
A-Amazing!
Alley-oop!
Wow!
Did we do it?
Heh!
Time to finish her off!
Here's my spinning punch!
We're going to win!
What?
[Fudou Myouou Boy Yawning]
I'm feeling kinda sleepy.
[Snoring]
What?!
Why is he napping?!
Kids like to play a lot and sleep a lot too, right?
We only had a little bit more to go.
Curse you!
Thanks to your meddling, the energy I've gathered is gone!
Huh?
In this case, I'll just have to take your souls instead!
We're right on time for the party!
Huh?
That's...
Sakami?
Jorougumo.
Your punishment for deceiving me is death!
Oh, dear.
Aren't you going to call me princess and kneel like you always do?
Shut your mouth.
You still have this much power?
Wh-what's happening?
It's been a long time since I've changed into this form.
Shutendouji?
What did he say?
Don't tell me.
S-Sakami was Shutendouji this whole time?
Let's go!
Agh!
You're so weak!
Huh?
Step aside, Douketsu.
No way! He melted through those webs!
Incredible.
My apologies.
You haven't fully recovered your powers. Don't be reckless.
Leave her to me.
Tch.
For your crime of dishonoring the princess with your wickedness...
...you deserve death!
[Jorougumo whimpering]
[Jorougumo screaming]
She got even smaller!
Is she finished?
It's over.
I underestimated you. How could you be this powerful?
Die.
[Laughter]
You won't escape.
You'll regret this! I'll get stronger and have my revenge!
[Micchi and Jorougumo laughing]
Micchi Beam.
[Jorougumo screaming]
Justice always wins!
Alley-oop!
Wow! Micchi!
Although my beam is ineffective on strong opponents, it becomes effective once they've gotten weaker!
We did it!
We defeated Jorougumo!
Natsume, did you see how useful I was?
Yeah! Not bad at all, Micchi!
Aw, shucks!
[Micchi chuckling]
They saved us this time.
Umm, can I ask you something?
Why did you save...
Don't misunderstand us.
I did it only to repay my debt.
That's a cliché line from villains who become the heroes' ally.
Hmm? Where am I?
So that's what happened.
I was being possessed by a Yo-kai called Jorougumo?
Thank you for saving me, Akinori!
Ah, no problem! Eh-heh.
Doesn't this look romantic?
Now, fatty! Tell her!
A-Ayame...
Hmm?
There was something I wanted to tell you at Motomachi Tower.
Actually... Actually... I...
Wa, ha, ha, ha!
Actually, Ayame, the one who defeated Jorougumo and saved you...
...was none other than me, Micchi!
Sparkle!
Is that so? Thank you so much, Micchi!
Micchi!
Why, you!
My apologies, Douketsu.
You were correct all along to suspect that she wasn't the princess.
Yes.
To be honest, I've been thinking about the great lengths you went to for her.
Don't mention that.
So what will you do now?
This tree's condition tells me that the real princess is still near.
I will find you, no matter what.
Princess.
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their best
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is on Zundoumaru!
He was a spirit residing within a ramen shop owner's favorite pot.
Zundoumaru
(Poisoned Pot of the Dead Spirits)
He became a shadow side Yo-kai called Shirei no Dokudoku Nabe.
His light side is called Zundoumaru,
but his appearance is just outrageous!
Just look at that kettle in his you-know-what!
Zundoumaru
He poured hot water out of that thing into my cup ramen!
C'mon! Gimme a break!
Zundoumaru
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
There's a rumor about a flustered Santa Claus.
A flustered Santa Claus?
Yeah. Even though it's not Christmas time, he'll still come to your house.
Huh? Does that mean he'll give us more presents?
Sure. But when you get his presents, something really terrible happens!
Eep!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
The Absentminded Satan Claus
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs