Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 20 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Hey, that child actor looks kinda like you...
Ha, ha... looks like you just got taken out... Woah!
What is this?
What... What happened to me?
Where did you go?
Takeru...
Don't leave me here...
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
A great adventure of traveling all throughout space.
A hero who stands up to save the world.
You can enjoy all sorts of movies at the cinema.
But even so, you must be careful.
There is a theater room that you must never enter.
The Phantom Theater Room 0
So hot...
Is the air conditioner still broken?
The electrician is really busy this time of year.
Oh, dear...
Everyone looks so depressed.
Not at all. A warm day is no excuse for slacking off, people.
Huh?
Since when?
But it's summertime. That's to be expected.
Of course!
Hey.
Anyway, have a look at this.
Movie tickets?
Uh-huh.
Do you all want to come?
Yeah, I'll go!
That's great! The cinema is air conditioned, too!
Huh? By the way...
There's a strange case that's related to that.
The Phantom Theater Room 0
I heard there’s an urban legend about a Phantom Theater Room 0.
Last week, I went with a friend to the theater, and I saw the theater
room 0 for real.
My friend tried to enter theater room 0 out of curiosity, and I tried
stopping him immediately, but...
My friend was already through the doors and inside theater room 0.
Scared, I waited outside until the movie was supposed to be over.
Even though the movie is over, he still hasn’t come out.
Did he disappear for real...?
See Comments(32) >
Submitter: Shigeta
Here it is!
Phantom Theater Room 0?
Yeah.
Multiplexes usually have many theater rooms numbered from 1 counting up.
They say that a theater room numbered 0, which wasn't there before, appeared.
According to eyewitness testimony...
"I saw it with my friend last week."
"There were people desperately trying to stop others from going in."
"I heard that my friend went in, but..."
"...nobody knows what happened to him afterwards."
"If you go in, you won't ever come out ever again, they say."
Something must be happening in there...
They say that theater room 0 is a gateway to another dimension where monsters live.
Or perhaps the government is using using the cinema...
...as a front for a top secret laboratory doing highly dangerous experiments on unsuspecting guinea pigs.
I see. That sounds pretty scary.
Yeah.
That's such a weak reaction!
If you don't scream "Aaagh!" like Keisuke, I can't get into the mood.
Well, sorry about that!
Speaking of which, where's Keisuke?
There was a movie he was looking forward to.
He went to the movies this morning.
I hope he doesn't wander into theater room 0.
Even someone like Keisuke wouldn't get involved in weird stuff like that.
How did Keisuke wind up being this late?
Ah, there he is.
Keisuke!
When will you stop fooling around?
Movies are so much fun.
That's what my friends talked about.
What? Is it really that much fun?
It's very fun.
Very.
Hey, why don't we watch together?
No. We can't do that. Let's go home.
Then let's watch it tomorrow.
I see.
But we've finally found a big clue about theater room 0.
I understand. Contact me later, then.
So Natsume isn't coming?
That's right.
Keisuke insisted that Natsume should absolutely watch a movie with him.
Keisuke?
What's wrong?
Nothing. It just isn't normal for Keisuke to act like that.
For sure. Keisuke isn't the type of person to demand things from Natsume.
By the way, what about this big clue?
Yeah, of course!
A kid who's been inside theater room 0 is willing to talk to us.
A friend of mine invited me to see a movie that day.
It seemed normal at first...
But the movie had a character in it that looked just like my friend.
Even though my friend told me not to go.
I...I ran away...
This might the the work of a Yo-kai.
Yeah.
It must've been scary for that to happen to your friend right in front of you.
That's right, but...
Something even scarier happened after that...
He...
He came back!
Here it is.
I'm here only because you wanted me to come no matter what.
This better not be something boring!
It's fine.
Your friend returned, you said?
In other words, was he okay?
No!
He was...
He became someone completely different!
Alright. Alright.
Who is it?
It's me.
Hey, Takeru.
Let's go see a movie.
Let's go... to the movies...
I heard about a really interesting movie.
Hey. How about it?
I want to see it with you.
It's very interesting.
Very.
Okay then.
That was surprising.
U-Umm... You know...
This isn't really my type of movie...
What?
What's going on?
Keisuke, let's run.
It's rude to stand up in the middle of a movie.
Keisuke!
Look. You're in there too.
Why?
What is this?
No... No...!
Here it is.
This is where Takeru saw theater room 0.
It'd be nice if we could find some clues.
Let's go.
Number 0... Number 0...
Huh?
There's only theaters numbered 1 and higher here.
Maybe it's further in.
Huh? Natsume?
Ah, you're right!
What? You were here the whole time.
Did you all come to see a movie?
Nah. We're here to investigate theater room 0.
Natsume, where's Keisuke?
He's inside.
Hey.
Let's watch, everyone.
It's very interesting.
Very.
But we're in the middle of investigating.
Just forget about it. Let's just go watch it.
Sure!
We would have needed to check it out anyway. Let's go watch some.
Of course! Let's go!
It's no good.
Natsume, how about the Yo-kai Watch?
It's no good. I can't move my arms.
Ayame! Akinori!
Get out!
Don't be fooled!
Those guys are fakes!
It's no good. They can't hear us.
Oh, no.
Are you not sitting?
I see.
After hearing Takeru's story, I finally get it.
I know why the kids who got attacked were invited.
This is a trap!
They use their victims' appearances to invite and lure in even more prey.
That's right...
Both Keisuke and Natsume strongly insisted that we come watch the movie.
That means...
I knew it! You're fakes!
Everyone!
Watch out!
Natsume!
Keisuke!
Do not interfere!
Theater room 0!
This was it?
We gotta save them!
This is...
A normal theater?
What does this mean?
There must be some kind of condition for entering theater room 0.
You probably need to be invited by its friends, or you can't enter.
Exactly.
We will remember your faces.
We will never allow you to interfere with our theater again.
So just go home already.
That's right.
-Go home.
We won't let you interfere.
Don't come again.
SHADOWSIDE
You can't enter theater room 0 without being invited by those guys.
But...
They've memorized all of our faces. too.
It's a dishonor to not be at Natsume's side when she's in such trouble!
I must go to that theater...!
-No. They'll figure out that you're a Yo-kai right away.
Muscles is scrap meat at ￥2 per gram!
So cheap!
So we need someone whose face they don't recognize yet.
That's right!
Now... for our next prey...
Now, which movie should I go see...?
There's too many new movies to choose from!
Hey you.
Who? Me?
If you have trouble deciding, I've got just the movie for you.
Huh? For real?
Yes. Right this way.
It's here.
They're showing a very interesting film just for today.
Ooh! Looking forward to it.
What? That's me!
Huh? Another one?
Umm...
Are you okay there?
It worked!
I'm just acting like a handsome young man who loves new movies.
But my true identity is...
Ta-dah!
Ah! That's...
The Yo-kai Watch Animus?!
That means...
You're Akinori, but thin!
Whatcha think?
After summoning Suzaku, I even changed my hairstyle!
That's quite meticulous.
Not bad, Akinori!
Alright, let's get out of here!
Come here, Suzaku!
Alright!
Suzaku!
Hold still!
You did it!
Awesome!
These clothes are tight!
Alright! We're back!
Are you all okay?
Whoa! Akinori's clothes are so tight!
Just let it go.
You bastards!
Here it comes!
I'll handle this!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Jibanyan!
What is this?!
I hate water!
Jibanyan?
What happened to him?
I don't know.
Watch out!
Ayame!
Everyone...
You're all alone now.
What?!
What is this?!
Touma! Akinori!
What happened to those two?
Natsume! Over there!
This is...
This Yo-kai creates illusions!
Perhaps...! Whisper, the arks!
Yes!
Whom shall you be summoning?
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Raioton!
(Papa Bolt)
W-What happened?
Just now...
We were seeing its illusions.
Tsk! So that was it.
Alright, it's my turn now!
Possession! Genma Goemon!
Lend me your strength!
Goemon has arrived!
Heavenly Ascension Wild Dance Cut!
(Tenshouranbuzan)
We did it!
That's...
Oh, hello!
My name is Filmlin!
Why'd you capture people in this theater room 0?
That's because... I am a Yo-kai who used to be film reel shot by a movie director.
The person who filmed on me is the movie director Shinji Maeyamada.
Cinema King
Director
Shinji Maeyama
Making
Hits
One
After
Another!
Making
Hits
One
After
Another!
Main Actress
He was lauded as a genius disaster and horror filmmaker who created many wonderful and novel works.
Haunting!
Star Cinema
But even so...
Let's screen this again.
Best of luck, dear.
Yeah. This movie is going to be my masterpiece.
I'm looking forward to seeing the audience's faces.
This movie really had an impact never seen before.
What is this crap?
What bad taste!
Disgusting!
It's the worst movie!
It's too much, no matter how you see it!
The audience didn't appreciate the director's best masterpiece.
Damn it!
But it's a good film!
If only more people would come to see it...
...this work would have found an audience that would love it...
I was born from the love her and the director had for this film.
I wanted a lot of people to see the director's movie. So I lured people into theater room 0.
You didn't have to trap people in here, did you?
But the director's work is quite shocking, and people would leave during the film.
So I had no choice but to trap them.
How shocking is this film, really?
Hey, why don't we all watch this movie?
What?
I-Is that really alright?
W-Wait a second! Why do we need to do that?
Because I'm curious about this movie.
And if we watch this movie, Filmlin won't do anything bad, either.
Yes!
What do you think?
I agree with Ayame!
If it'll make Filmlin feel better, then it's alright.
What?
Now, let us begin!
That was really good!
Really?! Thank you very much!
Ayame's really incredible!
She's still calm after seeing that?
Ahh...
As you can expect from the beautiful 1-in-400,000-year girl!
Which should I pick?
Princess...
May you please acknowledge it soon?
That fact that you actually are a princess.
But I've told you before. I'm just Himeno. I'm not a princess.
Welcome!
Prepare for us the best crepe you can. Immediately.
Yes, sir.
Princess. Please wait momentarily.
Allow me to present the finest crepe ever.
O-Okay...
Thank you.
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is on magic!
The magic that I use was passed down through the Arihoshi clan for generations.
Magic
(Youjutsu)
But one must practice very hard in order to use it.
There's also techniques for fortune-telling and exorcism.
But my grandma is better at using that other boring magic.
By the way, Ayame can also use some magic...
Could this be fate?!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
There's some serious trouble happening!
What? What?
Someone very bad just appeared!
But just who is it?
We were suddenly drawn into a fight with Douketsu,
and the Mythical Beast Suzaku was injured!
What do we do?
(Yo-kai Holy Sword, Suzaku Azure Heavenly Slayer)
To heal Suzaku, we need to obtain the Youseiken, Suzaku Soutenzan.
(Swordsman Spirit)
And then restore Suzaku's original Kenbumanji form!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch Shadowside!
(Swordsman Spirit)
Revive! Kenbumajin Suzaku!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs