Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 29 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Hmm...
They're not here.
No four-leaf clovers.
Huh?
A red clover!
This one has four leaves!
Alright!
What a rare find.
Hmm?
[Screaming]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
When facing the unknown
shiranai koto ni mukiau to
SHADOWSIDE
I know the urge to hesitate
tachidomaritai kibun wakaru ze
"We need to stop and think about it"
tomatte kangaeru koto mo hitsuyou tte
It's the first rule adults tell you
otona ga itteru maana ichiri aru
But the spirit of the young is unstoppable
demo shounen no ikioi wa tomaranai
We can't stop
tomaccha ikenain da
Stop for even a moment, and you'll get dizzy
isshun demo tomaru to memai shichau ze
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Surpass reality and grasp the fragments of the future
genjitsu wo tobikoe mirai no kakera wo tsukamou
Faster than mach speed
mahha wo koeru supiido de
Run and jump and you can be a bird
kakedashite janpu wo sureba tori ni nareru
Jump forward, young ones!
susume shounen tobitatou
Zip zing zoom possession whizz
hyuui hyuu hyuu hyoui hyuu
Possession zoom zip zing whizz
hyoui hyuu hyuu hyuui hyuu
Our freedom!
bokutachi no furiidamu
You must know about four-leaf clovers, right?
They say you will find happiness if you find one.
It's a good luck clover.
However, if you find a four-leaf clover that is completely red,
Be absolutely sure never to touch it!
Because that type of clover is...
The Bloody Clover of Tragedy
[Humming]
Ribbit?
What's the matter?
What is Keisuke doing, ribbit?
I think he said that he's looking for a four-leaf clover.
Why do four-leaf clovers grow?
There's a theory that when young plants are injured, they grow a fourth leaf when they mature.
Therefore, it's easiest to find them in high traffic areas.
I found one!
Clovers that grow in the shade get less light, which is required for photosynthesis.
Another theory says that the plant grows additional leaves to compensate for this.
Jii found one!
Look at how many we've gathered!
Thank you, Unchikuma!
Kuma-Unchi is incredible!
Kuma! Please don't mix up my name willy-nilly!
Unchi's incredible! Incredible Unchi!
Touma, what's a four-leaf clover?
What is it? What is it?
YAY!
They say that if you can find a four-leaf clover, good things will happen.
My friends asked me to help them gather some.
Huh? You want to gather four-leaf clovers?
Yeah.
I want to bring some to a friend who's in the hospital.
Do you think you can help?
Leave it to us! How about it, guys?
Huh?
Yeah, of course!
I'll give you buckets full of 'em!
Thank you, guys!
Alright, let's find some more!
Alright! Da ze!
Hey, Keisuke, come here for a second.
Huh?
What's up, chubbso?
Don't mix "chubby" and "fatso" together like that!
Heh, heh.
The Bloody Clover of Tragedy
Submitter: Yan
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover there...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
"The Bloody Clover of Tragedy?"
Yeah. There's been a lot of posts about this recently.
When Keisuke mentioned that he was gathering clovers, he reminded me of this.
Huh?
Does this have something to do with four-leaf clovers?
There are blood red clovers that hide among a bunch of other clovers.
The moment someone picks one up, that person will be cursed with bad luck for the rest of their lives.
They call it a bloody clover because it's blood red.
[Whimpering]
C'mon! Gimme a break!
What if there's one of those bloody clovers in here?
But still, the bloody clover of tragedy, huh...
What in the world is it, really?
I wonder.
Perhaps it's a magical creature created by mystic arts passed down since ancient times.
Or maybe it's an explorer who transformed into a host for them after discovering a mysterious plant in the jungle,
and he's still screaming in agony even while he's covered with red leaves.
Stop it! This doesn't make me feel like looking for more clovers!
Stop spooking him.
Sorry about that.
Well, since these articles are out there, wouldn't it be safest to stop looking?
Maybe we should tell Manami and friends, too.
Well, it's not like I would believe anything like that!
But let's go warn them about it, since you're all so worried.
Manami and the rest aren't here.
Are they somewhere else?
Where are they?
Whoa!
What's with this clover?
It's a four-leaf clover, but it's all red!
[Screaming]
Are you okay?
U...Uh-huh.
What was that just now?
Hey, Tadao!
Let's go over there!
[Tree roots straining]
Huh?
[Screaming]
Look out!
Micchi Punch!
That was awesome, Micchi!
That was a kick, though, not a punch.
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Uh, I'm fine.
[Gasping]
What's that bruise?
A bloody clover?
The person who wrote that Usuranura post lives here.
You're Shoko, right?
Ever since I touched that clover, accidents have always been happening around me.
Are you sure it's not a coincidence?
I wish it was.
Look out!
Are you okay?
It's always been like this ever since I grabbed that red clover.
[Crying]
Sniff, sniff.
Psst, hey, Touma. I smell Yo-kai energy wafting from her.
For real?
Whis!
Akinori, check out Shoko with the Youma Radar.
Got it.
Oh, excuse me, Shoko, but can you show me what's under the bandage on your hand?
That's...
The bloody clover!
Looks like it's true that touching a bloody clover will bring bad luck.
Are Tank and Kouji going to be okay?
Everyone!
Wow!
Hey, Keisuke!
Here you go.
You got this many?
Thank you!
That's incredible, Keisuke!
I'm sure this will cheer up your friend!
Yeah.
By the way, have you all see a bloody clo...
...I mean, you haven't seen a red four-leaf clover, have you?
Huh?
Red clover?
Aren't all clovers green?
They seem fine.
Yep.
If you ever find one, don't touch it!
Keisuke.
Do you mean this red clover?
I found this a little while ago.
Don't!
[Screaming]
Natsume! Ayame!
What do I do? I just touched it!
Me too!
Ah! Ayame, your hand!
Ah! Me too!
Did we just get cursed by the bloody clover?
Natsume...
Let's go meet with Akinori and think of something for now.
Maybe Akinori's grandma can do something about it!
That won't work. I heard that she's at a hot springs resort with the neighborhood association.
I mean, should we really worry about it?
Uh...the bloody clover already ran off somewhere, right?
And that bruise will go away if you leave it alone, right?
SHADOWSIDE
What?!
Ayame and Natsume both touched the bloody clover?
So that's how you almost got hit by that car.
Good thing you're both safe.
I thought we were going to be goners for sure.
Natsume!
[Screaming]
Leave it to m...
Micchi!
If it weren't for Micchi, we wouldn't be here.
I understand.
You finally made the rare sacrifice worth making.
Well done, muscles!
But even so.
The mark that you have is the same as that girl's.
I wonder how many others are affected.
We should try to prevent there from being more victims.
That's right.
If we don't hurry, something irreparable might happen.
My apologies.
As your knight, I wasn't able to prevent you two from being cursed by the bloody clover.
It's okay.
It's not your fault, Micchi.
Argh!
If only I had touched the bloody clover instead.
That way, my body could take your misfortunes for you!
No, it's fine.
Wait, that's it!
Huh?
Ah, I found it.
Leave it to me.
Sorry about that. We're already cursed.
We can get rid of all the bloody clovers this way.
Micchi Punch! Punch! Punch!
I'll protect the both of you!
Thank you, Micchi!
But that was a chop, even if you call it a punch.
Micchi Block!
Micchi Interception!
Micchi Double Woman Grab, Jump and Landing!
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
There's another post.
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
Recently, Some friends and I were looking for four-leaf
clovers by the riverbed.
But there, we found a very peculiar looking four-leaf clover...
It was a completely blood red clover.
They say that finding a four-leaf clover brings good luck.
But picking up a red clover brings nothing but bad luck.
Could it be some kind of curse?
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
See Comments(61)>
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
I found a Bloody Clover.
It’s behind the convenience store on 4th Street.
It’s a red four-leaf clover right in the middle of
other green clovers,
Is it really true that people who touch it get bad luck?
I’m going to test it out.
See Comments(0)>
Bloody Clover Found
Submitter: Kouta
There's one behind the 4th Street convenience store.
Natsume and Ayame are doing their best, but they can't keep up.
What should we do?
Alright, I'll do something.
Yoshitsune has arrived.
These tiny leaves lead to something much bigger in numbers.
What are those red dots?
Those are all the places where the bloody clovers were seen.
Huh? What is that shape?
Looks like we've found it.
Huh? That's a four-leaf clover!
That's right.
And in the very middle of it is a hospital!
There's gotta be a lead there.
Let's go.
O-Okay.
We should find the secret of the bloody clovers here.
Suguda Hospital
Let's go.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Waugh! There's more of them coming from somewhere!
Suguda Hospital
There's a lot!
What are they doing?
[Whimpering]
What is that?
That Yo-kai is called Tsuchinoko!
Usually, it's a Yo-kai that brings good luck to those who find it.
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Your opponent is me! A fellow snake Yo-kai!
[Hiss]
Micchi Punch!
[Muffled] Natsume!
[Gasp]
Micchi!
Very well! I'll devour luck from the rest of you too!
It's my turn!
Possession! Genma Benkei!
Lend me your strength!
Benkei has arrived!
You haven't won yet!
Now it's my turn!
Let's go!
Descend! Genjuu Kirin!
Kirin has arrived!
Let's go!
Now it's my turn!
I just need a little more.
Don't get in my way!
Look out!
O-Ouch.
You okay?
Seems like this tree cushioned us!
Where's Tsuchinoko?
Over there!
Let's go after it.
Suguda
Hospital
Wait up!
Huh? Keisuke?
Manami?
Why are you here?
The friend that I mentioned is staying at this hospital.
Her name is Erika. She's in 3rd grade and lives in the neighborhood.
She's like a younger sister to me.
But she has a disease and has to have surgery for it.
Huh?
Manami!
How are you holding up?
Here's a present.
It's a bunch of four-leaf clovers.
Wow! There's so many!
Thank you so much, Manami!
Just a little more.
Just a little more, and it'll all go well!
There's no way I'd give up now!
I'll be fine if I have this, right?
My surgery will go well, right?
Of course!
Besides, Erika, you've got a strong friend!
Uh-huh.
A strong friend?
There's a beautiful white snake that I found.
Snake?
Erika, can you tell us more about this snake?
There it is.
It seems a lot smaller.
There's nowhere to run!
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it, Natsume!
Keisuke? What's wrong?
Ayame?
Are you the white snake that Erika saved?
Erika?
Who's that?
She's Manami's friend who's hospitalized here.
Were you trying to save Erika?
Huh?
Yeah. That's right.
I want to help save Erika.
Quit bullying that snake!
It's okay now.
On that day, Erika saved me.
I heard that Erika needed a really difficult surgery to get better.
I couldn't do anything to help at all.
I felt so frustrated about it...
...that before I knew it, I turned into a Yo-kai.
I turned into the Yo-kai Tsuchinoko.
So I tried to gather good luck from other humans so I can give it to Erika.
"If I do this, Erika's surgery will be a success!"
That's what I believed.
Well, I can relate to what you're feeling.
But isn't inflicting misfortune on others wrong?
I know.
But I can't think of anything else to do but this!
Are you not able to return the good luck that you stole?
It's fine. It'll all go back in about a week.
One week?
Erika will have her surgery in about a week, actually.
Can you please forgive me?
Do what you want with me afterwards.
Please!
One week, huh?
Let's bear with it.
Huh?
You're going to be putting yourself in danger for a week.
I want to help save Erika, too.
I'll just protect Natsume and Ayame!
Keisuke.
How admirable! That's what brothers do for their sisters!
Well, there's no one else better to be Ayame's bodyguard than me!
There are others who are affected by the bloody clover. Let's take turns protecting everyone from misfortune.
That's right.
It's all hands on deck for the agency, huh?
I've contacted all the other Yo-kai as well.
We'll do our best to manage the bad luck.
So make sure to do your best to save Erika.
Yes. Of course!
Thank you, everyone!
Right on.
Erika.
This is all the good luck I've gathered for you.
So please get better!
Good luck, Erika.
Suguda
Hospital
Erika, congratulations on your discharge.
Thank you very much.
Thank you so much!
I'll never forget your kindness.
Y-Your condition...
Rejoice, Douketsu.
After going all around the world, I've finally narrowed it down.
I've discovered the country he's in! The legendary man that the princess wants!
Oh, my.
It's over here!
T-That's...
That's this country.
That's right!
What's with that look? Be more happy!
Yes.
[Laughter]
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, Monsters! Monster! Monster!
bake bake bake bake  bakee! bakee!
Monsters! monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters, monster shish kebab!
bake bake bake baa shishikebabu kebaa!
Doing work all day long, diligently doing your best tan-tanuki
ichinichichuu shigoto ni bennkyou kinben majime ni ganbattantantanuki
It's the "Thanks for Working Hard Today" Land
kyou mo otsukaresamaa wa rando degozai
Prizes and vacations await for those who do their best
isshoukenmei yareba gohoubi kyuuka ga matteirunba
A ru-ru-roomba is a fun vacation
runrun runba wa tanoshii bakeeshon
Winter vacation!
fuyuyasumi!
Skiing a lot and laughing to the max is fun
sukii ni sukeeto suberimakuri warai makkusu tanoshiizo
If you're tired, get in the hot springs and have some dinner
tsukaretara onsen haitte yuugohan
C'mon, eat a lot of food, everyone
saasa minna de takusan tabeyou kai
Chew your food well, like a Yorkshire, a kind of dog.
gohan wa yooku kande ne yooku shateria wa inu desu nen
Let's happily slide on skis tomorrow, too
ashita mo genki ni suberimashou
But test-takers should avoid sliding on banana peels!
demo ne jukensei banana no kawa to shiken wa subeccha dame ne!
Monsters! Monsters! Monster vacation!
bake bake bake bake bakeeshon
Monsters, monsters! Monsters! Monsters!
bake bake bake bake
Monster! Monster!
bakee! bakee!
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Komajiro.
Komajiro
In his previous life, Komajiro was a frog who was crushed to death by a Komainu statue together with Komasan and became a Yo-kai.
Komasan
Komajiro
His shadow side form is somewhat spindly!
Actually, he's incredibly spindly!
Whenever he sees Micchi, he always pokes him in the eye!
It's not what you'd expect to happen between a frog and a snake. Are you okay with that, Micchi?
Komajiro
Next Episode
Preview
Have all of you heard?
The mysterious girl Ayame Himeno shows two different sides.
She has a pure and innocent side and a suspicious and questionable side.
Which side is the real Ayame?
While we find out the exact answer to that question, tragedy will befall Ayame.
Agh! Ayame!
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs
Ayame's Fall