Youkai Watch Shadow Side Episode 26 English Fansubs:
Noroinohanako: Translation/Typesetting/Timing/Karaoke/Encoding/Distribution
Manjiknights: QC/Editing
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
Be sure to watch in a well-lit room
at a safe distance from the screen!
SHADOWSIDE
Ah! I gotta pee!
[Deep growling]
-Hey! Who's in there?
Hey, are you okay?
Huh?
[Deep growling]
Wha? Augh!
[Bubbling]
Everything in this this world always has two sides.
Society,
school,
politics,
and human relationships.
Everything has a hidden side.
And of course, so do the Yo-kai...
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
SHADOWSIDE
Let’s leisurely wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Yet another day has passed
kyou mo ichinichi sugoseta ne
Painful things, lonely things, sad things,
tsurai koto ya samishii koto kanashii koto ga
Even when it silently comes close
oto mo naku shizukani chikazuite kite mo
A big black cloud coming closer
ookina kuroi kumo ga yatte kite
Blocking the morning light with its shadow
asa no hikari wo shadou ga oottemo
The light will always return with the passage of time
toki ga tateba hikari wa kanarazu modotte kuru yo
Time is precious to us
bokutachi ni wa jikan ga taisetsu nanda
Time is timely timing
taimuri na taimingu to taimu nari
Watch, watch watching!
uocchi uocchii uocchingu
Let’s wait slowly wait for these strong feelings
yukkiri ookina kimochi de matou
Ten o’clock, twelve o’clock, three o’clock, seven o’clock, nine o’clock
juuji juuniji sanji shichiji kuji
Today was another happy day
kyou wa ichinichi shiawase datta ne
It's been said since long ago that ghosts tend to gather in places with much water.
There might even be spirits gathering in such places in your very house.
The Demonic Man-Eating Toilet
Cheer up, Manami.
I'm sure he's okay.
Hey, Manami. Are you okay?
Did something happen?
Manami was looking after Terry, but he's gone missing.
Terry?
We were playing in the park yesterday.
Let's go, Terry!
Catch!
[Barking]
What a good boy, Terry!
It's this late already?
Terry! Let's go home!
Terry?
Ah, don't go in there!
Terry went into the restrooms, and I chased after him.
And then...
[Barking]
Terry?
[Roaring]
I heard a really scary voice!
Terry! Come out, Terry!
Terry!
Terry...
After that, I couldn't find Terry no matter where I looked.
Could this be the work of a Yo-kai?
No. It can't be!
Terry is family to me.
We've been together since we were both little.
Just where could he be?
It's okay, Manami!
We'll find him for you!
Huh?
Let's all find him after school!
Are you sure?
Of course! Isn't that right, Keisuke?
Huh? Umm... Er...
What? Don't tell me you're scared!
That's not it at all!
Let's go find this Terry or Robin or whatever.
Who's Robin?
Thanks so much, everyone!
C'mon. A Yo-kai must be behind this case, no matter how you slice it.
I think so, too.
Me too.
I agree.
Jii too.
You've got it all wrong!
It's not a Yo-kai case at all!
But just in case it is...
Whisper, Micchi and whoever can come too.
You sound nervous. I wonder if we should.
My hands are full protecting Natsume.
Jii is worried about Terry. Da ze.
Jii, you're so nice. We'll find him for sure.
Ouch!
Micchi is worried about Terry too! I'm super nice!
You don't care at all about how this looks, do you?
It certainly is concerning, though.
Keisuke, can you confirm that Terry went missing at the park restroom?
What's this indicator for?
They're places where people were victimized.
V-Victimized?
Yeah. By the Demonic Man-Eating Toilet.
D-Demonic Man-Eating Toilet?
From within the innermost toilet stalls, groans of agony can be heard.
When one approaches the stall, the door opens.
BAM!
Augh!
A monster emerges and drags you into the toilet.
Stop that! Geez!
According to my hypothesis, the demonic toilet is a front for mole people
who are abducting humans to experiment on in preparation for their invasion.
[Keisuke whimpering]
Or perhaps it's an attack by a creature who moves with superhuman speed!
There's no mistake about it, Terry's been captured by the Demonic Toilet.
That isn't right. That isn't right at all!
Keisuke?
Can he really investigate with us in that state?
Ohh... I don't wanna go. I don't wanna go, but I gotta go.
Good grief. Well, we can't just leave him like this, either.
Yeah.
It's fine! We'll find him right away!
That's right!
Thanks for waiting, guys!
You're late, Keisuke.
Huh?
Natsume and Akinori are coming to look, too.
Thank you!
My pet went missing
See Comments(36)>
Submitter: Kainushi
Yesterday, I walked my dog to the park.
Suddenly, he started barking and ran toward the restroom.
I chased after him into the restroom, but
he was nowhere to be seen at all...
I filed a police report, but they couldn’t find him.
Hey, Touma.
What are you looking for?
The Demonic Man-Eating Toilet has suddenly been trending online lately.
That might have been triggered by these posts about it,
so I decided to read them all.
All of them? That sounds hard.
But I must.
Jii is rooting for Touma! Da ze!
Dum dum!
Do your best!
That's right! Do your best!
YAY!
[Honking]
Thank you.
There's lots of posts about pets going missing here.
So it's not just Terry. Have other pets gone missing as well?
How is it? Did you find him?
Nothing here.
Nothing here, either.
Terry, where did you go?
The last place you saw him was the restroom, right?
Let's look there again.
We'll look here, then.
Yeah. I'll look in the girls room.
Hey, do you think this has something to do with the Demonic Toilet?
I wonder. The Youma Radar doesn't seem to be reading anything.
It's intimidated by me. No mistaking it!
Perhaps your radar is busted?
That's ridiculous! My grandma made this!
It won't break that easi -
[Beeping]
It's here!
It's moving.
Ah, that's right!
It's in the accessible restroom!
[Eerie moaning]
Whoa!
There you are!
Ha!
[Groaning]
It's running!
We can still pursue it. Let's go after it!
Natsume, did something happen?
Keisuke, go with the others!
Over there!
Come on out! Man-Eating Toilet!
[Eerie moaning]
What is it?
[Groaning]
Kuma...
-W-What is that?
Disgusting!
That's Unchikuma.
(Poofessor)
Unchikuma?
Yeah.
It's a bear Yo-kai who possess all sorts of knowledge and lives in toilets.
It's my turn! Micchi Punch!
What is this? It's muddy and disgusting!
Stay away!
Whoa!
W-Why won't people just accept me?
That's...
Well...
You're so dirty!
Dang.
Our best bet against this enemy is...
Summoning!
Light!
Come on out my friend! Robonyan 00!
From rescue operations to plumbing emergencies, I provide 24 hour support!
I will protect world peace and your way of life.
Robonyan 00!
Robonyan 00, I'll leave him to you!
I see.
Cleansing may be the most effective option.
Let's go!
Almighty Cleaning System! Ignition!
Kuma!
Your struggle is futile. I've completely analyzed your every move.
What?
What's wrong?
My vacuum has been overloaded with fur.
That looks dirty.
I told you. I've completely analyzed your every move.
Shadow side! Transform!
Ultimate Steamer! Fire!
Phew. I think I've calmed down.
I am Unchikuma.
I am the one who secretly grants humans wisdom.
Huh? Wisdom?
How do you grant that, exactly?
Yes, about that.
When gum gets stuck in your hair, apply butter to remove it.
Ah! So that's how!
Quit writing graffiti in people's bathrooms!
To me, humanity is like a student whom I instill with knowledge.
And that is why I was warning everyone to stop.
Unfortunately, they never listen.
Them?
I had no choice but to change into my shadow side form to scare them away.
In order to get people to not intrude into "his" territory, I warned people to stay away.
Huh?
Stay away!
So you were really saying "stay away," huh?
We couldn't really hear it.
In any case, toilets and other fixtures that drain into sewers are dangerous.
Take care when approaching them.
Huh?
Hey! What's this?
Is that... animal fur?
Do you think Terry is stuck in there?
No way! It's too small for a dog.
[Growling]
Huh?
Tank? Kouji?
[Keisuke whimpering]
Unchikuma. Who's behind these incidents?
He is one of the most dangerous among all of the Yo-kai.
He lurks in the underground below this town.
His name is... Orochi!
SHADOWSIDE
You shouldn't get any further involved in this.
Orochi is much more powerful than anything you've encountered before.
And he's in no mood to speak with humans right now.
If you go, you may wind up dead.
Huh?
W-We can't stop.
Kuma?
Tank and Kouji are being held by Orochi.
We've got to save them.
B-Because they're my friends!
Keisuke...
That's right. Let's go!
Over here!
It's going to be okay, Minami.
They're going to find Terry and the rest of your friends.
Right?
Yes.
He's here! Right in front of us!
Where?
Orochi! You're here, aren't you? Stop attacking people!
[Gasps]
There's a person!
You're Orochi, aren't you?
Orochi is a wandering Yo-kai who's been on a journey searching for strong opponents to duel.
Why have you been doing this?
I came to this town simply by coincidence.
Why are there animals that don't belong here?
I didn't understand it at first.
But I found out the answer soon afterwards.
They were playthings abandoned by humans who grew bored of them.
It is the natural order of things for the strong to consume the weak.
But trifling with another's life is absolutely unforgivable.
That is why I have decided to mete out a fitting punishment.
I have captured those who would toy with the lives of others by abandoning them.
I saved the lives of animals from human hands.
You call kidnapping people's pets "saving them?"
That's correct.
There may be those who abandon their pets. But there are also people who take good care of them!
There are so many happy pets who are loved and cared for!
Shut up!
Whatever you have to say,
it doesn't change the reality that they have been neglected!
[Animals growling]
Then what about Tank and Kouji?
Why did you capture them?
They never did anything wrong!
It's because they dared to encroach on my territory.
Just because of that?!
Let them go!
They're my friends! They're important to me!
I can't do that.
The same is true for the other humans.
All of your precious friends...
They're all in my stomach!
No! No way!
Tank, Kouji.
Unforgivable!
Summoning!
Shadow!
Come on out, my friend! Mitsumatanodzuchi!
Me too!
Descend! Genjuu Kirin!
(Mythical Beast Kyryn)
Kirin has arrived!
I want to follow them, too!
Manami! Wait!
Now, Kirin!
Right!
Huh?
Kirin!
Alright. It's my turn.
(Swordsman Spirit)
Possession! Kenbumajin Suzaku!
Suzaku!
Lend me your strength!
(Blooming Flowers, Suzaku Azure Heavenly Slayer)
Hyakkaryouran Suzaku Soutenzan!
Suzaku has arrived!
Take this! Heavenly Cross Attack!
What's that?
Not good! He's going to blow the whole sewer away!
I won't allow it!
Touma!
Terry! Where are you?
Hey, everyone!
Manami! Stay back!
Huh?
[Screaming]
[Roaring]
Huh?
[Terry growling]
This dog...!
Is that Terry?!
[Terry barking]
You wish to protect this one?
Even if it means fighting me?
[Terry barking]
I see.
[Moaning]
Tank! Kouji!
Orochi?
Do as you please.
Thank goodness! They're still alive.
Orochi?
Terry.
Umm...
Elizabeth the spectacled caiman goes to Tanaka on 2nd Street.
Watson the anaconda goes to Oobayashi on 1st Street.
Is this Elizabeth?
That's George the saltwater crocodile.
Returning these to their former owners seems tough.
But we should try to return as many as we can.
I've got it. This one is Elizabeth!
Field
Guide
Close! But that's Steve the smooth-fronted caiman.
Field
Guide
I can't tell them apart at all!
Da ze!
[Meowing]
The more beautiful men the princess consumes, the more powerful she becomes.
I must offer her more beautiful men.
Huh?
That was a delicious looking one just now.
Leave it to me.
May I have a word with you, biker?
Here you go, princess.
Domestically produced beef extract, your highness.
Are you an idiot?
Huh?
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
Welcome my boogie friends
uerukamu bukii na nakama tachi
Funky beats tonight again
koyoi mo fankii biito de
Join in, join in, join in, my boogie mate
notteru notteru notteru bugiina meito
Dah dah dah dah dance that dance!
daa daa daa daa odori odotteneeee!
Turn with energetic steps
hazumu youna suteppu de taan de
Scratch that feeling of being born
umareta teno kimochi wo kizande
Everyone is here is together with the happiness here
koko ni iru minna to koko ni aru yorokobi
Repeat repeat, take it easier
ripiito ripiito motto karoyaka ni
Thumping down your back, boogie-bubah
koshi ni zun to kitara saahora bugibuba
Super high rhythms only found here
koko dake no chou hai na rizumu da
If you wanna have fun, it’s easy, no sweat
tanoshimitai nara kantan sa riki muna
That step is a funky boogie-bubah
sou suteppu wa fankii na bugi buba
Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah Boogie bu bah bah
bugi buba bugi buba bugi bubabaa
SHADOWSIDE
AKINORI'S
Trivia
Today's topic is Junior!
Junior is kinda like a mascot for the agency!
Junior
When shown a template, Junior can transform into virtually anything.
But the things he transforms into are empty inside, like a balloon.
Taking after a certain someone, Junior's got a foul mouth!
Junior calls Micchi "Muscles."
And Junior also calls me "Fatty!"
Junior
That's not nice!
I'm not fat! I'm just big-boned!
Next Episode
Preview
Hey, have you all heard?
Komasan had a younger brother long ago!
Huh? Is that so?
His name is Komajiro.
But what do you mean by "long ago?"
Long ago, when Komasan died and became a Yo-kai,
Komajiro never became a Yo-kai!
Huh? Is this Komajiro's grave?
Something emerged from the grave!
Could it be Komajiro?
Next time on Yo-kai Watch: Shadowside!
The Wandering Komajiro
Noroino
Hanako
Fansubs