Continuing with the news...
"UFO" sighting!? Witnessed by fishermen! Paranormal Files!
Last night...
...an unidentified flying object has been spotted.
According to eyewitness accounts,
...the object is estimated to be about 300 meters...
... and there is speculation that this might be a UFO.
Whoa Keita, there seems to be some interesting news!
A 300 meter wide UFO?
No way!
This is the perfect mystery!
You can't help but to get excited for it!
Well, if yo-kai exist...
...it's not weird for aliens to exist too.
Are there really alien spacecraft bigger than soccer fields flying around?
Of course not.
Of course, that's Keita's way of thinking!
"That's all just science fiction!"
That's just perfectly normal!
Aren't those who unconditionally believe everything on TV & the Internet the weird ones?
W-Wait, you're wrong!
How could you possibly say something like that about me?
Huh?
But you don't know anything about the real world, right?
You're useless without your tablet!
And completely dependent on googling!
Um...W-What...
What did you just say!?
Why don't you change your name to "Googling Pad"?
You bastard, you're always...
Nya-Nya-Nya
Nya-KB!
Nya
K
B
KB...
Everyone!
For coming out to see NyaKB today...
Thank you...
... thank you very nyan!
You're welcome!
Everyone, let us join our hearts together and get excited!
Nyan!
Of course, nyan!
Yoohoohoo!
Komajiro...
Eating ice cream is great anytime!
You never get bored of it do you?
What are you saying? As if I'll ever get bored!
The more I eat it, the more I like it!
Even the clouds look like ice cream these days!
What is that?
What...?
What was that?
Geez!
What voice is this?
What...?
What's this?
What is this!?
Big brother!
This is kinda weird...!
MONGE!
What!?
What in the world is this?
What just happened?
Is this me?
What is this?
This is so weird!
No matter how you slice it, it's totally weird!
My clothes feel so weird too...
Whoa!
The watch now looks metallic!
It looks so cool now!
L-Let's calm down and think this through
Sure
Umm... So I was laying on the bed...
...while reading manga...
...and talking to Whisper about UFOs and such...
Uh huh
And then...
...as always, Whisper was being stupid...
W-What!?
..."as always"!?
Whisper looks completely different!
Oooh!
Heh heh! Of course!
So I was like this...
But now I look better like this!
Well now that you mention it, I kinda....
I look kinda different too....
Of course, speaking of you, Keita...
You had a puffier face... smoother skin...
...and unique wing-like hairstyle, kinda like this...
Ouch ouch ouch!
That hurt!
This is as you would say...
...the physical world... the real world...
...the material world... where everything is different...
Yeah... seriously...
When I look at my hand...
...I see wrinkles... and tiny dots...
Those are your pores!
The skin of human beings have pores that look like tiny dots!
Keita!
Eh! Don't....Don't tell me...
Mom...!
Mom will appear in....
Keita!
Dad is out of supplies, can you go buy some?
Umm....
You're mom...right...?
Mom...
Good.....
Good... Morning!
What are you saying?
Are you going or not?
Umm..... What was it....?
An errand.
Ah! I get it!
I'll go soon!
Don't worry, I'll go!
Just...give me the room.
What was that?
Strange kid.
What is with this tension...?
Yes.
Your mom just got the most wonderful makeover didn't she?
Makeover?
Yes.
What's up?
Well... if it's going to be like this...
I can take it.
Positive thinking!
Dad will appear in....
I'm home!
Welcome back!
Welcome home!
That's....Dad, right?
Seems like it.
Welcome home!
The department chief suddenly wanted to stop golfing halfway.
He wasn't in the mood, so I'm off the hook.
Wait, so you guys left in the middle of the game?
Make sure his wife doesn't wind up blaming you.
I'll be back!
See you later!
Take care!
So he said he went golfing and stuff?
Doesn't seem like the kind of stuff he always talks about..
Is that so?
For a salaryman to entertain clients by golfing...
...is just a normal thing to do.
Yes.
That's amazing!
What is this?
They're running.
Garbage cans
Postal box
Old man
Who you calling old!?
Hey, this might be...
...pretty amazing!
Keita!!!
Ah! It's Jibanyan!
Ouch
My body feels a little heavier than usual.
Looks like you tripped over this
Don't just tell everyone that I tripped!
More importantly, you're Keita, right?
I've changed a lot though. But...
...still Keita!
Well then let's leave it at that.
Seems like something happened just now,
All the yo-kai are in turmoil!
All the yo-kai are....
in turmoil?
In other words, the humans haven't noticed it..
But the yo-kai are all just as confused as I am?
Yes, nyan!
I wonder why?
Ah-ha!
Because Keita is heavily involved with yo-kai...
...he's treated like a yo-kai!
Huh?
I get treated like a yo-kai?
We're a yo-kai group!
We have no choice.
Must must...
...solve this mystery!
In the name of my grandfather!
That line doesn't work here.
Just stop it.
First, let's gather some info.
Let's visit Fumi, Kanchi and Kuma!
That sounds really fun! Yahoo!
Mission: Meet with Fumi-chan
Is Fumi-chan even home?
Wait, Keita.
Doing that will make you seem really pathetic!
Nyaa! That's really bad!
In that case...
...let's just make up an excuse...
... and meet her directly!
Does that mean you're just going to charge right in?
Ouch ouch...
Keita?
Fumi....-chan?
What's going on Keita?
You're....
Fumi-chan, right?
I'm going to cram school. What do you want?
Cram school?
She's kinda overwhelming.
That sure is.
What are you mumbling to yourself?
Why did you come to my house in the first place?
Um....
Oh, that's right...
I forgot my notebook....
...I accidentally left it in the classroom.
Umm... You're being very awkward.
Nah, it's not like that at all!
I mean, anyone could get careless and then...
Err... I'm busted....
Ah ha. So that was it.
Eh?
But as you know, we're not children anymore.
Being too candid will bring trouble.
You understand, right?
If someone sees you here,
...people will misunderstand that we're going out...
That's going to a problem. So don't loiter here, OK?
Yeah... That sounds right. Ok.
If you want to hang out, there are much better places, aren't there?
Huh?
I'll see you again then.
Was that really Fumi-chan?
Nevertheless, that was a very awkward and unusual conversation filled with unease!
I like it.
Huh?
This world...
is pretty good!
What!?
Even Fumi-chan's pores are cute!
The world of pores is awesome!
Yeah! Awesome!
There's some level of wrongness with this kid's subconscious.
Mission: Meet with Kuma and Kanchi
Oh! They're there!
Oh!
Alright! Come out!
Come out! Come out! Come out!
It's here!
Definitely! Definitely! Definitely!
I've finally got the rare Mr.Epochman figurine!
That's great! Good for you, Kuma!
Are those two...
...Kuma and...
...Kanchi?
Looks like it.
Kuma....
...kinda looks like a middle-aged man. Or rather...
...A yo-kai?
Hey Kanchi. Good luck to you too.
Wait a second, Kuma!
I'll...
I'll buy it for 30,000 yen!
What?
That's not a funny joke, kid.
This has a market value of at least 50,000 yen!
Well, about that... since we're friends...
how about 35,000 yen?
36,000 yen?
37,000 yen?
40,000 yen.
38,000 yen?
No. 40,000 yen.
That's rough.
They were Kuma and Kanchi... right?
This world...
...is so different from what we know.
Compared to Fumi-chan, they're completely different characters!
But Nya-KB is cute even in this world, nyan!
Yep!
Kanchi is ok but Kuma is too much.
Nya!
Isn't she...
Emi-chan?
Emi-chan!
JIbanyan!
Anyway...
This has got to be the work of a yo-kai.
I can't think of any other reason.
What?
Wait a second, Keita.
I've never heard of a yo-kai that can change this world like this!
There it is!
It exists after all!
What is that thing?
Koala...?
Stuffed animal?
Keita, don't you think it's trying to charm us with its cuteness?
I know!
It's a dreadful yo-kai trying to be cute while hiding the fact that ...
...it was the one that caused all this to happen...
Hey! Turn everything back to normal!
Why is it making us do these silly poses?
It's useless...!
Good...
Show your true self, evil yo-kai!
It's trying to say that you've got it wrong. Poor thing.
What's your name?
It doesn't really seem to know.
Let's just call it, Koala-nyan.
Koala-nyan
My goodness!
As expected from Keita's disrespectful and terrible sense of naming.
It's easy to understand though.
People like you...
Instead of naming a dog something normal...
...like "Spot" or "Fido" you'd just call it "Dog".
Koala-nyan!
You can try all you want not talking, but...
... not if Bakuroba is around!
Alright, my friend! Come on out!
Bakuroba!
Yo-kai medal...
...set on!
It's mysterious time!
Dream Roulette!
Mysterious... Mysterious
What's going to pop out next...?
Mysterious!
Congradulations!
Bakuroba!
Okay, Bakuroba! Get Koala-nyan to tell all its secrets!
How's that Koala-nyan?
Confess everything and anything you know!
That seems like everything...
What did it say?
I haven't the faintest idea...
Bakuroba could only get it to say stuff we don't understand.
What in the world were you trying to tell us?
How stubborn...
Huh?
We're back!
What's with this plot twist!?
How did we get back to our world?
What are you trying to say?
What was that just now?
Well... Anyway, it's good to be back.
That's still to early to say!
Fuyunyan!
This phenomenon was definitely the work of a yo-kai!
Huh? What did you just say?
I'm trying to say it'll happen again!
Why in the world is Floaty here for anyway?
Because of various and all kinds of such-and-such...
I perceived the phenomenon...
...And knew that it all depends all up to you, Keita!
Huh...That's a fairly half-baked explanation.
So which yo-kai is responsible for this?
It's something huge with a mysterious nature and such.
And it's something kinda wicked, like this!
That's too way to vague...
And it swallowed me up!
Anyway!
The reason that the world changed...
Is something we need to find out immediately!
But we don't have any clues.
We'll just ask someone who knows.
Who in the world would know that?
That would be Enma-Daiou!
What!? Enma-Daiou!?
Well... It seems certain that he would know...
We can't meet him unless we're in the yo-kai world...
Then leave it to me!
I'm going!
There he goes.
Yeah...
What's that?
There's trouble!
What in the world happened just now!?
The yo-kai master, Keita should know right?
D-Did you mean the world of pores from before!?
Even I don't...
I don't know that.
Did something happen?
There's big trouble...!
If that happens again, there's going to be trouble!
After the world got really weird..
Inaho...Or the girl that looks likes Inaho, rather...
...She suddenly started mixing some crazy suspicious potion!
She probably put in some dangerous materials to try to enhance performance...
Dangerous materials...?
Like biological weapons or something like that...!
In other words, she's trying to make something terribly dangerous!
So it's not just people's appearances that change ...
...personalities get exaggerated in the world of pores.
Of course!
No wonder someone with such a plain personality...
...wouldn't have much to exaggerate in the first place.
Yaa! What is that?
Didn't that show up on TV?
That alien spacecraft...!
But doesn't it look too soft and rubbery to be that at all!?
Maybe these types of aliens make their spaceships...
...from soft and rubbery space metals!?
But this one looks just like a whale!
That can't be possible!
If it's a whale, it should be yelling "Hogee" or something!
It's yelling that right now!
Hogee!!!
I understand now!
If my thinking is correct...
That is the yo-kai that's responsible for this!
Well, anyone would be able to figure that out at this point, Keita...
We're in this world again?
Oh no! She's probably going to finish making that potion now!
Bye-bye!
What a loud one...
Huh?
The whale's gone.
It completely disappeared!
Emi...
Emi...!
Jibanyan?
What's going on?
That's not the Emi that I know!
Emi loves cute clothes as always!
And that's because...
She has dreams of being a clothing designer!
Mom!
Let's throw these out.
What? Why?
Keep them for a while.
Nah...I don't care...
I'm not interested in design anymore.
Huh? That's fine with you?
Yeah.
Cute dogs! Interesting dogs!
Popular dogs from all over Japan!
Broadcasting just dogs!
Woof woof wonderful!
Emi isn't interested in this, right?
She's cat person, 100 percent!
Whoa.
So many different kinds!
Come here, Kuromaru!
Whoa whoa, Kuromaru!
Good boy! Good good!
So cute!
Good boy! Good boy!
For Emi to turn out like that...
...this world is no good...
Eh!? Who's that?
That's Koala-nyan.
It's a lame name though.
Not again!
It's just going back and forth now...
Huh?
Could it be...?
Of course!
Koala-nyan's nose is the switch for changing the world.
What is this?
If that is so, then allow me to...
Huh?
Wait!
Come here!
Stop right there!
I said stop!
Come here!
Why you....!
How's this? How's this? How's this?
I've got you!
Wai...What?
What was that pose!?
Of course!
When you pull the ears...
...this happens!
Is that all you know?
It's the nose!
See?
It's true!
With a power that we can so casually control, you know what this means...?
Yes!
Let's see what it can do!
Sorry about the wait!
Thanks.
Thanks for the food.
Hey.
You guys!
You know...
It's rude to be staring at people like that.
Woof!
Jeez.
That was shocking.
To meet Jinmenken like that...
That's so creepy...
I know right?
Yeah.
What's up?
I'm itching to do something here.
I've haven't fought a truck in a while.
I feel like doing that right now!
It's coming!
Let's do this!
Paws of.....
You trying to kill me!?
Are you... weak against water?
From what we've seen so far...
This world is different in many ways from the world of pores.
How was that other world created, I wonder?
I wonder what the real cause is...
Between these two worlds...
I feel like there's a big difference that we are missing.
Are you sure you're not just imagining things?
Hmmm. Maybe.
It's like the world of pores is missing something that this world has.
No matter where you look, I can't find it!
I've got it! It's that whale!
Come to think of it... that's right!
Nya nya!
I know that whale!
I saw that whale while I was buying chocobars at the candy store!
It's that!
It looks just like the one that was flying in the sky!
In other words...
So this is that whale's true form?
But what does this sign have to do with the whale in the sky?
What the...!
The candy store is gone!
What's wrong?
In our world, the candy store was over here!
I can't get any chocobars like this.
Hospital...?
Calm yourself...
Hey.
Are you listening?
Careful...! Careful...!
Quit it already... Quiet down...
That's it!
I'm starting to get it!
What are you?
Are you the one doing this?
Who are you?
I'm Keita Amano...
It's a little hard to explain...
You're not from my world.
T-That's right.
I got myself lost in this world and...
What about it?
Anyway, we can't leave things like this.
We ought to turn things back to normal.
There is no need for that.
But why?
This is weird.
I mean... You can't be at ease when you're not home.
Really?
But I love your world the most.
It's all changing again!
So she's the one who is causing all this!
She's flying?!
This world is great, isn't it?
I'm so free here.
Are you guys alright?
Let's just go after her!
Wait!
I can do anything in this world.
Anything I intend.
Look... Just like this...
It's definitely her.
She called out to that whale...
...and caused our world and the world of pores to be connected!
Why are you following me?
I want to...
...help save you!
You've got a reason you're doing this, right?
So why are you doing this?
That is wonderful.
So cool!
Now's no time to be staring!
If it's going to be like that...
Come on out, my friend...!
Koma-Mom!
Since when did you befriend her?
Komasan gave it to me.
My mom always seems to be lonely...
Why don't you summon her from time to time?
These explanations are always so dodgy!
Yo-kai medal...!
...Set on!
Koma-mom!
Stay right there!
Good!
Oh yes!
You did it!
Because the world of pores is her original world...
...she can't fly around now.
I figured this out after thinking about the differences between our worlds.
Why are you messing with me?
I...
All I wanted to do was to dance.
Dance?
If I don't dance...
...nobody...
...will ever look at me...
I will never stop dancing!
Bakuroba?
Oh? Is that revenge for last time?
The first time I started ballet...
I was still just a small child.
I fell in love with ballet at that very moment.
I'm Kanami Minami.
Let's work together!
Kanami...
...let's try our best together.
Yes.
I did it! Teacher!
Kanami! You did your best!
Yep! Thanks teacher!
From that day on,
I started to love ballet more and more.
Teacher, I'm definitely going to win at this competition!
Yes.
You can definitely make it!
Yes!
Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
Congratulations, Kanami!
Please have this.
Thank you, teacher.
You're going to make it into ballet academy now.
Kanami...
...you could become...
...the very best ballerina in the entire world!
Let's take on the world together!
Yes!
To aim for the top as a ballerina.
Before I knew it...
Ballet became everything to me.
In spite of that...
A sudden accident.
I had to stop doing the thing I love.
...because I could never dance ever again.
No!
No! No!
I wanted to turn back time.
Even though I knew it was impossible,
I wished for that miracle.
At the time..
...when I looked at that whale.
If a whale could fly in the sky
If I could go to a world where such an absurd thing could happen...
I could do what I've done before.
Is that why.
Ah! The whale's in this world too!
Was it never in the world of pores before?
She's becoming more powerful...
...enough to summon the whale into this world too!
Is that even possible?
It's real!
She's not supposed to fly in this world!
What are we going to do now?
Run after her!
Keita?
Keita!
Wait up!
Ballet school?
Maybe Kanami came back here?
Let's take a 10 minute break.
Okay
Don't forget your things.
Um.. Excuse me.
Are you...
Are you Kanami's teacher?
And you are?
Kanami....
She always worked the harder than anyone.
When she was doing ballet...
She was more energetic...
...and more motivated than anyone.
But when that happened..
You mean the accident?
Yes.
To her...
Ballet was everything.
It was her dream to go international with her ballet.
But then that dream...
...because of that accident...
She gave up on that dream.
That's really sad.
It is.
But...
It was her own decision to give up.
Huh?
What do you mean?
What are we going to do now?
I am definitely going to save Kanami!
What do you mean?
Come on out my friend!
Kyuubi!
Orochi!
Robonyan Type-F!
Yo-kai Medal! Set on!
Kyuubi
Orochi
Robonyan Type-F
There's someone I need to find. Please!
I'll find her for you.
Let's find her together!
Understood!
Leave it to me!
Is that it?
Keita? Can you hear me?
I've found her.
Towards the west.
She's flying!
Amazing!
Something seems off...
Kanami...
Kanami...Why?
It's her grief.
It's the darkness from the grief in her heart.
It's binding our world to her's.
If this continues, she'll stop being human.
Huh?
We need to pry out this darkness that has inspirited her!
But how?
Leave it to me!
This is the reason I've come back.
My King...
This is...
Have you noticed it? Nurarihyon?
Yes.
I sense a grave situation.
My appearance, which was merely beautiful...
...seemed to have developed further into perfection.
Lord Enma!
It's as if...
...a hotness from the spiciness of lava soup...
...spit from the fires of hell...
...a concentration of charming hotness was endowed to me.
King Enma...
I have also seem to have...
...absorbed some of that hotness,..
...adding to my charm and handsomeness.
What was it that happened?
Perhaps...
Enma....
Enma!
Yes it is! It's Enma!
My body is moving on its own!
Nurarihyon, get it together...
Enma....
Enma!
Yes it is! It's Enma!
It got me too!
Our beauty....!
..Is overflowing!
Is that so?
The strange phenomenon in the human world...
...has spread its influence here as well!
We feel it.
So what you are saying...
Is that these two worlds have mixed together...
In that case, Fuyunyan.
I want you to investigate the situation for me.
Yes.
It seems that...
A darkness has taken hold of a powerful human with a very strong heart.
An evil born from the heart of humans.
I sense this existence of pure evil.
Nurarihyon, bring me that.
Yes.
This should be enough.
Thjs is...!
This is called...
...Enma Blade.
King Enma's Enma Blade.
It's witty, isn't it?
It's not just witty... It's also fitting.
With this blade, the darkness inspiriting humans is...
Enma...
Nurarihyon, don't forget me!
Enma!
Yes it is! It's Enma!
Enma...
Enma!
Yes it is! It's Enma!
Enma... Enma...
Enma!
So this is the...
Enma Blade!
Uh huh!
Cut her off from the powers of darkness!
The powers.... of darkness?
Yo-kai watch!
Dream Link!
King Enma medal!
Set on!
King Enma!
It's a katana!
This is the power of the handsome Enma!
Hear me...
Come on out, the power of god!
Yes!
What is that?
Um...Um...
That's the great yo-kai demon, Daiyoki Hoge-Whale!
What is it?
A heart of darkness born from inside humans...
...inspirited by the will of Kaima.
That's my line!
No good...!
I will... continue to dance!
There's no way!
Be careful! Keita!
If you leave it like this...
It'll destory both our worlds!
There's no choice but to defeat Hoge-Whale!
Let's do this already!
Let's do it for her sake too.
I'm finally able to dance now...
...so don't get in my way!
Thank you, Orochi!
No need for thanks.
There's no shame on relying on us!
Kyaa! Those two are so cool!
Smootch!
Awesome!
As you can expect from Orochi and Kyubi!
It's trying to run away!?
It disappeared!
Looks like it wants us to fight seriously!
What...?
Looks like Orochi and Kyubi are releasing their true power!
Huh?
They look so cool in this world too!
Light Orochi & Dark Kyubi
We will defeat you!
When we end this fight...
What was that!?
...they were busy talking!
How dishonorable!
How cruel....
Aren't we weaker in this world?
Seems like it.
In that case...
It's here...
Now leave it to me!
I'll support you!
Of course...
Paws of Fury!
What the?
Paws of Fury become pathetically realistic!
This isn't good...!
It's dangerous to fall from that high!
What are you doing?
Over here! Jibanyan!
Good! Now's our chance!
Aha! Paws of Fury!
Yeah!
Oh no! Not again...!
Leave it to me!
Failure is dishonor for a warrior!
Bushinyan! Be careful!
There is no need for worry.
I have no intention of loos...
What were you thinking? It ended just like last time!
Tch. It just doesn't play fair.
We're going to have to fight it more practically.
Everyone!
Komajiro!
Try using this!
What's this?
It's the yo-kai bazooka!
I remembered there was something like this...
...so I went and ordered it over the yo-kai mail order.
That was getting a little long!
I'm still a little relieved to be back in this world though.
Looks like we're making progress gathering things.
Yes!
Yo-kai watch!
Dream Link!
Lend me your strength, my friends!
Melamelion!
Set on!
How much power will it be? Will it be maximum oni power?
Oni Maximum power!
And here's a bonus!
Eh? Onarazumono?
It stinks!
Look out!
Did we get it?
We got it!
What's that?
That is...
What in the world is that?
It's not showing up on Uki-pedia!
Anyway, for the time being let's call it...
Whaleman! (Kujira-man)
Ehh!?
That's such an arbitrary name!
How about something more fitting for a final boss?
Geez. Really...
Go get them, Whaleman.
What? You agree with him?
Whoa! For real!?
Whaleman (Kujira-man)
What? Oh no...
Mackerels?
Such lung capacity!
What?
That?
What? Wait, what's that?
Hey!
Hey! It's dangerous! It's dangerous!
Oh dear...!
A one-man octopus...
What can we do?
Let's fight it in our world!
What? Huh?
It's there! Koala-nyan!
Hey! Aren't you overdoing it with the water?
Hey Keita! Let's hold him back!
I will also help.
Yes. Please!
Wait, Koala-nyan!
Wait!
Koala-nyan! Wait!
Oh no!
One child ticket please!
What are you doing?
I've got to buy a ticket!
We'll be going ahead!
Please!
Hurry, please!
Whaleman!?
Since when did it get there!?
It's coming here!
Leave it to me!
Rocket punch!
What a big-shot...!
But you're missing the point?
Wait...
Big brother, hurry up!
Gusty Cross Paw!
Paws of Fury!
It's no use!
I can't use my Rocket Punch either.
It's come to this, maybe we can use this!
Weekly Subscription Bit-by-bit...
Do It Yourself Final Boss Defeating Tank!
First issue.
That's kinda cool!
What is that?
Hey.
Isn't this taking a bit too much time?
This world isn't so convenient.
Ah! It's here!
That old lady is overdoing it with the water...
Ah! Jibanyan!
Fuyunyan!
Agh! It's not making any progress!
We've finally caught it!
What do we do now?
Push its nose!
OK -zura!
What did you say to push again?
Push anything!
Boop-zura!
Do it, USApyon!
Let's build it all at once!
It's done!
Let's go!
Finish it off!!!
We did it!
You did it! Good job, USApyon!
Hey!
Komasan!
You saved us!
What?
Bluefin tuna!
Watch out!
Look out!
Komajiro!
It's getting bigger and bigger!
What are we going to do...
Ah! Of course!
Let's try using this!
This suspicious potion made by that Inaho look-a-like girl!
What about it?
You drink it.
It's filled with powerup ingredients.
Drinking it will increase strength for certain.
For real?
Yes.
However, it is extremely bitter.
Huh?
Bitter?
Okay! Who wants a drink?
Me!
Me too! Me too!
What? Uhh...
I'll do it too!
Help yourself.
So it's come to this.
Fine.
Here.
Do not worry.
I am a robot.
It doesn't matter how bitter...
It's clear that it's showing some effect.
What in the world did Inaho make?
Oh! Everyone!
What?
Do I taste that bad?
Robonyan Type-F...
What is this?
Swallowed Union!
Ultimate Robonyan!
What a combination!
Priming missile systems.
We turned into missiles!
What kind of plan is this?
I can never stop dancing!
Fire!
Yes!
I...
Go!
Let's go!
There's just one world!
One Million Paws of Fury!
I...
Kanami...
I've... heard...
...from your ballet school...
...about your legs.
That the doctors said...
If you work towards rehabilitation...
You will move your legs again.
It might take some time....
...but you'll do ballet again.
Easy for you to say!
What do you know about me?
I've risked everything for ballet!
I've practiced more than anyone!
It was my purpose.
I won't abandon myself on this world.
A world without hope for me.
That's why I wanted to erase this world.
Anything and everything.
Kanami.
Kanami...
Did you want to erase every precious thing?
Even the feelings of the people who supported you?
You teacher, she showed me...
So this.... This is the rehabilitation plan that I've made for her.
A little at a time.
In time, she can overcome.
Someday, she'll be able to dance again.
The goal is...
...in about 3 years.
She'll be able to compete in the Nationals.
It's not just a fantasy.
However...
...It's up to her...
To make the first step.
If she does it only half-heartedly...
...she won't be able to overcome the rehabilitation process.
Her ballet...lifts the spirits of people watching.
And her smile encourages everyone.
She has also made me quite quite happy.
Kanami...
Ballet isn't just her purpose.
She has a gift for it.
I thought because I wasn't able to dance
People were separating from me.
You weren't being separated.
People weren't separating from you!
You were separating yourself!
Kanami...
Do you remember?
When you were practicing hard with everyone?
I'm Kanami Minami!
Let's work together!
Let's practice together from now on.
Kanami.
We'll be waiting for you.
I was the only one who gave up on me?
Only me?
What was I doing this whole time?
For me to not notice such an important thing.
It's thanks to you that I've remembered.
My dream isn't mine alone.
It's also the dream of those who support me.
Kanami, you can do it.
You even have the power to create such a terrifying yo-kai.
Whisper!
Your ballet is that good!
There's nothing to worry about!
I'm sorry for dragging your world into this.
But it's fascinating.
I couldn't believe that you were from a different world.
Uh-huh. Me too.
But...
This world has so many details...
In other words, I'm really into pores now.
Pores?
Goodbye, Keita.
Thank you very much.
Huh?
Chocobars! Chocobars! Chocobars!
Keita! What are you looking at?
N-N-N....
Nothing at all!
What is it? What is it?
What is it What is it What is it
I told you, it's nothing!
Oh! Since when did you get that?
That's forbidden love! Forbidden!
But it's okay!
My feelings could get strong enough...
...to link this world with the other one!
Oh geez.  What are you even trying to do?
Ah!
What?
Your face! Your face!
Ah! Run away!
What's gotten into him?
Geeeh!
Who's this old man?
Gimme a break!
Subtitled and translated by Noroinohanako. Not for sale or rent.
King Enma
What about the next movie?
I wonder...
Fourth Movie publicly confirmed for Winter 2017