Busters Treasure Volume
Is that another treasure hunter?
We can't let them get ahead!
Wait!
Trying to get yourselves killed?
Treasure hunting is no walk in the park.
Poisoned arrow.
Poison?
They trying to kill us?
A real trap would have massacred us.
We're finally here.
But it isn't ours yet.
As expected of the Great Great Great Adventurer, Indie Jaws!
Oh my shark!
How did it come to this?
Everything started 24 hours ago.
I would have never imagined that this would happen then.
I didn't think this would be here!
24 hours ago...
Great Great Great Adventure! Busters Treasure!
In this world, there are ancient ruins.
But all ruins all share the same thing.
Indie Jaws
Does everyone know?
I don't know
Treasures and other valuables sleep beneath all of them.
I want treasures!
Uh-huh uh-huh!
You guys kinda look like treasures though.
I don't get it.
...as well as countless traps for unsuspecting adventurers.
Traps that are waiting to take a life.
Uh-huh
Will Professor Indie go to an ancient ruin again?
Ha! Of course I'd like to go. But I don't go with people that need handholding.
Indie Jaws...
...humbly teaching history in grammar school...
...while also a specialist expert on every type of ancient ruin.
You are...?
I am...
What!?
That's dirty!
Umm... More importantly, who are you?
I've said it already.
My name is Are Bachiino! (That's dirty!)
Are Bachino (That's dirty!)
That's a name?
There's a treasure that I want you to find for me.
Treasure?
That's dirty...!
What is with this guy?
The name of that treasure is...
The Great Treasure Yo-kai Yoderusen
Yoderusen!?
Do you have any information on it?
Yes. It's said to be hibernating somewhere for a long time.
It's a great treasure class of yo-kai.
It surpasses every yo-kai imaginable.
And it's said to have an incredibly rare ability.
This is...
That is unmistakably the yo-kai medal of the Great Treasure Yo-kai Yoderusen.
But as you can see, it has turned to stone...
...and has lost all its power.
Find the Yoderusen emblem...
...put the medal inside of it...
...and you'll be able to call out to the Great Treasure Yo-kai Yoderusen!
Oh my shark...
If you've got the knowledge, you can decipher this map...
...and you should be able to find the emblem.
So, Professor Jaws...
...can I rely on you?
Now is the time to go on an adventure!
I'll have to refuse!
I must apologize. As you like, you'll be compensated for...
That's not what I meant.
I don't go on adventures.
Why? You just told your students that you'd like to go on adventures.
You...
Are you trying to...
...get me killed!?
Are you trying to get me killed?
I have never gone out on a real adventure before!
I'm an air adventurer!
Air... adventurer?
Eh? Huh?
Like how air guitar doesn't involve real guitars,
An air adventurer doesn't go out on real adventures.
I just take in the suspense of adventuring while...
..seeing adventure movies and sipping tea.
It's a lifestyle without risk or injury.
What nonsense. You're just an indoorsman, aren't you?
If you've got the knowledge, you can decipher this map...
...and you should be able to find the treasure.
I can't live up to your expectation.
One last thing...
...about Yoderusen's extremely rare ability.
And that is...
... the ability to change...
...yo-kai into humans... and humans into yo-kai...
I'm not interested.
Going on an adventure for real? You're kidding me.
It's too dangerous.
Living life together with my little sister Cindy is the most important thing.
I'm home!
We'll be eatting an entire seal alive for dinner tonight!
Just kidding!
Welcome home, big brother!
What the shark is this!?
Huh? What's wrong?
W-Who...
W-Who are you?
Why is there a human in the house?
Cindy! Cindy! Where are you, Cindy!
What are you talking about? I'm right here.
Liar!
You're a human!
What are you saying?
What the shark?
That shark-like reaction...!
Are you really... Cindy?
What in the world happened to me?
Big Brother!
What is this indescribable feeling?
First of all, those teeth...
That jagged look that our family inherited is gone!
And that skin!
That skin is smooth and silky like the skin of a baby!
What happened to the Jaws family's shark skin?
And those eyes!
They look so alive.
What happened to the dead eyes of a shark?
Imagining this form trying to swim, It's completely ridiculous...
...the ambience is completely off.
No!
I want to turn back into a yo-kai!
How pitiful...
But what can we do?
What's this?
It's medal and map for Yoderusen...
That guy from earlier!
...Yoderusen's extremely rare ability...
... the ability to change yo-kai into humans and humans into yo-kai...
If I can find Yoderusen,
...I should be able to change Cindy back into a Shark yo-kai...
Don't tell me...
That he turned Cindy into a human to get me to find Yoderusen...
Big brother...
My hip moves differently from before.
Grr... Cindy...
I will find Yoderusen for you!
I'll definitely turn you back into a yo-kai!
Hello?
The plan looks back on track.
Boss! Sorry about that, boss.
If this plan fails, you know what happens, right?
I wonder what will happen to you...
It'll be bad if I don't take more precautions...
It doesn't matter who finds Yoderusen first, as long as we have it at the end.
All of the world's treasure hunters, go!
Take these maps, find the treasure and make a name for yourselves!
Cindy... wait for me.
Have a safe trip.
Crap... Be more reserved about those poses.
On a real adventure, I should bring him along.
dig... dig... dig... dig...
dig... dig... dig... dig... dig...
Hey! I've come.
climb... climb... climb... climb...
Good morning, Mr.Scoop.
Scoop morning!
As always, I've dug out a few items on my digging adventure today.
Let's imagine a new air adventure while looking at them!
No. Today is different.
I need to go out on a real adventure.
A-Are you for real?
Cindy... Something really serious has happened to her.
Can you stops talking like that?
For this charming power to dig into her... it's not so bad...
No way this is any good!
In any case...
I need to find the Great Treasure yo-kai Yoderusen.
If we can analyze this map...
We should be able to find our treasure.
Mr. Scoop, don't you think so?
Our experience with air adventures should still serve us well in a real adventure.
There's no doubt about that.
It should be useful in any ancient ruin!
Of course!
So in that case, don't you want to come with me?
I've got good news and I've got bad news.
Which do you want to hear first?
Huh? Right now?
Well then... Give me the bad news.
I am...
I am not going!
No way! I can't go! I don't want to go!
Then what's the good news?
I've dug dugged out something
And got my hands on this.
Another medal that turned to stone.
And also these too.
What are those?
These are also ancient items.
I've also repaired them.
...And its name is...
Yo-kai Pod.
Did you name these?
Nope!
I've also dug digged these out too!
Those were there too...
And this is Treasure Gear Magnum.
I understand.
Treasure Link!
Awesome!
It works like this?
Are you serious?
How do you know how to use it?
Isn't it written on this picture?
I'll leave the scoop to you.
Hey!
Yo-kai Watch!
And so, I've set out for the ancient ruins by myself after all.
Tch... This is the worst.
Why am I here all by myself?
Oh my shark!
I was afraid of going alone!
Ouch... Ouch...
Are you okay?
What's with this? I thought there were going to be scary animals.
W-Well, Sharks do count as scary animals though.
Isn't that a map to Yoderusen?
That's right.
We're here on our way to find Yoderusen!
I'm Jibanyan
I'm Komasan!
I'm also trying to find it!
Is it possible... that your family also turned into humans?
I just thought it would be interesting...
...if I used Yoderusen's power to turn into a human.
There's all kinds of fun!
How useless...
See you later!
Bye!
No good. At this rate, I'll be left alone again.
That's right!
Wait guys, don't you want to go on this adventure with me?
Not particularly.
They say it's dangerous to go with strangers.
Hey!
I know a lot about ancient ruins.
How do you know a lot?
Who are you in the first place?
I'm...
I'm..
I'm Indie Jaws!
I'm a great expert on great adventures! I'm a Great Great Great Adventurer!
A Great Great Great Adventurer! That sounds kinda awesome!
Beginner's Temple
Whew, it's a relief I found someone to partner with.
Is he really an adventurer?
Doesn't "Great Great Great" have too many Greats in it?
I'm being suspected!
I need to find something useful to show them...
That slope...
Wait!
What?
Are you trying to get killed?
In a dungeon...
..there are traps waiting to take the lives of unsuspecting adventurers!
Do you guys think...
...that this is springtime? With weather ideal for casual strolling...
...where you bring lunch with octopus sasages prepared by your mom...
...to enjoy in some kind of picnic?
That's a really long example...
Look! Look at this ramp!
What is going on with this ramp?
Indie Jaw's Adventuring Lesson One...
Whenever there is a ramp, remember that boulders will roll down!
That is a usual thing in an adventure.
That's why you proceed with caution.
As expected from a Great Great Great Adventurer!
Good. This looks fine.
Let's go.
If you don't check the sides, this might happen. So be careful.
Why don't you be careful?
Let's go.
You guys! Are you trying to get killed! Look around before...
Look around befor...
There's paths to the sides! Go into them!
Oh shark!
How does that work?
Oh crap! Oh crap! Oh crap! Oh crap!
What was that?
We're finally here.
But it isn't ours yet.
I haven't seen an adventurer like this before.
Looks like that trick worked.
As expected of the Great Great Great Adventurer Indie!
Hmm...
Don't let your guard down. This treasure hunt ends when you get home.
Didn't you let your guard down?
Oh shark!
Do something!
That's right...!
Shark!
Nothing's happening!
Like I thought, it's useless!
My medal is glowing!
What's this?
Like this?
Seems like it can fire off something incredible.
Dogushakko!
Eat this!
Treasure paws of fury!
You go, me!
Oh crap oh crap...
Oh no! It's not reacting anymore!
Dogushakko!
Use my power...
That's the medal Mr.Scoop gave me...
I'm borrowing this!
okurete kakurete hi ga kurete
kure kuretara kure kure
Kurekurepatra
Dogushakko!
So this is this dungeon's treasure...
So this isn't the Great Treasure Yo-kai Yoderusen after all...
Gimme gimme!
What is that?
There is only one path to Yoderusen...
...that is to open a path to these other treasure yo-kai.
There's seven left to collect?
I will gather all of them. For sure.
Dig dig dig dig...
Mr. Scoop
I'm back.
Indie! Are you still scooping alive?
Yes. Somehow.
Anyway, what were you digging for?
Ehh... I'm scooping nothing...
That's... my grave!
There's no mistaking it!
Professor Indie...
I've heard there's many traps in ancient ruins...
Have you ever fallen into one?
Heh... oh for sure.
But is there anyone who would fall for a trap this basic?
No one would.
Someone who is a Great Great Great class of Adventurer like me...
...can go home without a single scratch.
Now excuse me...
Today's yo-kai medalium...
Keita! What's today's yo-kai?
Treasure medals!
Hey everyone! I'm Indie Jaws.
I'm a Great Great Great Adventurer!
This is Jibanyan and Komasan.
Starting today, don't miss our great great great adventures!
What's with this?
In the next Yo-kai Watch...
Yo-tube showdown?
We Yo-tubers also battle for views by uploading videos!
But you've got only 2 views!
Komasan's got 500 million views?