I am Indy Jaws.
I'm an expert on adventures.
I am a Great Great Great Adventurer.
In order to return my sister back into a yo-kai...
...I am searching for treasure yo-kai today.
Oh no!
My hat!
Don't fuss over a hat!
How did this happen?
Everything started 3 hours ago.
At the time. I couldn't have seen something like this coming...
I couldn't have expected anything like this!
Three hours ago
Let me introduce to you...
This is my adventuring friend, Mr. Scoop.
Nice to scoop you!
Well... Me and Indy are adventuring friends, but...
We don't do real adventures. We do air adventures...
We just see adventure movies and get excited by watching them...
Um...
Me and Mr.Scoop have been on several great adventures together.
As can be expected of a Great Great Great Adventurer!
Wasn't he about to say something...?
Maybe...
I'm Komasan!
Nice to meet you, Mister Mr.Scoop!
I'm Jibanyan!
I've been going on adventures with these guys to find the treasure yo-kai.
Well, we're fine on our own without Indy though.
Going on adventures alone is too scary!
Please just play along!
Umm....
I've held on to some spare equipment for you guys as you go on your adventures with Indy.
I've found some more as I was digging around.
These use medals to shoot out awesome things!
I see.
If you were to pull the trigger while aiming at fire or water, it will suck it in.
...and then it will shoot those things out.
For real?
You didn't read the instructions?
Those are long instructions though.
Let's test this out on that lit candle.
Aim at the fire and pull the trigger...
It really sucked it in!
So to shoot it out, pull the trigger again?
This is awesome!
What are you trying to do to my precious hat!?
If I sucked this in...
I can save it for eating later!
Preparations for the adventure are...
...complete!
Okay!
The next ruin we are heading to...
...is over here!
Cindy. I will definitely return you to your original form.
Falling Wall Ruins
After analyzing the map, I can say...
There's a strong possibility that a treasure yo-kai is here.
Then let's hurry and charge straight in!
Wait!
Are you trying to get killed?
There are countless traps just waiting for you!
Those who die first are those who get caught up in the moment!
And also traitors...
...those who talk about their family...
...and "I'm going home and getting married"
People like that always die!
As expected of Indy, the Great Great Great Adventurer.
Are those just from adventure movies?
Let's go.
Indy!
Is he really going to be alright coming along with us?
The way back just got blocked!
Hurry! At this rate, we'll be trapped.
Oh no, my hat!
Oh no!
It's finally time to use this!
Treasure paws of fury!
Oh dear, what power.
How's Indy?
My hat seems fine.
You were about to die because you were fussing about that hat.
You should have just let it go!
Hats are important for adventurers.
The reason is because the hat is cool.
But not just that...
This hat...
...holds some precious memories.
Not intererested.
It's another falling wall.
But it's much slower, so no need to hurry going through.
That's right.
Oh, my hat.
I'll save him!
'Why did ice cream come out?
I forgot that it sucked that in last time.
Good grief...
If I weren't wearing my hat, I would have suffocated.
Still trying to act cool even though you're covered with ice cream.
As expected of a Great Great Great Adventurer!
We've found it!
It's treasure!
It looks like it's locked
Leave it to me.
Indy, you can pick open locks?
Hah. In my hands, this is a piece of cake.
That's incredible.
Two hours later...
What...? Crap... Why...?
Four hours later...
Open... Why you....open already...
Open... huh...?
Open..!
Open already!
Six hours later...
Eight hours later...
Let's take a little break...
It's not open yet?
If even the Great Great Great  Adventurer Indy can't open it...
...then this is an incredible box then...
What the...
That box...!
What's inside of it?
T-This is...
It's ice cream!
Bon appétit
My teeth hurts.
I hate this kind of chocobar!
Crap!
What was all that effort for?
Isn't there anything else? Anything?
Oh my shark!
Yo-kai are all around you.
You can't see them but,...
They might even be causing trouble around you right now.
For example,
After watching a Hollywood movie, everything always explodes...
This happen sometimes.
Everything is caused by yo-kai.
Let's use the Yo-kai Watch now....
...and try to find those troublesome yo-kai.
Let's battle for view counts on Yo-tube!
Keita, what are you looking at?
It's a huge video posting site!
There are so many interesting videos being uploaded everyday, I can't look away!
Speaking of which...
Something similar is in the yo-kai world.
Eh? Really?
Yes. And it is called Yo-tube.
Yo-tube?
Yes.
Yo-kai who upload videos to Yo-tube are called Yo-tubers.
And they compete for views everyday.
Maybe Whisper is also doing it too.
*shock!*
That reaction was predictable.
Whisper Channel!
Eh? You've uploaded a lot haven't you.
Whisper recording his own face while sleeping?
Whoa! Gross!
Is there anything else?
Whisper trying to swipe on his tablet at high speed?
What is this? But you do this all the time.
You're used to seeing it, but this is really fast!
People will want to see it for sure!
But you've got only 2 views though.
No no, people are definitely talking about it.
These are all your own comments though!
Well... It's just that the rest of the world...
... hasn't realized how interesting I am yet!
I should be quickly getting more popular very soon.
What kinds of videos are popular on Yo-tube?
Umm... Oh!
This one seems to have an incredible amount of views.
Komasan tries to be Gomasan?
What does that mean?
Let's play this immediately.
I always have vanilla ice cream, but now I'm having black sesame goma flavored ice cream.
Look, it's goma-san!
Komajiro, was that okay?
Big brother, that was perfect!
Why are you pointing the camera at me?
I'm going to upload this video on to Yo-tube so everyone can see my big brother!
I'm being seen by everyone right now?
Umm.... Nice to meet you.
I am Komasan.
Big brother, you're acting way too nervously.
Isn't that how Komasan acts normally?
The views for this should be pretty low...
Incredible, the number of views is 500 million.
What?
And there's also a lot of commenters too!
It's very popular!
And no comments are self-written, unlike in Whisper's videos.
What do I have to do with the Koma brothers? Please stop accusing me.
Ok. Next... next...
Who is the strongest? Orochi and Kyubi strike decisively in black and white.
What? Orochi and Kyubi are going to fight each other?
Who's the strongest between those two?
Whisper! Hurry and show us!
Yes. yes. Pressing play.
Who is the strongest? Orochi and Kyubi strike decisively in black and white.
I'm coming for you!
Come at me.
It's my turn now.
Not too shabby.
You too.
Don't just stop it there on your own!
Yeah! I want to know who wins!
No no, they're just striking black and white stones in a game of Go.
The number of views is definitely going to be lo...
T-T-T-T-Ten trillion views!?!?
Why is that? Aren't they just playing around in this video?
In the world of yo-kai, Orochi and Kyubi are the two biggest stars!
I just got really interested for some reason.
Although if you did the same, Whisper, I won't watch it.
I don't understand it!
Ah. I get it!
In short, all I need to do is to grab everyone's attention, right?
Huh?
In other words, I should do anything as long as it will grab people's attention, right?
No, that's wrong I think..
And so...
Keita!
Please call out to Bushinyan immediately.
Uh... Okay.
I've been waiting for you.
Please cut me without hesitation!
What are you thinking, Whisper?
If I do bizarre things that no one else does, I'll be sure to grab some attention!
May I really cut you?
Bring it on!
Very well.
Here I come!
Straight Across the Middle of a Popularity Seeking Yo-kai Slash!
Yaaagh!
And now to upload the video.
What? You were filming just now?
Look at the number of views!
What? Six views?
I did it!
I got six views!
It's three times more than my previous video!
He did that for just six views?
Let's upload some more extreme videos, just like this!
I did it! My views are now finally...
...in the double digits!
I'm home.
Huh?
Whisper isn't home yet.
He wasn't with you, Keita?
He said he came up with an impossibly extreme idea for a video and ran off...
I-I-It's terrible!
What's wrong, Hikkikomori?
Please look at this...
Whisper's Channel Special?
"Wake Lord Enma Daioh From His Sleep Challenge"?
What the?
No way!
Good morning everyone!
Today's challenge is to wake Lord Enma Daioh from his sleep.
I've brought this with me today!
What? That's my yo-kai bazooka!
Don't tell me he's going to fire that to wake him!
Looks like he's deep in sleep.
And now here I go.
Three... Two...
Hey you bastard!
What are you doing?
Oh, it's Nurarihyon.
U-Umm... Don't tell me. You're mad right?
Come with me for second.
This is punishment!
...don't take my life!
Sukiyaki....
Whisper...
He might not be coming back...
You got that right.
This video has been deleted by the administration.
hctaw iak-oY
Wow! That was really good!
Yo-kai D-Rex
It's been a while since we've seen an awesome movie like that!
It was really impressive with all the overwhelming explosions
Isn't that right!
Especially that very last part, when the bomb in the tanker exploded.
I've always wanted to be in a showy action movie like that.
Thirty seconds until explosion.
What? Explosion?
Twenty seconds until explosion.
Is it red one...?
...or the blue one?
Four.
Three.
Two.
One
I'm sav...
What?
What happened, Keita?
I was... caught in an explosion...
Did you see that in your dream?
How was that? Was it thrilling and exciting?
Don't tell me...
Whisper, what's that yo-kai?
Yes, I know that one of course.
That yo-kai looks like a dinosaur so it must be yo-kai Jurassic Pa...
That's not it...
It looks kinda like a giant monster so it must be yo-kai Shin Godzill...
No that's nothing like him...
Err... That's right! It's yo-kai D-Rex!
D-Rex
Explosions are awesome!
Super punchy explosions are the real thrill of Hollywood movies.
Uhahahah!
Well... I certainly do like those kinds of movies...
Isn't that right?
So... All day long today, like a Hollywood action movie...
...let's have thrills and excitement continuously!
What...?
What? Again?
What's this? What's this situation?
We're shaking off pursuers!
Geez. The only thing I want to be chased by are cute girls.
Heh.
Only unpopular guys say stuff like that.
Hey, do you really want to hear why I'm so popular right now?
Let's hear all about it later.
Ha ha! Yes!
We did it!
And now...
BOOM!
Ke-Keita?
What?
Thanks!
Keita!
Did you do your homework?
After... I finish this...
Oh no! I'm trapped!
What? Even right now?
This is what you'd call a hopeless situation.
You can never enough lives when you're around.
But it never mattered. We've always broken our way through.
Right?
Yeah. Let's go, partner.
You still alive, partner?
Yeah. This doesn't look like heaven.
You belong in hell though.
Let's leave that discussion for later.
And...now...
BOOM!
Keita!
Mom!?
Stop always playing games and do your homework!
You still alive, partner?
This doesn't look like heaven.
This is...
*gasp*
D-Rex
D-Rex!
And...now...
BOOM!
No, I don't think we needed that.
Ah.. Yes.
Today's yo-kai medalium...
Keita! What's today's yo-kai?
D-Rex!
Oh no!
Help us!
Whisperman!
Eighteen...
In the next Yo-kai Watch...
Last Bushinyan's studies?
The legendary merican yo-kai, Last Bushinyan...
...is Studying
What? Tomnyan is teaching him?
Is that really ok?