I am Indy Jaws
An expert on adventures!
I am a Great Great Great Adventurer!
In order to change my human little sister back into a yo-kai...
I'm searching for the treasure yo-kai!
Don't tell me...
We just got eatten!
How did it come to this?
Everything started 12 hours ago.
I wouldn't have imagined that this would happen then.
I couldn't have expected anything like this!
Busters Treasure Chapter
12 hours ago
In my professional opinion, as a Great Great Great Adventurer...
The next place we should look...
Is right over here!
However...
To reach this treasure, we need his help this time.
We need his cooperation!
We need
His
Cooperation!
Let's go, Mr. Scoop!
What are you saying?
You should already know that I go on air adventures, not real ones.
Watching adventures in movies is enough.
Why is that?
Err... I meant...
I'd love to go, however I have a shop to run.
Take care. Adieu.
But if you come with us, you can dig as much as you want.
What did you just say?
The place that we're headed is Saba Saba Desert, Ari Ari Ari Hell.
This treasure seems to be buried quite deep.
In other words...
We need someone like you, Mr.Scoop.
I understand!
Let's dig!
Dig dig dig with all your might!
Why do you like digging so much?
Do you...
Do you really want to dig there?
If you keep digging at that topic...
...You're never going to come back the same.
That seems like a pretty scary episode.
Well... the statute of limitations passed, so I'll talk if you want.
Statute of limitations?
This smells like a crime!
It all happened under here, about five years ago
What is this?
This smells like a real serious crime!
Do you want to dig deeper?
Ok, let's stop.
Please forgive us!
Ok! So are we settled?
Let's do this!
So this is Ari Ari Ari Hell?
So treasure is waiting right below us, right?
Let's dig now!
Wait!
Are you trying to get yourselves killed?
If you dig here carelessly...
You'll get swallowed by the sand, and never come out alive!
It's like if you're going out with your girlfriend to the beach and burying each other to the neck with sand!
That explanation was way too long, as usual.
As expected of the Great Great Great Adventurer Indy!
Good! No problem.
Let's go
Oh my shark!
Treasure Link!
Leave the digging to me
What is with that shovel?
It's attached to a Yo-kai Pod!
Let's start digging!
dig dig dig...
Mr.Scoop is amazing!
Dig dig dig...
Okay. Let's follow after!
Wait Mr. Scoop! We've gone too far! Stop right now!
Dig dig... huh?
Are you...
...trying to stop me?
P-Please go on!
Please dig as much as you want!
Got it!
Dig dig dig...
Mr.Scoop's personality changes that much when they've stopped digging.
That's an understatement.
Bringing Mr.Scoop along might have been a mistake.
Dig dig dig...
What's up?
It's snakes.
Please, Mr.Scoop. Be more careful while digging.
Really?
Dig dig dig...
Doesn't seem like Mr.Scoop is doing anything differently.
Why does Mr.Scoop lose their sense of direction while digging?
What's that?
Do you...
...want to dig that up?
We don't! We don't!
We'll just leave the digging to you!
Got it!
Dig dig dig...
What?
What is it this time?
What's with that arrow?
We should dig that way.
Wait! That's clearly a trap!
Dig dig dig...
Wait! Don't dig any further!
It's a secret passageway!
It's another arrow.
This way huh?
Hey wait!
Let's go!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
You're going to get caught in this obvious trap!
What's this?
Don't tell me...
We just got eatten!
Somehow, we escaped inside its eggs.
That was a great adventure!
I want to do that again!
As you wish. Let's dig once more!
Oh... Let's not dig anymore!
Are you...
...trying to stop me?
No!
Yo-kai are all around you.
You can't see them but,...
They might even be causing trouble around you right now.
For example,
When you get so tired, you fall dead asleep and can't even wake up.
This happen sometimes.
Everything is caused by yo-kai.
Let's use the Yo-kai Watch now....
...and try to find those troublesome yo-kai.
kin kira kin ni goorudo ga ichiban
Flashy, glittering gold is the very best
pikka pika na goorudo ga ichiban
Shining, sparkling gold is the very best
miryoku to maryoku to jitsueki de
With its glamor and its charm and all its benefits
goorudo ikooru manee ga suteki
Gold equals money, how lovely, but
yume mo kibou mo chii mo meiyo mo
Our hopes and dreams and our status and prestige
kaenai mono wa aru wakenai
Are things that can't be bought, they certainly cannot
tte na koto ittara bachi ataru
When you say things like that, it’s like I've been punished
yo no naka namecha ikenai yo
You can't be naïve about the world we live in
kin kira kin wa mitame dake
Some things only appear to be glittering like gold on the outside
nakami ga kirari to hikatte hoshii
You want the inside to be shining and sparkling too
sariganaku sariganaku aa sariganaku
You’re casually, casually, aah, casually hoping
mihararashi yosageni haruka uekara
From all the way up here I can get a good view
te wo furukimi ga suwatteru no wa
Of you sitting there waving to me
dondon fukuramu kiniro no fuusen
On a golden balloon that’s steadily growing in size
waretara taihen da
(It’d be pretty bad if it popped)
juubun wakatteta hazu darou
I thought I had it all figured out perfectly this time
nanoni mata kurikaesu no ne
But even so, the pattern repeats itself again, huh?
nodo mo tosugide atsusa wasure
Danger past and it’s forgotten
meguru mekuru yo jinsei gekijou
And so the stage show that is life plays over and over again
yo no naka namecha ikenaiyo
You can't be naïve about the world we live in
kin kira kin wa mitame dake
Some things only appear to be glittering like gold on the outside
nakami ga kirai to hikatte hoshii
You want the inside to be shining and sparkling too
sariganaku sariganaku aa sariganaku
You’re casually, casually, aah, casually hoping
The Tengu's Fierce Battle
It's a good thing we went hiking!
The air is so fresh, isn't it.
Geez
What?
Hey... Wait...
Stop right there!
Hey guys!
There they go.
That wind just now was suspicious.
It's got to be the work of a yo-kai!
Too bad!
Don't you think it's natural for the wind to blow that way on a mountain?
For you to put that kind of blame on a yo-kai...
See? It's here.
Oh!
What yo-kai is this?
Oh! Of course I know that one!
That has got to be...
...A handsome yo-kai...
...a blue-faced yo-kai...
...something of that sort...
What's this?
This is the yo-kai Karasu-tengu!
Karasutengu
A legendary classic yo-kai who controls the wind and flies in the air!
Oh Karasutengu-senpai!
Whisper, you're always looking up to classic yo-kai.
Speaking of which, don't tengu usually have long noses?
Karasutengu's nose is not long.
That's right.
What did you just say?
I was thinking that even if you were a tengu, you don't have a long nose like one.
Please stop with the wind!
Why did you do that?
All we said was that you didn't have a big nose!
Don't tell me you're insecure about your nose!
How could you say that to me!?
Hey!
Cut it out!
Tengu!
That's right.
I am the a true tengu.
My long nose is the proof.
A tengu doesn't need a long nose to be a tengu!
In that case, have a look at this.
After surveying six million of the nation's children...
"The most memorable part of a tengu" is overwhelmingly...
The long nose!
Well, there it is.
Of course...
Karasutengu...
The long nose is the proof of a true tengu!
Crap...
Why are you so fussy about the nose?
That's...
Hey
Who are you?
I'm Karasutengu
But your nose isn't long.
Your nose is seriously not very long
That's super funny!
Nose... nose... nose...!
Everyone else fusses over the nose!
Why do they acknowledge the long nose?
But they never acknowledge me?
Let's decide whether you're a tengu with a tengu battle!
Tengu battle?
What is that?
That is how tengu settle matters ever since long ago.
Anyway, you don't seem to remember me.
Eh? Umm...
Of course we remember, right Jibanyan?
You're Nekuramatengu!
What are you doing here?
I live right here.
Is that so?
I came over to referee the tengu battle.
Referee?
Every time these two have a quarrel, I come over to referee them.
They have quarrels that often?
Alright. Let's get this started.
This time, whoever loses this battle leaves this mountain.
Okay?
I say the exact same thing back to you!
Whoa. This looks kind of serious.
This battle has three matches.
This first match will decide who can fly the fastest.
The fastest one will bring back the fan on the summit of that mountain.
Take your places... Ready...
Go!
I don't intend to lose!
That's my line!
They're both so fast!
Here's the result of the first match...
Karasutengu got ten points. Tengu got zero.
It's not over yet!
The second match is a wind battle.
Who can cause the biggest winds?
Let's go!
Ready? Go!
Keita's completely naked!
Keita!
Here's the result of the second match.
Karasutengu gets zero points. Tengu gets ten points.
It's a tie!
It's not time to get excited. Hurry up and wear your clothes!
Third match
Geta sandals are important for a tengu.
Whoever can kick them off the furthest is the winner.
Geta kicking?
I wonder what will happen.
The winner of this match will get a hundred points.
In other words, whoever wins the third match is the winner of this battle.
So the first and second matches basically have no meaning...
You haven't forgotten the promise that the loser leaves this mountain, right?
I was going to say the same.
Well! Then let's begin the final match!
Alright! Get ready! Go!
I guess I'll do the same.
H-H-How could this be?
The one who kicked it out the furthest is Nekuramatengu!
Umm... In other words.
That means that Nekuramatengu won the battle?
Seems like Nekuramatengu was the dark horse!
Is that even possible?
Who could have predicted such an outcome?
What a failure.
Nekuramatengu, you can do it when you try!
I didn't think I would lose to him.
But a deal is a deal.
Here's a reward for helping with the battle.
Take it.
Thanks a lot!
Nobody could have predicted that I would win but...
But for me to win a tengu battle like this...heh heh.
I couldn't have seen this coming either.
Something Watch!
I'm home...
Yo-kai Batan Q
Welcome home -nyan!
Welcome home!
Conk out
Keita, you're already asleep?
He was up late last night reading comics so he's conking out.
What does it mean to conk out?
To fall asleep like this. Conk out.
To fall asleep like this means to conk out.
By the way, the sound that I make when I conk out is "sponpee"!
Pop!
What is that?
Who is that?
That yo-kai! Of course I know what that is!
It's got a ring on it so it must be Ringy or something.
Or maybe it's Big Beany, like a broad bean!
I found it!
That's the yo-kai Batan Q!
You were completely wrong!
Let's conk out!
Batan Q
A yo-kai who cause people who come back home to collapse on their beds and conk out.
A legendary yo-kai that tired people can be thankful for!
A legendary yo-kai?
That's correct
So it was you who caused Keita to conk out just now right?
He seemed pretty tired.
That's why I used my soutimate move.
Soultimate?
Yep. Its name is...
Sanzu River Eternal Slumber
Sanzu River Eternal Slumber?
Right now, Keita is having a relaxing time on Sanzu river.
What!?
He was floating there the whole time that we were talking!
That's where people go to get to the afterlife, right?
Hey! Putting him there was a terrible idea!
As long as he doesn't make it to the other side, he's fine.
How is someone supposed to relax in a place like that?
If you're so worried, then take a look.
Can we see through that?
Let's Batan!
So this is Sanzu River
So nice
Oh man. Reading comics late last at night really tired me out.
We went on hike so long that our knees ached.
Isn't that right, Komajiro?
That's right. We got a little tired.
I was also busying with the company.
Company?
It's really nice to relax in outdoor places like this sometimes
It's so much fun.
This is such a nice place.
It's like our own secret resort.
Our towels!
Hold it right there!
Keita!
Don't cross over!
You're going to cross into the afterlife!
What a relief.
Oh I thought I was gonna die!
Oh Keita! That was too close.
I've a bad feeling one of them actually crossed over though.
It's just your imagination.
Oh this feels good.
Floaty floaty
Such relaxation
This warms my heart
I want to be here forever.
Keita and others are floating to the other side!
What!? You're right!
Keita! Go back! Go back!
Keita! Hang in there!
Keita!
Go back!
Huh? Whisper?
Jibanyan?
Huh? We're getting carried away!
You're right!
We need to swim back!
I wasn't doing anything
Keita! Hurry! Hurry!
Just a little more!
That was close!
We were pretty close to the other side.
Keita made it out okay somehow.
I'm so tired from all that yelling.
Would you like to try going there as well?
Let's go to the Sanzu River! Q!
Huh?
Whisper? Jibanyan?
Where is this?
A river? Don't tell me!
This is the Sanzu River.
We're about to reach the other side now.
Wait wait wait!
nihinihinihi nihinihinihi
Smiling wide, smiling wide
nya nya shichau shi tanoshi shi
Because we’re grinning and having fun
hahihihinihi ihihii rooren
Laughing and smiling, rolling on the floor laughing
rooren rooren hai hai hoo
Rolling, rolling, hey hey ho
natsu no owari ha fuyu no hajimari
The end of summer is the beginning of winter
haroo uintaa iyoiyo harouin
Hello, winter, Halloween’s finally here
sore kara haro kurisumasu
And after that it’s hello Christmas
harokuri harokuri harokuri harokuri
Hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas
odotte odotte haro haro kuri kuri nennai ippai
Dancing and dancing to welcome Christmas, lots to do before the end of the year
kyou ha nani ni demo nareru hi
Today is a day when you can become anything
akakute marukute neko ga ii?
How about a chubby red cat?
koe no takai medama ha dou?
Or how about an eyeball with a loud voice?
umihousu kato omottara zura wo hazushita tonari no ojisan
The Umibozu I thought I saw disappeared and was replaced by an old man
hige wo tsuketara santa kuroosu
He looks like Santa Claus with that mustache
akai geehaa gojyushichi!
It’s the red game hardware 57!
asu kara kitto samuku naru
When tomorrow comes it will surely become cold outside
shiroi kisetsu ga kuru mae ni natsu no omoide katariai
Before the white season arrives, we’ll reminisce about summer memories
jakkurrantan minna wo terashi
Everyone will light their Jack-o-Lanterns
kurisumasu made mainichi paatii
Every day until Christmas will be a party
saa odorou otori tsudukeyou
So come on, let’s dance, let’s keep on dancing
harokuri harokuri harokuri harokuri
Hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas
odotte odotte haro haro kuri kuri
Dancing and dancing to welcome Christmas
nennai ippai nennai ippai
Lots and lots to do before the end of the year
Today's yo-kai medallium...
Keita! What's today's yo-kai?
Karasutengu and Batan Q!
Ahh I'm so tired
I'm going home and conking out.
Make sure you wash up first...
What!?!
You're conking out right here?
On the next Yo-kai Watch...
Yo-kai Bon Odori Dancing?
At this time of year just as humans do, we yo-kai also have a huge summer festival!
Oh no! Looks like a human girl got lost!
Translated and subtitled by Noroinohanako. Song lyric translation for OP and ED by @Manjiknight. Not for sale or rent.
What!?