I am Indy Jaws
An expert on adventures!
I am a Great Great Great Adventurer!
In order to change my human little sister back into a yo-kai...
I'm searching for the treasure yo-kai!
That was dangerous!
Don't move!
Are you kidding me?
Oh my shark!
How did it come to this?
Everything started three hours ago
I wouldn't have imagined that this would happen then.
I couldn't have expected anything like this!
Three hours ago
As a result of analysing the map...
I discovered a new dungeon where a treasure yo-kai is supposed to be sleeping.
Kokohazure Mountain Range Ruins
We can't go further!
What's with this rope?
That's right!
If we use this, we can cross ahead!
Wait!
Are you trying to get yourselves killed?
This rope might just be a setup for all kinds of traps!
When you're on a date with your girlfriend in the park and you see a small girl crying because her balloon's stuck to the tree, which you get for her,
"Oh! you're so wonderful!"
Don't naively believe that you'll always get her to think that of you!
As expected of the Great Great Great Adventurer Indy!
That example is way too long.
Listen, in this situation...
This could be a trap where the rope is weakened on purpose.
Or the ceiling could collapse from you pulling on it.
First off..
Check to see if the rope is ok.
Is that so?
Sorry for grabbing the rope even though there could have been a trap there...
Don't worry about it.
You need to learn from your mistakes as an adventurer.
Indy!
Now let's go!
Hah!
Oh my shark!
Indy!
He's making too many mistakes.
Good.
This rope definitely won't break this time.
Oh my shark!
Indy!
This time...
...the rope...
...won't break!
You'd be better off it it did break.
It's better if we didn't use that right right?
Let's find another way.
...oh...shark...
That was close!
Don't move!
Are you kidding me?
Oh my shark!
Sneezing in that situation. Unbelievable.
Sorry
You were the one that fell for that trap.
Those are two different things.
What is that?
There's another rope here!
K....K-Komasan, that's.....
That's not a rope!
You're the adventurer! Do something about that snake!
Don't be ridiculous!
Just looking at that snake...
...it's scary enough to give my sharkskin goosebumps!
Are you really getting goosebumps?
Oh no!
It's another cliff!
How deep do these ruins get?
There's a red rope and a blue rope!
Let's choose which ever you want to cross over!
I'll go with the blue rope because it's the same color as my eyebrows!
My body is red so I'll go with the red one!
Wait!
You trying to get yourselves killed?
The choice between red or blue...
Is a common pattern when defusing time bombs!
You'll need to choose the right one!
That snake is already this close!
Red... Blue... Red... Blue...
Hurry up an choose!
This one!
Oh my shark!
Oh no!
Indy!
Komasan! Hurry up!
Hurry and grab the red rope!
Ouch...
We've fallen quite far.
What's this soft thing?
It's a hot spring!
Kokohazure
Mountain Range Ruins
Entrance
Why did bring me out here?
Two hours later
Sorry! Sorry!
It's no good!
Four hours later
When... When are they going to stop chasing me...
Eight hours later
Stay.... away....!
Oh, that's right...
I forgot all about this.
I'm saved...
Oh you're finally back.
You two were fine?
We found this treasure as we were leaving.
Woah! That's incredible!
What kind of treasure is it?
Oh shark!
Snakes....
Why did it have to be snakes...?
Yo-kai are all around you.
You can't see them but,...
They might even be causing trouble around you right now.
For example,
You try different things, but you're not satisfied with anything.
This happen sometimes.
Everything is caused by yo-kai.
Let's use the Yo-kai Watch now....
...and try to find those troublesome yo-kai.
kin kira kin ni goorudo ga ichiban
Flashy, glittering gold is the very best
pikka pika na goorudo ga ichiban
Shining, sparkling gold is the very best
miryoku to maryoku to jitsueki de
With its glamor and its charm and all its benefits
goorudo ikooru manee ga suteki
Gold equals money, how lovely, but
yume mo kibou mo chii mo meiyo mo
Our hopes and dreams and our status and prestige
kaenai mono wa aru wakenai
Are things that can't be bought, they certainly cannot
tte na koto ittara bachi ataru
When you say things like that, it’s like I've been punished
yo no naka namecha ikenai yo
You can't be naïve about the world we live in
kin kira kin wa mitame dake
Some things only appear to be glittering like gold on the outside
nakami ga kirari to hikatte hoshii
You want the inside to be shining and sparkling too
sariganaku sariganaku aa sariganaku
You’re casually, casually, aah, casually hoping
mihararashi yosageni haruka uekara
From all the way up here I can get a good view
te wo furukimi ga suwatteru no wa
Of you sitting there waving to me
dondon fukuramu kiniro no fuusen
On a golden balloon that’s steadily growing in size
waretara taihen da
(It’d be pretty bad if it popped)
juubun wakatteta hazu darou
I thought I had it all figured out perfectly this time
nanoni mata kurikaesu no ne
But even so, the pattern repeats itself again, huh?
nodo mo tosugide atsusa wasure
Danger past and it’s forgotten
meguru mekuru yo jinsei gekijou
And so the stage show that is life plays over and over again
yo no naka namecha ikenaiyo
You can't be naïve about the world we live in
kin kira kin wa mitame dake
Some things only appear to be glittering like gold on the outside
nakami ga kirai to hikatte hoshii
You want the inside to be shining and sparkling too
sariganaku sariganaku aa sariganaku
You’re casually, casually, aah, casually hoping
Yo-kai Mosaku
It's Fumi-chan and friends.
Which should I buy?
They can't decide on which candy to buy it seems.
They seem to be really serious about it too.
Senbei it is!
How about Ramune?
How about a stick of dango?
Fumi-chan and her friends seem a little off
Not at all!
For girls to be troubled over which candy to buy...
...It's a pretty common problem.
But would they normally be troubled in that exact way?
Alright! Let's skip some stones!
Let's see who can skip the furthest!
Let's go!
Ooooh.... It's no good.....
What kind of stone should I be throwing?
How about a square?
Or a round one?
This one is too heavy to even lift!
Those two are acting weird!
This is the work of a yo-kai!
Oh Keita, you're needlessly blaming yo-kai again...
People are just concerned about trying out every ways of doing things.
There it is!
What?
Whisper! What is that?
Yes yes!
So um... that yo-kai... is wearing lumberjack clothing, so it's got to be... um... Lumberjack Gonnosuke or...
...or Treestump Gonnosuke or... It's got to be Gonnosuke something...
Oh I found it!
That's yo-kai Mosaku!
Mosaku
Mosaku?
Inspirited humans get indecisively inquisitive.
In other words, they try everything without deciding on anything!
As for the incidents that they cause...
You get anxious worrying about things while saying "That's not it! This isn't it!" continuously!
This yo-kai causes those things!
Um, Mosaku...
Can you stop inspiriting people and go somewhere else?
Is he even listening?
He looks he's got a lot on his mind to worry about...
In that case...
Come on out my friend, Jibanyan!
Yo-kai medal! Set on!
It's a pretty time!
Tempura Roulette!
Pretty! Pretty! What's going to come out?
Pretty. Pretty. Pretty!
The top best fried shrimp tempura!
Jibanyan
Jibanyan! Drive Mosaku out!
Leave it to me!
Paws of Fury!
This isn't good enough...
J....J-Jibanyan...
How should I eat a chocobar more deliciously?
Not like this...
Not with sauce...
Eatting it with spicy wasabi is too spicy!
Even Jibanyan?!
He seems completely inspirited...
That isn't good enough!
Is there a cooler way of wearing this Yo-kai Watch?
Not on the head!
Not on the leg!
It's too small to wear on the waist!
I've a feeling there's something better than this swirly thing to put on my head?
Ice cream isn't it.
A snake isn't it.
And Unchikuma's poo really stinks doesn't it?
Uugh! What's this?
Why is the chocobar covered in mayonnaise?
The swirl on my head!
Wait, Mosaku!
Why are you doing this?
Just why am I doing this?
How should I tell you this...?
Not as a video
Not as a powerpoint
A cardboard slide show won't do at all
Nah. You can just tell us normally.
Is that so?
Well even talking normally is a little hard though.
It was from before I became a yo-kai.
This sound won't do
How can I cut a tree in a way that sounds better?
So this was what you were fussing with...
Like a typical craftsman.
Who would fuss about something like that?
Oh! Look out!
And that's how I was reborn as a yo-kai.
And like always, I've been thinking "This isn't it, that isn't it."
W-Wait!
Those arms are getting longer again!
Even of the people around me, "He's not it, she's not it"
I've wound up thinking those kinds of thoughts.
What a troublesome person.
If there's a way of cutting a tree with a sound you're satisfied with, will it stop?
Maybe.
If you're going to cut something, you'd call him out right?
Good thing you called to me.
Chop that tree down! Do it with a good sound!
Leave it to me
Forty-to-Fifty-Year-Old-Lumber Slash!
As expected of Bushinyan!
That was a great sound!
Was that ok?
How should I put this... Not enough pleasant vibrations...
What? Was that no good?
Failure!
Even Bushnyan can't do it...
Well, in that case...
Karakuribenkei!
That isn't it!
Chikaramochi!
Tearing it isn't it!
Cut! Cut!
Cutting a bush is pointless!
Doesn't seem like we're hitting the right notes.
I wonder if we can use someone else...
Of course this yo-kai wouldn't work, right?
Of course! No way!
That'd be impossible.
You summoned it in the end though.
He called him alright.
Please! Onarazumono!
What!?
Why did it fart when he hit the tree?
What's he planning?
Oh...
Can you... let me...
...hear that one more time?
What a sound...
The way this tree cutting sounds... It's the first time...
... I've heard anything like this.
Of course.
It normally doesn't sound like this.
This is just a farting sound.
What a wonderful sound...
A sound that reveals your heart...
I've always wanted to hear this sound.
Thank you.
I can rest satisfied now.
Mosaku seems to be satisfied.
Let's go home.
This tree...
"So that sound was no good"
That's what is said...!
So the tree was the one that turned into Mosaku!?
The one that was fussing over the sound was the tree!?
Now that's a shocking truth.
Oh man. Yo-kai are beings that are still as mysterious as ever.
Well, now the number one mystery is this sound, right?
Let's leave this mystery alone.
Yeah.
Last Bushinyan's Japon's way of walking! "Onigiri"
Japon has various different cultures...
Oh! Are you interested in Japan?
You're...
Nice to meowtch you!
Tom is Tomnyan!
I'm Last Bushinyan
Oh my god, meow!
Are you that Merican yo-kai Last Bushinyan?
I'm so happy to meet you!
When did  you come to Japan?
I just arrived here.
How about Tomnyan?
Tom's been living here for a long time!
It's like I was born here!
That's really helpful! Please teach me more about Japon!
Tomnyan-dono
I mean, Tomnyan-senpai!
Tomnyan-senpai...?
That sounds great!
Tomnyan-senpai! Tomnyan-senpai! Tomnyan-senpai!
Ok, meow!
I'll teach you anything!
I'd like to ask you about these onigiri.
Oh! Of course I know about that!
I've eatten these before but...
...because it was so delicious, I'd like to eat them again!
So... please teach me how to make them!
How... to make them...?
Indeed
♫ Meow meow meow meow meow cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling meow cats meow!
Cats rolls turn & around like this! Cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling roll ♫
Perhaps you don't know...?
You don't know?
Of course I know that!
I know SO much that conversely I got really surprised!
As expected of Tomnyan-senpai!
So in that case, please teach me how to make onigiri!
L-L-Leave it to me!
Last!
An onigiri is made by cutting oni demons. That's why they're called "onigiri".
That's what Tomnyan-senpai told me!
Now, Red Oni-dono. Time for you to become onigiri!
That's wrong.
Onigiri aren't made that way.
You make it by molding rice with your hands.
So you don't cut oni demons?
That's right.
I have committed the mistake of my life.
I am prepared to follow the way of the warrior!
Stop it! Stop it!
Meow meow meow meow meow cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling meow cats meow!
Cats rolls & turn around like this! Cats rolling cats rolling cats rolling roll
nihinihinihi nihinihinihi
Smiling wide, smiling wide
nya nya shichau shi tanoshi shi
Because we’re grinning and having fun
hahihihinihi ihihii rooren
Laughing and smiling, rolling on the floor laughing
rooren rooren hai hai hoo
Rolling, rolling, hey hey ho
natsu no owari ha fuyu no hajimari
The end of summer is the beginning of winter
haroo uintaa iyoiyo harouin
Hello, winter, Halloween’s finally here
sore kara haro kurisumasu
And after that it’s hello Christmas
harokuri harokuri harokuri harokuri
Hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas
odotte odotte haro haro kuri kuri nennai ippai
Dancing and dancing to welcome Christmas, lots to do before the end of the year
kyou ha nani ni demo nareru hi
Today is a day when you can become anything
akakute marukute neko ga ii?
How about a chubby red cat?
koe no takai medama ha dou?
Or how about an eyeball with a loud voice?
umihousu kato omottara zura wo hazushita tonari no ojisan
The Umibozu I thought I saw disappeared and was replaced by an old man
hige wo tsuketara santa kuroosu
He looks like Santa Claus with that mustache
akai geehaa gojyushichi!
It’s the red game hardware 57!
asu kara kitto samuku naru
When tomorrow comes it will surely become cold outside
shiroi kisetsu ga kuru mae ni natsu no omoide katariai
Before the white season arrives, we’ll reminisce about summer memories
jakkurrantan minna wo terashi
Everyone will light their Jack-o-Lanterns
kurisumasu made mainichi paatii
Every day until Christmas will be a party
saa odorou otori tsudukeyou
So come on, let’s dance, let’s keep on dancing
harokuri harokuri harokuri harokuri
Hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas, hello Christmas
odotte odotte haro haro kuri kuri
Dancing and dancing to welcome Christmas
nennai ippai nennai ippai
Lots and lots to do before the end of the year
Today's yo-kai medalium...
Keita! What's today's yo-kai?
Mosaku!
I want an image change!
What is that?
It's a sudden change to your style
I understand!
Leave it to me!
Yeah I did it!
What!?
It's perfect!
On the next Yo-kai Watch...
Tengu battle?
The long-nosed tengu and the legendary classic yo-kai karasutengu with wind powers...
...seems like they're about to fight!
They're fighting over the length of their noses!
They're fighting over that!?
Translated and subtitled by Noroinohanako. Song lyric translation by @Manjiknights. Not for sale or rent.