Youkai Watch Episode 214
Translation/Timing/Typesetting/Encoding/Distribution: Noroinohanako
QC/Corrections/Stylings: Manjiknights
Raw Source from Leopard-Raws, TV Tokyo(TX)
A quiet and completely normal night
Town of Yo-kai
It's during nights like these,
That incidents involving yo-kai creep through.
Zura?
Zura...
Damn it!
Becoming a yo-kai... getting laid-off...
Woah, oops
Huh?
What?
Inaho! Inaho!
Eheh eheeh
Inaho, wake up!
Something felt really weird just now!
Augggh~! Augh geez!
In my dreams, I become the 4th member of the Sailor Piers,
and then I saved the prince from the Neo Galatic Mafia!
"Thank you, Sailor Pier Misora"
BAM! As he slams against the wall...
Huh!? What was that just now?
Did she just notice?
Meow? Meow?
That's right. Nobody has noticed it yet.
That fact that an unprecedented threat to the yo-kai...
...never seen before, will soon arrive shortly.
So hot!
Why is this room so hot?
Nya...
Wha...?
What's wrong, Jibanyan?
I-It's too hot to get closer.
*Snore snore snore snore*
H-Hot! Hot hot! What is this, a sauna!?
J-Jibanyan... He's...
Whis?
H-H-HOT H-HOT! That's seriously hot!
Hey! Jibanyan! Jibanyan!
Bababan Banban Banbaraya!
Banbarabarabara Banbaraya!
We leap through the ages
bokutachi wa jidai wo
with the speed of a bullet
dangan no youna supiido de tobikoeru
through the past and the future
kako mo mirai mo
all to meet you without fail
kimitachi ni au tamenara mayowanai yo
From troubled times to the present era
ransei kara heisei
When we hear someone crying
kikoeru darekaga naiteru
We zip! Fly in to take care of it
nara byun to tonndette kaiketsu
Looking over the stars at the desert of people
kono hoshi miwataseba hito no sabaku
But if these tears are yours
demo sono namida kimi no mono nara
No matter how small, we'll find you in a flash
hitotsubu demo patto mitsukerareru sa
Bababan Banban Banbaraya!
Banbarabarabara Banbaraya!
Going straight you you without fail
burezu ni massugu kimi no moto he yukeru
As it's destined
sadame no mama
Jibanyan, are you okay?
Actually, you don't look okay at all....
There's... nothing wrong... with me...
A Nya-KB concert is... happening today...
What are you saying? No way! No way!
Use this to measure his fever for now.
This is a yo-kai body thermometer.
Oh. Thanks Hikikkomori.
NyaKB...
Jibanyan, I'm taking your temperature.
36.7C? Seems normal.
No! Take a closer look, Keita!
It's 367C -whis!
Wha~! This is definitely weird!
Whis-!? That's so hot, it started a fire!
Feels kinda hot. -nyan
That's obvious!
Anyway, just put out that fire!
Nya...
*cough cough cough*
We gotta see what's wrong with Jibanyan.
Come on out my friend, Robonyan Type-F!
Yo-kai Medal, set on!
Robonyan Type-F!
Robonyan Type-F, Jibanyan's condition looks bad!
Please help him!
Leave it to me!
In the far future, there is no illness that can't be cured!
Super Jibanyan Search!
Whoa! Cool!
As expected of future technology -whis!
Beginning the search now!
Huh?
Oh no! My balance...
Ouch ouch ouch.... O-Ouch ouch!
Strange, that wasn't supposed to...
Why don't you go back home, while you're still functional?
I was simply scanning him with my hand.
Next, I'll scan him with the latest technology!
Ta ta ta tadah!
Super Jibanyan Search Mark II!
That's...
It's a price scanner used in convenience stores...
Huh?
What's this?
This is strange... Sorry...
Can you bring over a different item?
It really is a price scanner!!
Don't be an idiot!
Nyaa......
So we still don't know the cause after all?
That's correct.
How are you not ashamed?
It's so hot...
That fever's getting even hotter!
Alright, Leave it to me!
Transform!
Woah!
It's complete! A specialized refrigerator for Jibanyan!
Alright, before it's too late, put Jibanyan inside....
Come on out my friend!
Fubuki-hime!
Yo-kai Medal! Set on!
It's a Pretty time!
Sushi
Roulette
Pretty! Pretty! What's gonna happen?
Pretty! Pretty! Pr-et-ty!
First-class tuna!
Hehehehehe! I did it!
Fubuki-hime!
What's wrong, Jiba-chan?
We don't know what's going on, but that fever won't go down!
Try cooling down Jibanyan.
Got it!
Glittering blanket of snow!
Nyaa.....
This coldness feels great!
Roll... Roll... nyaa....
Looks like that fever's going down. Thanks Fubuki-hime!
Thank goodness.
Whis?
C-C-C-Cold! Nyaa......
Oh no! Now it's too cold! He's even turning blue.
Too blue!
Aaah!
Now it's too hot again...nyaa....
Jibanyan!
Nyaa... Feels kind of heavy...
Whaaa!?
Jibanyan's tails got huge!
Jibanyan! Hang in there!
Whisper, what's going on?
I have no idea.
Eighty yen
Cho...Chocobar?
Woof!
A D-Dog...?
Just a little....
Huh? Who's that?
What is he now?
Whisnyaa.....
Ah, now he kinda looks like Whisper?
No! Anything but this!
What's that supposed to mean!?
Gentlemen!
Did you forget that I'm right here?
Ah...Sorry.... We completely forgot.
Of course
As a result of continuing and discreet analysis,
I’ve finally established what’s going on with Jibanyan
Wha- What is it?
This is a seriously terrible illness.
These are its symptoms.
A 367 degree fever.
The tip of the tails becoming large
It's an illness that transforms your appearance into a dog or a disgusting ice cream shaped yo-kai.
Quit joking around!
And because this illness makes yo-kai drunk from fever...
It is called....
Yo-kai Dead Drunk Fever!
Yo-kai Dead
Drunk Fever
Yo-kai Dead Drunk Fever?
What an easy to understand name...
Right on the nose...
Ah, was that what that was? I was thinking the same thing...
On top of that, in the latest stage of the illness, It's written
that something terrible will happen.
Sometime terrible?
Is he going to turn into a terrible white yo-kai again!?
HEY
Nyaa.... Keita....
What's going to happen to me?
Feels like my head is floating, nyaaa....
All the fun I've had until now...
and my memories of Emi-chan....
The day that I befriended Keita...
When I met the Koma brothers...
Huh? What about your memories of me?
I understand it now!
For someone of my caliber...
Of course you're saving me for last!
My memories of Inaho and USApyon.
And Tomnyan, who moved next door...
Jerry. Robonyan Type-F.
Fubuki-hime. Jinmenken.
Android Yamada...
And finally...? Me right?
I didn't appear at all, Jibanyan! You jerk!
Whisper, calm down.
Huh?
Hey, who is that kitty cat?
Whis?
W-what do you mean who?
What's wrong? He's Jibanyan of course!
JIba... nyan...?
Certainly. This is that terrible final symptom!
What? What do you mean?
Jibanyan's existance will be erased from everyone's memories!
Whaaaaaat!?
Fubuki-hime, did you really forget about Jibanyan?
Jibanyan?
Who's that?
Memories are already starting to fade.
This is serious!
Robonyan Type-F, isn't there some way of curing him?
Um, in that case.
In that case, umm umm umm.
Ah, it's here!
It's this, it's this! There's no mistaking it!
Cause:
Withdrawal syndrome
Withdrawal syndrome?
So withdrawal syndrome happens...
...when you stop doing something you do all the time!
What has Jibanyan stopped doing recently?
That's it!
Whis?
Umm.... Keita...
So perhaps you think it’s because Jibanyan hasn’t been hit by a truck recently...?
Yep!
Don't tell me you're trying to roll our sick patient in front of a truck!
Robonyan Type-F!
Standby OK
We can launch anytime!
Are you serious!?
I don't really understand, but it seems kind of mean.
Yes, It's coming.
Let's go, Jibanyan!
There!
Nya Nyaa!
Now, Jibanyan!
Paws of....
I'll be back!
I'll never die!
Jibanyan!
It's no use, he's not cured!
That sure is strange.
Hey!
I've got it! A way to cure this illness!
Really?
We should stimulate the memories that Jibanyan have formed on this world.
If we do that, we may be able to fix Jibanyan's presence onto this world.
Uh huh. I see. I see!
Our first priority is to find things that jog Jibanyan’s memories from before he became a yo-kai.
Umm... What do you mean by that?
What we need is something that will remind Jibanyan of when he was a cat named Akamaru.
But none of us have anything like that though.
Yeah, but Jibanyan's former owner, Emi-chan should have something like that.
Let's find Emi-chan!
Yeah but...
You might have heard about Emi-chan, but you don't know what she looks like.
That's right!
InaUSA Mystery Detective Agency
I see, I see.
In that case, just *bam* leave it to me!
Please, Inaho!
I leave it to you, Haku!
You not doing it yourself, though.
Show us what Emi-chan looks like from Jibanyan's memories!
Understood!
HAAAaaaaaa
Kuuuuu!
Ah, she's here!
So this is Jibanyan while he was alive.
And this must be Emi-chan.
Alright, I see. Thank you, Haku.
I live to be useful
All we need to do now is to find Emi-chan.
I'll help too!
Come on out!
Come on out my friends!
Everyone, come with me to find Emi-chan!
It's showtime, everyone!
Well, can't help it.
Okay! Meow!
Leave it to me! Wonderful!
We'll stay behind to nurse Jibanyan!
Thank you, everyone.
We'll leave it to you.
Have a safe trip!
Okay! Leave it to us dogs to search for Emi-chan by scent!
Alright!
Oh! There's no mistaking it! It's here!
There seems to be a wonderful scent over here!
Good job, Ikemenken!
You're so reliable!
Damn it!
Huh? Which way?
Okay, We'll go this way.
Then we'll go here instead.
Whis!
Let's see, why were we searching for this person for again?
Huh.......?
Emi-chan! Emi-chan!
Emi-chan!
Cool down
Cooling down is delicious!
Big brother, you were talking about that?
If that's the case, then let us help your search!
Murikabe, don't search for Emi-chan!
No way I'm not helping you find her!
Got it. I'll cooperate as well.
BaaBAAA!
If we don't hurry, everyone's going to forget Jibanyan!
Whis!
Zura... Zura...
This time, let's cool down with this.
Zura? Who is this? Zura?
What are you talking about, big brother?
This is....
I wonder who this is...
Keita!
Inaho!
There was nothing there.
Is that so? Thanks anyway.
Huh? But why was I trying to search for her again?
Wha? It's for Jibanyan!
Jibanyan?
Who is that?
No...
This is bad! They've already forgotten!
But... Who did they forget?
Whisper, you too!?
K-Keita...!?
I'll never forget!
Never!
I will never forget about Jibanyan!
Emi-chan!
O-Ouch...
Ah!
Hey, can you lend me some help?
If I go with you together, I should be able to find Emi-chan.
Ah!
Hey..!
Huh?
Ah! I knew it!
You must be... Emi-chan, right?
...That's right.
You've owned a cat named Akamaru, right?
Huh?
Y-Yeah.
Um...
this might be hard to believe, but...
Akamaru is still alive... and...
Well, he's not Akamaru now, but...
...a lot of things happened....
Um.... Err.....
I understand.
Huh?
Akamaru,
Even now, I feel like Akamaru comes to visit sometimes.
Yes!
So, how can I help?
Um...
Actually, he's become sick.
huh?
To help him, I need some kind of memento to help him remember.
Something that has a lot of memories for Akamaru.
Can you lend me anything?
Memories?
Yes
In that case, I've got something perfect!
Ah!
This cat is having a hard time it seem...
Huh?
Jibanyan!
Jibanyan! Hang in there!
Come with me, quick!
Akamaru used to love riding on my bike's basket while going up the hilly road.
That should be his best memory for him.
Yaaaaaah!
Jibanyan! Look!
This hill, you must remember this place, right?
Nyaa? This place...
Emi-chan!
Alright, let's go!
Yaaaaaaaa!
Gah!? Uah Wah!
Uwa Gaaa ah!?
Nya Nyaanyaa....
Uwaaaaaah...
Gu.... Ouch ouch....
Keita....
Jibanyan!
Keita...
Its no good...
What are you saying, Jibanyan?
Keita...
It's been fun being with you this whole time
Meeting you, Keita,
...was really fortunate for me.
Please... don't talk like we're saying goodbye.
I will never forget about you, Jibanyan! Please!
Don't disappear!
Don't disappear....
Jibanyan
Sorry, nyaa, Keita.
Thank you, nyaa.
Jibanyan!
What is that?
It's a hairball
H.....Hair ball?
Aaaah
I feel so much better after barfing that out, nyaa!
♪Nyaa Nyaa nyaa
Keita!
Ah, is Jibanyan cured?
Yep! Completely fully refreshed!
Whisper, you remember Jibanyan now?
Yesswhisp!
Ah! I wonder if Jibanyan is okay...
Komajiro, let's visit Jibanyan with some ice cream
Let's go give him some!
I see. So cats spit out hairballs.
If hairs were to build up inside,
it would be bad for the body.
It was all because of that the whole time?
Roll roll
Seems like it.
For me to barf out hairballs,
I'm no different from any other cat! nyan!
Isn't that great, Keita?
Everyone took this way too seriously!
It was just a little fever.
Even if you say that,
you got everyone really worried.
Maybe you should sound a little more appreciative?
I couldn't help it.
Sorry for causing you trouble. So so sorwy.
S-So hot!
Don't tell me Keita's also got a hairball!?
OF COURSE NOT
KEITA'S FISTS OF FURY
Why me too!?
Well... It all ended well didn't it? heh.
Weary of the midwinter air
mafuyu no kuuki ni akitekite
Look up to the sky, those numbers multiply
sora wo miageru kaisuu fueta
From my chilled body, I let out a yell
hieta karada ga sakenndeimasu
With all my strength, I stretch my arms and legs and yell
omoikkiri teashi wo nobashitaitte sakenndemasu
Oh please great burning sun,
ookiku atsui taiyou kudasai
Please scorch our hearts
bokutachi no kokoro wo kogasu
Oh hot hot sun
atsui atsui taiyou wo
Banbaraya sun, please
banbaraya no taiyou kudasaimase
Hot hot hot h-h-hot hot!
acchii acchii aa aa acchii achi
Looking forward to the hot summer
atsui natsu ga machidooshii
Hot hot hot h-h-hot hot!
acchii acchii aa aa acchii achi
Mind and body and summer vacation
mii mo kokoro mo natsuyasumi
Hot hot hot h-h-hot hot!
acchii acchii aa aa acchii achi
When it turns to summer, a goddess is sure to appear
natsu ni nareba kitto megami ga arawareru
I will meet a goddess for sure
zettai megami to meguriaeru
Whisper’s
Challenge
Can you find the answer?
This is today's problem!
I am hidden somewhere here
Do you know where?
Ahh...
Don't you already know?
I’m that handsome butler overflowing with aura.
Huh? Have you not found me yet?
I'm right there. Right here!
Answers after the break!
Tadah! Here's the answer!
I was right here!
Did everyone get it right?
Here's today's medallium!
What's wrong?
I wasn't able to sleep today!
I've prepared just the right thing for this the whole time!
It's fine
Whis?
This show ends today.
Whaa!?
I didn't even hear about this!
Keita! Keita...!